In this section, I'll be helping you to get set up with everything that you'll need for the course, and
you'll get your first real taste of programming in D3.
I'll start off by helping you set up your development environment, showing you all of the basic software
that I currently use for D3 development.
Next, I'll introduce you to what SVGs are, and how they work with D3.
I'll show you how to use some of the basic D3 commands to write shapes the screen,
and I'll take you through how we can associate these shapes with pieces of data.
By the end of this section, you'll have created something that actually looks like a real visualization.
You'll be using rectangles to represent the heights of the world's tallest buildings, which will be a
precursor for our first real visualization,
when you be making a bar chart at the end of section three.