In this lecture I'll be helping you to set up your development environment for programming in D-3
I'll show you the web browser and text editor that I'll be using in this course,
I'll introduce you to the template files you'll be working from and I'll help you to get set up with an HTTP server
for your local machine.
For a web browser, I recommend that you use Google Chrome because it has a really nice set of developer
tools and it's fast.
It'll make it easier for you to follow along with my examples if we're looking at files in the same
browser.
But you're free to use whichever browser you feel most comfortable with.
You'll also want to get yourself a simple text editor for this course. For all the project that we'll
cover,
I'll be using Sublime Text 3, which is a basic text editor that works across Windows Mac OS and Linux.
You can get a trial version of this software for free on Sublime's website or you can actually pay for
the software to stop it bugging you with pop ups every now and then.
It doesn't take much to get started with D-3.
We'll be using D-3 version 5, which you can find in the D-3 GitHub page
by following this link right here. You just need to include the D-3 library somewhere in your HTML
in the same way that you'd include any other JavaScript library like jQuery or Underscore. You'll often
see these script tags are used to include D-3 in an HTML file, but we'll actually be downloading the file
into our template folders, which is a good habit to develop in case anything changes with the copy online. To keep
things simple so that you don't need to worry about getting the right versions of the different scripts
that we'll be using in this course,
I'll include everything that you'll need
in the template folder for each project. I'm keeping all my files in this directory here which is organized
into the different sections that we'll cover. Here we can see all the files from this section which is organized
by lecture.
I'm going to open up this whole folder in Sublime so I can show you how everything's structured.
Let's take a look at a file from later on in this section.
Here we are looking at an index.html file, which we'll be running in a web browser. Here I'm including Bootstrap
to help structure the page.
Here is a CSS file that I'll sometimes use to add some custom styling. Here we're including the D-3 library, which I
downloaded to the .js directory and here's the file that we'll be writing all D-3 code in. For most
of the visualizations that we'll be creating in this course, it is important to note that they'll need to run
over a local HTTP server because our page will be sharing files between different folders.
There are a few different programs that you can use for this but for this cause I'll be using the HTTP
server that comes in built with Python.
If you have Python already installed on your machine then it's super easy to get started.
If not, then just download Python from the official website and make sure that you can get the latest version
for whichever operating system you use.
Use once you have Python installed,
fire up your terminal in the folder that you want to run your server and run the command
python3 -n http.server
So here we can see that the server is working on port 8000
So if we navigate to our browser to local host 8000, then we should be able to see the files from
the directory that we're looking at.
I'm running my terminal from the root directory of all my project files so I can click through to whichever
directory that I want to look at.
This folder here for 2.6 should be the same as the one we have in the Sublime window.
As long as you're always looking at your page through a local host server, then your visualization should
show up here.
So hopefully by now you should have everything that you need to start programming in D-3.
If you have any problems setting this stuff up then leave me a comment in this video and I'll try to help
out what's going wrong.
Now that we're finished with set up we're ready to start learning about SVGs and how to add them into
the screen.