In this lecture, I'm going to go over some of the basics of SVGs, which D3 uses to visualize data
on the screen.
I'll be teaching you about how they're positioned, I'll show you some rules about placing SVGs, and I'll show
you what the syntax looks like in HTML. Basically, SVGs, which stand for Scalable Vector Graphics,
are shapes that we can make in a browser window with code. All that we need to do is pass in some simple
information, such where we want to position a shape and how big it should be, and we'll be using some
familiar syntax and HTML to do this.
The reason why D3 uses as SVGs rather than images to display data is that they don't lose any quality
if they're resized, and they don't take up much space.
This means that we can have thousands of these SVGs render on the screen in seconds,
and there isn't a huge lag when you want to move them all around at once.
You'll sometimes find that companies will use an SVGs file to contain their logo on their websites
for similar reasons.
For example, you can see here how Google's logo
is put together using an SVG file of simple shapes fitted together. On the left,
we have an older JPEG logo, and on the right, we have a new version which is made with SVGs.
The new logo will look crisp on any screen size, and it takes up about 170th of the space of the old logo.
So what does SVG markup look like?
You can either include SVGs directly in an HTML file as you can see here, or you can add them in with
JavaScript, as we'll do later and throughout most of the course.
Something that you'll notice about this code is that you need to define this SVG tag to surround
everything that we want to render.
That SVG tag represents the "canvas" that we'll be drawing on. Any SVG that we try to draw outside of
the canvas won't appear on the screen.
Let's take a closer look at this code.
Firstly, we're defining an SVG canvas with a width of 400px and a height of 60px. Inside the
canvas, we position our SVGs based their x and y coordinates starting from (0, 0) and the top-left hand
corner.
For a rectangle,
we need to supply an x- and y-position, which corresponds to the top left corner of the shape.
Here we're giving the rectangle an x value of zero and y value zero,
so the top-left corner of the shape will appear at the (0, 0) coordinates in our imaginary grid.
We also need to provide width and height attributes, and we can color our shape using the "fill" attribute.
Something to mention here is that, if we have a shape whose coordinates like outside of our canvas, then
it won't appear on the screen.
For example if the coordinates were (0, 70), then although the shape should really exist down here, we
actually won't see anything, because it's outside the SVG
canvas. Another thing that you might find is that shapes can appear clipped from the how they're supposed
to look if they stick out over the edge of the canvas.
So here, if placed our rectangle at (375, 0), then only half of the shape would show on the screen.
We can also give shapes an outline by passing in a stroke attribute. This takes a color, and we need
to define how wide the outline is with the "stroke-width" attribute.
It's important to note that, technically, a stroke of a shape is drawn as a border around the outside,
rather than appearing on the inside.
This means that, in this particular example, we would only actually see the right and bottom border on
the screen.
For creating circle SVGs, the process is pretty similar, except we provide the coordinates to the
center of the circle, rather than the top-left.
So here, we provide a cx attribute of 90
and a cy attribute of 25, which is where the circle's center will be.
We also need to give it a radius value using the r attribute, which will determine how big the
circle is,
and again we're using the fill attribute here to color the shape. The next SVG is in an ellipse,
which is identical to a circle, except that it needs both an x-radius value and a y-radius value, which
we provide with the rx and ry attributes. Again, the coordinates for an ellipse correspond with the center
as opposed to the top left.
We can also draw a straight line as an SVG. To do this, we need to provide two sets of coordinates,
which represent the two points that the line should run between. Here our code is drawing a line between
(185, 5), our x1 and y1 values, and (230, 40) our x2 and y2 values. Something to note about lines
is that applying a fill to them
doesn't affect that color.
We set the color with the stroke attribute, and the width of the line with the stroke-width attribute.
We can also render text as an SVG, which we'll frequently need to do for creating things like
axis labels.
By default, the x and y attribute give us the top left position of the text, but we can change this behavior
using the text-anchor attribute. Here, the text anchor is middle,
so the coordinates match the top-middle of the text... And then here the text anchor is end,
so the coordinates match the top-right of the text. The default value of the text anchor attribute
is called "start". The final type of SVG that D3 uses is called a path. A path is the most powerful
kind of SVG that we have available, and it can be used to create lines, curves, arcs and all kinds of complex
shapes. Later on in the course, we'll be using paths to create maps, line charts, area charts, and pie charts
The "d" attribute
here is what gives the path its shape.
This attribute contains a set of different letters and numbers which our browser can decode to figure
out how the path should look. For this course,
you don't need to know what the d attribute is doing.
D3 provides us with a set of different path generators, which will take in data and create these d attributes
for us.
Although we've defined SVGs in this example using HTML-like syntax, when we use them in D3,
we'll almost always be adding them to the canvas with JavaScript.
Learning how to do this will give you your first few steps in the D3 world,
and it's what we'll be covering in the next video.