Now that we know a little bit more about SVGs, I'm going to show you how to add them in with D3, rather
than in your HTML.
I'll be introducing you to D3 select, D3 append, and D3 attr, which will be using together to make
new shapes on the screen.
I'll also be making sure that you understand how method chaining works in
JavaScript, since it comes up a lot in
D3. Here we have a simple template folder that I'll be giving you to practice with over the course
of this section. For everything that we'll do in this course,
you'll be writing all of your code in a separate JavaScript file
to your HTML. For a small project, it might make sense to put everything in one HTML file,
but to make things a little cleaner, you'll be writing in the main.js file in your js folder.
I have included this file with script tags in our HTML file.
Here's the file that will be writing. At the moment,
there's nothing in it as you can see, but we'll be adding to it in this lecture.
Let me show you how a first D3 function works.
D3 select uses CSS selectors to return page elements, in a similar way to how jQuery works.
This gives us an object that we can then manipulate with D3 commands, such as binding data to shapes.
The regular select function will return one element, and selectAll will return all of the matching
elements on the page.
For example, here we have an SVG canvas with three rectangles. On the far left, calling D3 select on the
retc tag will return the first rectangle that D3 finds on the page -
the one on the left.
Next we're using a CSS selector to grab the rectangle with the ID of center, which gets the one in the
middle. Next, we're using selectAll on every rectangle on the page, which gives us all three, and finally we're using
selectAll to grab all the rectangles with the class of outside, which gives us the outer two rectangles.
Once we have an element selected, we can use D3's append method to add something to it.
Here we've selected the SVG canvas in our HTML, and we're adding a shape to it.
Append takes one argument, which is the type of element that we want to add to the screen.
In this example we're adding a rect tag, passing in the string of rect. To set the attributes of
an SVG,
we can pass values in with the attr method, which is a special D3 function that can alter attributes.
We pass in the attribute we want to set as the first argument to this attr method, and the value that we want
to give it as the second argument.
Something to note at this point is that, although we could write our code as it is on the left, in D3
we will almost always be writing it out as it is on the right.
If you haven't had much experience in JavaScript yet, then what we're doing here is called method chaining.
We're passing the result of our
first method call onto our second method call, which we're then passing on to our third method call, and so on...
Our call to D3 select here returns SVG canvas, and we're calling our append method on this, which
returns a blank rect tag.
We're then calling our attr method on that rect tag, which returns the same red tag with an x value of
25, which we're then passing on to our next method, which is going to be setting.
the y attribute. The indents here are useful to break up our code, and to show which methods are being applied
to which D3 selection.
This makes it clear that we're setting attributes of a rectangle, rather than assessing attributes of
our SVG canvas.
Here is another way that we could have expressed the same chain of methods.
The first part returns our SVG canvas which we stored in a variable called svg earlier. We're then appending
a blank rect tag to that canvas, which we were storing in a variable called rect before. Then, after
that, we're setting the different attributes of this rect tag with these attr methods.
Something that might not be obvious is that each of these method calls returns something. We are only
able to chain these methods together because each of the attr methods are returning the element that
they're changing.
If one of these methods return something different,
for example if we decided to use D3 append again to add a text SVG to the rectangle, then any attr methods
that follow would set the attributes of text, rather than rectangle.
Let's work through a simple example to see how we'd usually use select and append in D3.
I want to select the div element that I've labeled with the ID of "chart-area" in my index file,
append and SVG canvas to it, and then write a shape onto that canvas.
Notice that we don't already have a canvas set up in our HTML this time,
so we'll be adding that with D3. So, I'll start out by selecting our div with the D3 select function
using the CSS tag "#chart-area".
Next, I'll use D3's append method to attach an SVG canvas to it using the string of SVG to show
that we're adding in an SVG tag.
Once we have that to work with, I'm going to give the SVG canvas its dimensions of width the height using
the attr method.
So the first argument to this attr method is the attribute we want to set,
so in this case I'll start with the width, and the second argument is the value that we want to give it,
so in this case I'll make it 400px wide. To keep things simple, I'll set the height attribute with
the same value of 400.
Next, I'm going to store this as a variable so we can add to it later.
Now that we have a hold of this canvas that we just drew with the svg variable, I'm going to add a
circle to it.
First, I'm going to add a circle SVG with D3's append method, passing the circle tag.
Once we have that, I'll use a few attr methods to give it some sensible dimensions based on the size
of the canvas.
I'll give it a cx and cy attribute of 200,
so it should be in the middle of the canvas.
I'll give it a radius attribute of 100 and I'll give it a fill attribute of blue.
Now, if we go to our browser window, we'll see that this code has run, and we have a nice shiny blue circle
on the screen. Just as a sanity check,
Let's change some of these values around to make sure that the circles update.
I'm going to change the cx attribute to 100, the cy attribute to 50, the r value to 70, and I'll change
the fill to gray.
So, as we can see, once we refresh the page the circle has updated as expected.
So now you know how to use D3 select, append, and attr to add shapes to the screen.
In the next activity, I want you to replicate the code that I just wrote, and try to add a rectangle to
the screen, instead of a circle.
Feel free to play around with a different attribute values of the SVG canvas and the rectangle, to really
get to grips with how everything is working.