Now that you know how to work with SVGs and JavaScript, it's time to actually do something with them.
The whole point of D-3 is that we need to tie these SVGs to data, giving us Data Driven Documents. Once we
can associate these elements with a piece of data,
this lets us tweak their attributes to show something about the data that they represent.
One of the key features behind the D-3 library is the ability to perform a data join. D-3 reads in an array
of data and associates each item of the array with an SVG.
Let's take a look at a simple example.
I'm looking at the code that we just used in the previous exercise.
Now instead of attaching just one circle to the screen we're going to attach many of them at the same time.
I'm going to make a few edits for this code to get the behavior that we're looking for.
I've added in an array of integers  which D-3 will use for the data join.
The syntax becomes a little confusing here.
Firstly we use 'Select All' to get all the circles on the screen.
Next we associate this selection with our array of data using this data method.
We pass the results onto a method called 'Enter' and then we pass the result of that on to 'Append'.
You might think that this 'Select All' call here won't return anything because there aren't yet any circles
on the screen.
Then it looks like we're feeding this array of data into a selection of nothing. We're then using this
mysterious 'Enter'  method, together with the usual 'Append' and 'Attr" methods. D-3 is actually doing some
complicated stuff behind the scenes here.
We'll cover this in detail in section 5 when you'll learn about the D-3 update pattern. For now,
just take it on faith that using these lines together magically works.
The result is that we get a new circle on the screen for every item in our data array.
For each new circle we now have the option of setting attributes with an anonymous function instead
of an integer or a string.
If we do this then we can set the value of our  attributes based on the contents of each item in the array.
When we use a function instead of a value here we can give it one or two arguments.
The first argument will represent an item in our array.
And the second argument represents its index in the array.
I'm going to add in a few console logs here to show you what's going on.
The function is running once for every item in our array.
First we're setting the cx attribute and the function is running for every value in the array.
The function starts with the first element in the array at position 0, then it moves to the second element
at position 1.
And so on.
Once the function is looped through every item in the array, the same thing happens for a radius function.
We can also see the values match up between our anonymous functions.
The item with the value of 25 is always at the index 0,
the first item in the array and the item with a value of 15 is always at index four, last item in
our array.
Since none of these functions return anything, we are basically setting all of these values to Null
So our circles won't render to the screen yet. To fix this and to see if our anonymous functions
are working,
I'm going to return the same value in each of our functions.
When we take a look at the browser it looks like we only have one circle, but actually all of the circles
just have the exact same size and position.
We can stagger these circles by returning a different cx attribute for each data point.
We can space these circles out uniformly by multiplying their indexes by a certain number.
I'm returning a value of i x 50 meaning that the centers will be 50 pixels apart and I'm adding
25 to the result to shift everything to fit on the screen.
I'm also going to do something similar with the radius attributes. For each of our circles,
the radius will equal the value of the piece of data that it represents.
I'm using the old fashioned anonymous function syntax from before ES6 in this course because most of the
D-3 community still writes its code like this.
For any of the functions that we'll write in this course, we can just as easily have written them as arrow
functions and everything will work out just the same way.
So now we're getting somewhere.
The shapes that we're rendering to the screen are actually representing something about the data. In the next
lecture
We'll be working with a more complex array of data and learning how to load that data from a file.