Now that we can see how D-3 binds data to SVGs on a basic level,
I'm going to show you how to do the same thing with a real dataset so that we don't have to store everything
in a variable.
I'll be teaching you to load data from CSV, TSV, and JSON files and I'll be setting the properties of
our SVGs
according to the data.
D-3 has a variety of different functions to handle data from external sources.
If you want to get more advanced with this then you can use an Ajax request to load data from a completely
different source like an SQL server or a Google Docs spreadsheet.
But for this course we'll be dealing with static data held in the data folder of our project.
For this lecture I've included a data folder in our project files with three different example datasets
.
We have one CSV file, one TSV file and one JSON File. CSV stands for Comma Separated Values
and TSV stands for Tab Separated Values.
You can think of these files as  analogous to a spreadsheet with each of the columns being separated
by a tab or a comma and each of the rows being separated by a newline character.
Finally. JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation, which should look fairly familiar as it's basically
just a large JavaScript object. D-3 gives us these three functions at the bottom of the screen to load in
these files as an array. We'll be using D3 CSV, TSV and D-3
JSON.
to grab data throughout the course.
The functions all work in just the same way. We're passing in the relative path to the file that we're
looking at.
And since these functions are all written as promises we're using the then method to execute an anonymous
function.
Once the data has been loaded in. We can then access this data using the data arguments of this anonymous
As a side note, here's what the syntax used to look like before version 5.
You might sometimes see these functions written like this online, but you'll need to use the 'then'
syntax with promises to get things that work in the latest version of the library.
Since this course was written in Version 4 you might see the syntax in my examples but just be aware
of the subtle difference here between the two versions to get your code to work.
Let me take you through an example. Starting with the code that we had from last section.
I'll get rid of this data array and
I'm going to load in this age data with the D-3 CSV function. The result from calling this code
right here is a promise which could either be fulfilled, rejected or pending.
The great thing about using a promise here is that we can pass this value around in our code without
actually needing to wait for it to evaluate.
Here we're saying that we want to grab the file called ages.CSV
inside our data folder and then I'm going to define a function that we want to run once it's
been loaded in
with this 'then' method. Now that we have access to this data inside this function let's take a look at
what D-3 has prepared for us.
I always recommend starting off by logging whatever data you are working with to the console before
you write any code with it so that you can get a clear idea of the format that you're working with.
I'll also comment out this code for now just so that we don't have any errors that we need to worry about.
We can see that D-3 is read in the data as an array of JSON objects.
Here we simply have a list of names with their ages attached to them.
For CSV and TSV files D-3 interprets the object keys of name and age from the first row of our data as a
quick sanity check,
I'm just going to show you that D-3 does the same thing for our JSON File with d3.json,
so that's the same. And with our TSV file with d3.tsv
something to note about these age values
here is they're listed as strings rather than numbers.
Since I'm interested in working with these values as integers I'm going to need to convert them before
I do anything else.
This is a common task that you'll need to perform after reading in data,
as data is often read in from text files. To do this,
I'm going to write a simple for each function which will take every element in a data array and convert
the age values into integers.
If you haven't had much experience in JavaScript before, then what this function is doing is that it's looping
over the array that we're passing it.
And for every item in the array we're converting the age value of the object to an integer with this
plus sign.
If we log this data out to the console now, we can see the age values are now integers as we expected.
Now that we have data formatted,
let's take those circles from our previous example using external data with them instead of just using
an array. We'll also need to update our anonymous function here because this de-value is going to return
an object instead of an integer now.
I'll just make a quick console log to show you what each of our attr functions is working with now.
We see that we have access to a name field and an age field
for each item in the array.
Keep the cx function the same as before
just to make sure the circles don't overlap.
But this time I'm going to set our radius as two times the age of each person.
We can refresh the page here and it looks about right for the numbers in the dataset.
I'm also going to use an IF statement to set the fill of our circles.
Let's say that we want to color Tony's circle in blue and every other circle in red
Refreshing the page we can see that this is working as expected. As a final step
I'm just going to show you have error handling works in D-3. In the old version we used to handle errors
like this.
Here we have an optional first argument that defines an error message if something goes wrong when our
code tries to read the file.
And then we're throwing this error inside of our callback function
if something goes wrong. With promises we can handle this a little more succinctly by using the catch
method.
Here we're dealing with the event that our promise turned out to be rejected and we're using the error argument
to this function to tell us what went wrong.
As an example let's say that we accidentally misspelled the path to the data that we want to load here
There isn't a file called age.tsv in our data folder.
So our promise is going to get rejected.
Once we refresh the page we can see that on this line right here we are guessing a console log of exactly
what went wrong.
Error handling is a great habit to get into.
But it won't be that important for any of the projects that we'll cover in this course.
D-3 has given us the power to selectively edit the SVGs on the screen depending on what each data point
is saying. We'll be expanding on this going forward in a whole host of different applications to generate
all kinds of different charts. In the next activity,
I want you to work with a JSON file, which will be in the data section of your template folder, and
make a really simple visualization.
The file contains a list of the five tallest buildings in the world with some values representing their
heights.
I want you to make a rectangle for each of them like this.
The first rectangle is representing the Burj Khalifa, the second rectangle is representing the Shanghai
Tower.
And so on.
This will be your first step towards creating something that actually looks like a real visualization.
And we'll using it as a jumping off point to make a bar chart in the next section.