In this section I'll be introducing you to some best practices to help you to structure your code for
large projects.
I'll be taking you through the process of splitting up your code into different sections.
And show you how to write each of your visualizations in an object orientated style.
This will make it possible to add many visualizations onto the page at once but keeping your code understandable
and it'll also help you to start writing more reusable code that can copy into future projects.
Over the course of this section I'll be improving on I coin's that site we've made for a third class
project adding in some visualizations to complement what our graph is showing at the end of this section.
You'll be putting together what you learn throughout the whole course to build your final project.
I'll be starting off with some template community code you can find on line and you'll be going through
the process of gradually building up a powerful interconnected page.
This will be a production quality data dashboard which is designed to be used by a manager to assess
the performance of a company's sales team's.