Going back to code from project 3 You might think that things are starting to look a little messy.
There's so much going on in a manger file after we've added all of these different event listeners to
our visualization in this lecture.
I'll be presenting you with an alternative file structure which will make your code more usable for
larger projects.
Here's what we'll end up with at the end of this lecture.
Our main Jasc file will serve as a controller file which will handle events on the page and linked together
a common code that will spread across all files.
Then we'll create a new javascript file called Line J.S. which will contain everything that relates
to our line chart code.
As we start to add different types of visualizations to our page in this section We'll be including
more and more job script files for each type of visualization that we want to create.
I'll include both of these files with script tags inside of index file.
When we're trying to restructure a files like this it's important to have a good understanding of scope
in different parts of our code.
You'll see on this line that we've included another javascript file in our index page which at the moment
is just a blank file in our javascript directory.
Including two script tags like this basically just means the browser will copy and paste all of the
jast code to be right.
The first file stick it in here do the same with a second file including the main Jap's file after a
line of file so you can imagine that everything will write inside a line Choat file will be read by
a browser before anything in the main file.
So in the main file these variables that we're declaring at the top of the file will have a global scope
which is shared between the different files that we've included with script tags.
For instance we could easily access this selection in a file that was included after it.
However the file order matters here.
We try to access this variable in a file that we've included before it's then our code won't know what
we're talking about.
I'm going to shift as much of the line graph code that I can into this separate line chart.
X-File now in this file I have all the code that we'll be using to set up a line up where adding in
a SPG can this drawing a line setting up scales axes and labels and we're also defining update function
here.
In our main JSA file we now have event listeners and data loading function.
We can still access update function in this file since we're including a main file afterwhile line of
file.
We now have the building blocks of something that looks like a controller file.
Since all of the events on the page are handled in here this will start to make more sense as we add
more visualizations as it will become easier for us to group together.
Similar event handlers into the same functions will also be running the code to set up each of our visualizations
here.
Once we've written on visualisations in the object oriented style they'll be introducing in the next
two lectures after this lecture.
Our code is now a little bit more structured than before.
The file structure I've chosen to use is in no way canonical within the D-3 community but Elf has a
really simple structure that you can follow.
You might want to make a separate folder within your projects japes directory.
If you end up having a lot of different libraries to include in the next lecture you'll be talking about
the object orientated approach that I use for D3 development which will make it easy to create multiple
instances of the same kind of visualisation on the page.
This will also allow us to free up a global namespace making it easier for us to track variables across
more than one type of visualisation.