In this lecture I'll be introducing you to the principles of object oriented programming which we can
use to write up visualizations as objects.
I'll be talking about the benefits that this approach gives us for making more complex projects and
I'll be taking you through the syntax that we can to use.
So what do we mean by the idea of writing a visualization as an object in any programming language.
An object is a self-contained component which has a set of properties and methods which you can use
to express something object oriented programming or.
OK involves thinking about every piece of code that we write as being an object.
This allows us to create lots of different components within our code which can hold information about
their current state in their properties and perform certain functions by calling them methods.
For example here's how we might express an apple and a banana two objects for each of these fruits we're
giving them properties to show their name how sweet they are and their shape and we're giving them two
methods which express what we could do with them.
These methods could do absolutely anything.
Another key feature of O.P. the idea of creating new objects of a certain class.
For example we might want to decide to create a class called fruit which are apple and banana both belong
to if we create these objects as an instance of the class fruit then the fruits object can inherit some
of the fields from this class instead of having to define new properties and methods.
Every time for example we can have a generic it and throwing method attached to the class of fruit.
Then whenever we create a new instance of one of these fruits that automatically inherit these two methods
which they can use.
This means that whenever we want to create a new fruit we don't have to write out each of these methods
do every single time.
We just need to pass in the data that differs across the fruits.
We can do this with our visualizations too.
For example we have two types of visualizations here that we might want to create these visualizations
can have properties such as that width and height and we can give them different methods for them to
use.
We then create a class for every type of visualization that we want to write.
For example we might want to make a bar chart class which contains a bunch of fields that all bar charts
should have.
We should pass in some information to make a new batch of such as where we want to attach it and the
data source that you should use.
And then we could easily make many bar charts at the same time.
There were three main reasons why we should always try to write visualizations as objects.
Firstly it makes our visualizations a lot more reusable between different projects.
Once you have an object set up over a particular visualization then it should be easy to use the same
code for a different purpose.
You can copy your file containing this visualization object into a different project folder and then
you can use it in the exact same way.
Another reason why we want to write our visualizations as objects is that it reduces the number of global
variables that a site needs to keep track of.
Imagine if we wanted to create two different visualizations on the same page without splitting our code
and objects we need to make new variables for each visualization to hold things like their heights with
scales.
This could quickly become confusing if we ended up having a separate line chart with variable to a pie
chart with variable.
And it means that code will get messier and more confusing as time goes on.
Treating our visualizations as objects provides a solution to this.
We can hold variables as properties of our visualization objects and then we can hold the functions
as methods.
Finally the other upside is using objects like this that we can make many of the same type of visualization
without having to write much more code.
For instance if he wants to add four different line charts to a page at once then we just need to write
the bulk of our code once when we write the code for Object class.
Here's what the new set up will look like.
Each of our visualizations once that written piece style each of our visualization objects will have
three methods in it is Rangle data and update this unit.
This method will draw a graph for the first time possibly loading in a data setting the values for us
scales axes and setting up our SPG components.
Then when we have a Rangle data method we can shuffle or filter out data depending on what the user
wants to see.
Finally we have the update is function which will basically be doing the same thing.
Change functions have been doing so far.
So just updating us scales axes and SFE cheese when we first create an instance of our visualization
class.
This will trigger a that visualisations it is a method which in turn will call the Wrangel data method
which itself will trigger the update method.
Then whenever we want to update a visualisation like this with new data we can call our Wrangell data
method which will format out data and again cause update functions run.
Here's what the basic syntax will look like.
First we have an object definition where we're creating a new class called Barcott as a general rule.
We conventionally write classes in javascript.
In other camel case so the every word is capitalized.
The function is called the constructor function for a batch of class every time we want to write a new
instance of a bar chart object.
This function will get run in arguments that this function takes will set up a object with some initial
conditions and are typically written with an underscore at the front of their names.
In this second block here we can see how to add a method to the object in javascript.
We need to use this prototype syntax passing in whatever name we want to give our method.
At the end finally in the bottom block here we have the syntax of making a new object of a certain class.
We use the reserved word new in javascript to create a new object here and we're passing into arguments
which are a function will use.
First we have the string bartk container which object will take as its parent element and we're passing
in an array of data which officials zation will be using then since we're saving this object as a variable.
This lower case bartk variable we can now call any of its methods on our object.
So here we could call the potshots in this method which will then run that method's code something to
note here is that we are using the this keyword javascript to access the different methods and properties
are contained within the particular object instance that we're looking at.
When this object gets built for the first time in a constructor function the line colored in red will
call the method of the same object that we just created.
In the second block with then storing the value of this in a variable called vid's which will then use
to access objects different properties and methods.
At the end of this lecture you should have a good understanding of why we want to restructure our visualisations
in the form of objects and you've had your first look at how the syntax should work.
In the next Levchin I'll be taking you through the process of rewriting our code from project 3 in this
object orientating style which we'll be using when we going forward.