In this lecture I'll be taking a file restructuring process to the next level by writing a line chart
is a javascript object like we saw in the last lecture rather than just keeping it in its current form.
I'll be running you through all of the changes that I'll be making to do this.
And at the end of the lecture I'll demonstrate what this allows us to do by adding a new line chart
for every coin in a project three data recall from last lecture that we need to stitch together.
Each of these different parts of our visualization object in order to properly set up the construct
a function will be executed as soon as we use the new keyword in the name of our visualisations class.
That function will set up a new visualization object which we'll call its own and it is method that
method will set up the static parts of our visualization before triggering the Wrangel data method.
And then finally at the end of the Rangle data the object will trigger the update is method which will
affect our scaled axes and as piccies starts off.
I've copied the basic structure that we'll be using for official position objects at the top of our
line of file.
This is a constructor function here which will be calling whenever we create a new instance of a line
shop class.
Remember the syntax here we are using up a camel case to show that we're talking about a class and the
argument to construct a function here has an underscore in front of its name.
Inside the construct the function with just passing the field that we're setting in with the property
of this new object.
And then with triggering our net this method inside this first method with setting this variable is
as the value of the object that we're looking at.
It's a good idea to do this straight away at the start of each prototype that you write.
Since the value of this can shift according to where you're trying to access it within calling Rangle
data method here which is just doing the same thing right now before handing off to a statement.
So I want to start by moving this code down here so that it fits inside a new class in it.
This method should contain all of the static elements that we need to set.
This will include all of this code down here.
We're setting up our margins we're attaching SVGA.
Can this adding up path for the first time adding labels for axes and setting up scales.
Or make a change here so that SPG canvas will get appended to which ever argument we provide in our
construct to function.
We stored this in our visualizations parent element property earlier so I'll pass it to a select function.
This means that if we pass a C selector that matches an element on the screen we'll add a line chart
to the elements.
Next this Rangle data method wants to contain anything that we're doing to reformat or filter the data
that we're looking at.
In this case I'll put this block of code here into this prototype since we're using it to change the
coin y value and time range that we're looking at.
Finally I'm going to move all of this code in our update function into update this method.
So now all of this code should be in the right place but we still have a pretty tedious task to accomplish
before we can call this object for the first time.
Every time that we using a variable that used to have a global scope we'll now need to edit it so that
we're accessing as a property of a visualization object.
If we don't do this then all of the variables that we declare inside each of these methods won't be
available to the rest of our line graph code.
So here starting off at the top I'm going to set these variables as properties of a variable which represents
the object that we're looking at.
This is a pretty tedious process and you probably find that you'll miss some of these variables out
but ultimately you should end up with a new version that finally works.
So here we have the finished product.
We're now using this fizz object to store each of our global variables and each time we want to access
these variables we're looking at the properties of this object.
Going back to our main Jasc file here I'll show you how we would add one of these line graphs to our
code all starts off by creating a new instance of one of our line objects using the javascript new keyword
and storing it as a variable I'm passing in the name of the div that we want to append it to.
So in this case we're using our charts areata we can get rid of our called update here since the object
calls its own update method when it first gets created.
Next will need to change up the update functions that we using for our event handlers.
Since this function doesn't exist anymore.
Instead of firing the update function we'll be firing the Wrangel data method of a new line sheet.
Finally we'll also need to declare this line chart variable with a global scope.
The top of our file so that our code has access to it within these event handlers.
Now when we refresh the page we can see the same visualization that we had before.
But this time a visualization is coming from an object.
I'm going to make a few quick changes to this code to demonstrate why this change is such a powerful
one for us to have made.
I'm going to adapt our code so that we can now show five line charts at the same time.
I've had a few edits to a line chart.
Yes file I'm passing in a new value to construct a function which was saving this coin property for
each object that we create a Rangle data method is then just looking at the data for the coin that is
set to.
I've also decreased the height and width for visualization so that we can fit many of them on the page.
Once next I've changed the contents of the index file creating 5 new device where I'll be attaching
five new line shots.
I've also gotten rid of the coin select box since I want to show a new chart for each coin.
Finally in our main Jasc file I'm creating a different line of every coin that exists in our data.
I'm passing the parents element for each of these charts so the constructor function.
And I'm also giving it the name of the coin that this graph should show since I want each of these charts
date when we change selections.
I'm also creating one event handler that fires the Rangle data method for each of our line charts and
calling that method from Whenever I use it does something.
Once we refresh the page we can see how this is working.
We've automatically created 5 different charts which each show the same thing for each coin.
We can change the way value we want to show here and we can adjust the date range.
Up here you can see how important it was for us to split our code into objects for us to do this.
Imagine if we had to copy and paste the same code again and again each time we wanted to update this
once we have a visualization written as objects.
It becomes so much simpler to repeat the same basic format again and again.
You should now understand the process which is involved when trying to restructure your code into an
object orientated format.
You should try to go through this process whenever you can when you want to make and do visualization
even if you only need to make one instance of a particular visualization.
Writing as an object will still make your code a lot more reusable and will also make it easy for you
to recreate this specialization in another project.
For your final class project at the end of this section you'll need to write your code in this format
since your data dashboard will be communicating between multiple files at once.
In the next lecture I'll be adding on to this code again adding some donut charts alongside a main line
graph.
Then be talking about how we can communicate between these complex visualization objects by using some
well-designed event handlers.