In this lecture I'll be adding in two more visualizations to a graph and I'll be showing you how to
deal with event listeners that should affect more than one element on the page to do this.
I'll be writing events inside a manger file which will act as the controller file that communicates
between all of the visualizations on the page at the end of this lecture we should have a more advanced
page where visualizations can seamlessly communicate with one another.
Here's how I want our sites to work when we want to link multiple visualizations on the same page.
Each event listener that we register inside one of visualizations is going to map to an event handler
which will live inside a mange s file.
This will allow us to update the state of multiple visualizations at once.
Since that all accessible from our main js file these event handlers inside a major file will act as
a go between.
Meaning that we can make events happen inside the visualization impact all sorts of visualizations on
the page structuring our code like this will make it easier for us to express what each of these events
should be doing so that we can read facts or events to work as efficiently as possible.
Here's what I want us to end up with at the end of this lecture.
I want us to have two donut charts which will show the market capitalization 24 hour trading volume
of each of our coins in the present day.
If I click on any one of these slices then I want my graph to update to show that coin I'll be changing
the fill opacity.
Each of these slices whenever the selection gets changed and I still want to have the same effect when
changing the coins using the select box at the top of the screen.
So I also want that event update the correct coins color color to start off with.
I'm going to draw the two donut charts that we'll be using.
I've created a new file here which contains all of us Donat CHUGG code and I've included this in my
index page to nail file down.
Hit.
I've also changed of the structure of my age to male so that two thirds of the page will be taken up
by a line chart with the remaining third allocated to Donat charts.
Here is the file that I'm using to define the donut shop class which will be using created down charts
in the constructor function.
This time I'm passing in this variable argument and just telling charts what variable it should be showing.
We're also using this value in this method when assessing the value method for a pilot.
So this is just an access a function that the value method will use to tell which field it should look
at in the Wrangel data method.
Just grabbing the name of the coin that we're looking at from a coin select box.
Then I update this method we're using the same update function that we saw back in Section 7 for our
data join this time we're using a global data array called donor data which I've put together in a major
s file.
Here's where we are setting up the data to be fed into a donut chards we're making use of this for loop
that we already made to loop through every coin and we're just pushing an object.
This Donat dates here which we defined at the top of the file within passing in the most recent data
point that we have for each coin in the data field and in making a log down here to show you what this
looks like.
We can see here that our data is now in a format that we can use without Pylades.
We have an array of objects one for each field and can access different values using this data field.
Now that we have all of this set up I'm going to add in two new instances of the donut shop.
I'll add one chart.
Each of the diff that we setup passing in the field should display.
I also need to remember.
And these variables in at the top of the file so that we can access them later when you add events to
them.
One last change that I'll make is that at the same color scheme we're using for a donor chart.
The color path in a line show that is more obvious which coin we're looking at.
To do this or remove the color scale that we defined in our donor chart and I'll add it to the list
of global variables in our mange file.
We also need to change its name when the calling here or otherwise will again error and then in a line
of file I'm just going to make the color line come from this same color scale passing in the coin that
we're looking at once we refresh the page we can see that we now have three visualizations on the same
page and that the color of our line should match whichever coin we're looking at.
Now let's think about which events we want to add to our site to link the visualizations together.
Here's a list of all the new events that we need to incorporate whenever an artist gets clicked on one
of the charts then that we selected should become active.
For a visualization This should also trigger an update to a line chart to show the new coin and it should
also update the value of select bugs then we also want to add an event to a coin select box so the active
coin is not doing that chart of dates when we change the value here.
Of starts off by adding a click event for my donor charts.
I'm using that method as usual.
Added listen to each of these paths as they entered and I'll just call a function called.
Clicked which are right in the main file.
If I just leave it like this then I should be able to get a hold the item in data that is associated
with each of us slices.
So going back to a main file now after I've written out this function with an argument then this de-value
will give that item in its own data array as we can see here.
I'm going to be using the name of each point form the updates that we're looking for.
Firstly I want to update the value of our select box with the coin that it should show Next they want
to trigger an update to both of my Donat charts.
And finally I want this to update all line jobs.
Once we refresh the page we can see how this is working.
The final thing we need to do now is also up.
They don't add charts whenever a select box gets updated.
We can do this by simply copy and pasting these two lines in our event handler.
You might think that repeating yourself a little here since we're calling at least 3 update functions
in two different places.
We can do some refactoring at this point to clean things up a little by just bringing these lines into
a separate function.
I'm calling this function color change to make it obvious what it's doing and I'm firing it and each
of these places.
So now once we go back to a browser you can see that all of the events are working as we wanted them
to at the start of this lecture.
After this lecture you should be starting to get the hang of converting visualizations into the object
oriented style that we using to structure a pages.
You'll often find yourself going through this process from working with new visualizations but the payoff
is huge Once you already have these visualizations in the format that you want them in.
I've also taken me through the process of adding in events to update things between different visualizations
creating event handlers within Manger's file which coordinate things across a visualisations in the
next lecture.
I'll be talking about brushes and D-3 which allow us to select ranges in a different way than we've
been doing so far.