In this lecture I'll be introducing brushes and D-3 which offer as a way to make a selection by the
drag of the mouse for this course we'll be using brushes to create a context and focus effect for our
visualizations allowing users to get a closer look at a particular part of that data while keeping track
of how it fits with the rest of the graph.
By the end of this lecture we'll have added a connotates graphed the line shot that we've been working
with in this section this lecture should also give you some experience with handling events across objects
as well as adding some more events and uprush selection links to each of the components on the page.
Here's what we're trying to build with a brush by the end of this lecture we've added in this smaller
area charts at the bottom of the screen which is showing the same data as a line graph.
When we drag a mouse over this area we can select a range of data that we want to show a mange.
We can also pan this box over the extensive graph to pick a certain possible data to show and we can
change the size of this box by dragging its corners.
This is a nice interactive way to pick a date range for a graph which is more playful and interesting
just using a regular Jane queery you slider.
You'll often see this graph at the bottom referred to as the context graph.
Since it's fixed axis means that it will always show the broader context of what our charts are telling
us.
The main graph is then referred to as the focus graph since it shows a focused view of the data at a
particular range and time we put this graph together by using D-3 brush generator after creating an
empty group and calling a rush function on it.
D-3 will add these elements onto our charts.
We have an overlay which we can drag a mouse over to reposition our brush.
We have a selection area which is the shaded box that shows what we have selected.
And we have two handles which we can play around with on either side of our selection to fine tune the
parts of the graph that should be shown in focus chaat for this course will only be using one dimensional
brushes meaning that they're only selecting an area on the X axis of a context chart we can follow a
simple three step process to add a brush on to any chart that we using.
Firstly we need to clear out brush generators somewhere in our code where we can select properties like
the size and position of the brush and how we want the brush handles to look next.
We need to run our brush generates it by calling it on the context of our visualization.
This should look similar to how we created our axes and G-3 as we'll just be adding a group Halman onto
our visualization and then calling the brush function on that finally we'll need to add an event handler
onto the brush event so that whenever the brush change position so that whenever the brush changes positions
we can update our focus chart to show the data that we've selected.
Starting off with the code that we had from the end of last lecture or shared the steps that we need
to take to add in this other graph to our visualization I've made a few changes already in the index
file I've added in another div after a line chart to contain a context chart which I'm referring to
as our timeline area.
I've also included the javascript file in O.J.'s directory which is going to set up the context chart
in my line of file.
I've decreased the height of the visualization a little so that everything fits on the page.
And in mange as file I've added an instance of a timeline onto a graph.
Let's take a look at our timeline file looks like.
This should all seem pretty similar to the code we wrote for our line up we giving the show a width
of 800 pixels which matches the width that we set for our line shown in the other file and I'm keeping
the left and right margins the same so that our graphs will line up vertically on the page we're adding
in some simple axes We're adding up paths for the first time and then in our update method we're updating
our scales and redrawing area.
Pat The main difference with our line chart is that we're not filtering out data based on the position
of update rate slider meaning the X-axis will always show the full extent of our data.
The coin that we're looking at.
Let me take you through the process of how we would add brush to this chart.
Firstly have written out the brush generator that I want to use the fact that we are using brush ex-school
rather than the Jaric brush cool means that we're explicitly telling D-3 that we wanted to create a
one dimensional brush that goes in the x direction.
And using the extent method here to define the minimum maximum coordinates the brush run between.
So this means that D-3 will create an overlay for a brush that runs from zero zero points of our visualization
area.
All the way down to the bottom right corner of the SPG grid.
This means that the user is able to draw a brush over any part of the visualisation area.
The next step is that we need to call the brush in the context of our visualization.
I've done this in the same way that we usually call the Xs generators on that visualization.
I just attached a group to our visualization area giving a color brush and I'm using the call method
to run uprush generator.
If we go back to a browser now we can see that this brush has been added to a context graph but it isn't
doing anything to a page yet we still need to add an event handler to a brush so that we can update
a line chart when the brush moves around.
I've added in this event handler to get the behavior that we're looking for whenever the brushes moved
we getting hold of the pixel values of brushless selected using this selection variable if the selection
is empty as it would be if the user clears the brush by clicking inside the brush area.
Then this value will equal the whole range of our scale.
We then calling the invert method of our timeline's X scale to give us the date values that this points
relate to then we're changing the values of our slider to match these dates and updating our line of
recall that the Rangle data method of our line job is sorting out which dates to show based on these
values for our slide.
So we don't need to do anything else to get the focus effect that we're looking for.
Finally all that's left to do is to go back and add in a call to brushed whenever a brush event fires
on a brush.
We're attaching the on events or the brush generator rather than the physical brush component here just
the brush component actually returns the entire group.
The brush gets added to once we refresh the page we can see that our line chart is now automatically
updating based on the selection that we're choosing.
However we still need to add in a few more events to a page.
For one thing a timeline chart should redraw its path whenever we change the coin or the variable that
we want to look at.
I also want to say that our brush component should update when we move the position of a query slider.
Since these controls are doing the same thing to the domain of a line chart to update context chart.
Whenever a coin or a variable changes it's as simple as adding in a call to our timelines Rangle data
method.
Whenever either of these events get fired I'll add in one call right here inside of variable listener
and I'll add another one down here in our coin change function which will up.
They are chart when Iraq coin select boxes change or when a tuna char X gets clicked.
Finally it's a little tricky it's updates up brush component whenever we want to but they slide around
here we're calling out is move method on the group that it was attached to.
We need to pass in a set of values which match the pixel positions that the brush selection should run
between.
We're starting off with our date values which we had originally and we're using this map function to
feed each of them into our timelines.
Scale this spits out the pixel values that these dates would take on a timeline and then we using those
to set the values of a brush I've then move the current dates date labels into the brushed function
since this quarter the brushes move and also fire the brushed event.
Once we refresh the page we can see that everything is working as expected.
Adding in this brush with the context chart lets our users keep hold of the bigger picture was still
able to zoom in on a particular point in that graph.
There are many other interesting uses for brushes that exist within the world of D-3.
But this effect is a particularly powerful tool which can often take a simple chart to the next level.
After this lecture you should understand how to use the D-3 brush function to implement a focus and
context effect for your visualization.
You'll be making one of these yourself and your final project as part of the data dashboard then you'll
be building.
You should also be starting to feel more comfortable working with visualizations that are spread across
multiple different files linking these views together to form a more fully interactive page in the next
lecture.
I'll be helping you to get set up with your final class project where you'll be creating a data dashboard
to help a company to keep tabs on employee performance across different sales teams.