In this lecture I'll be introducing you to your final project in this course where you'll be building
a data dashboard for a large American company as usual.
I'll be giving you some background on what the project involves in this lecture and I'll be taking you
through the files that I'll be starting off with
for your final project.
I'll be asking you to imagine that you've been headhunted by an executive from a freedom called one
of America's largest companies to build the data dashboard for their sales teams freedom Corp. specializes
in selling all kinds of wholesale goods to companies across the nation.
They sell raw materials like planks of wood and bags of cement to construction companies.
They sell TVs and computers to electronic stores they sell fridges and washing machines to household
appliance stores and they also sell a range of furniture to a few different outlets.
The company has been going through a tough phase over the past year or so and they want to find out
which parts of their business are doing better than others.
Their sales team is split between four different regions of the U.S. and for each region they want to
be able to see how their stats compare between them.
You've been given a file containing information every sales call that was completed by each team in
2017.
Freedom Corp. wants to see how you call duration revenue perk freedom Corp. wants to see how call duration
revenue per core and the number of units sold has been changing throughout the year.
Here is what you'll be building over the course of this project.
The main part of the dashboard will be this stacked area chards here which we can zoom in on by brushing
on the context graph at the bottom of the screen.
We also have four charts on the right which is showing summary data for the date range that we've selected.
This time your code wants to take an average of each of these metrics.
Every time the date selection changes let me take you through the code and starting with in your index
file I've set up the page as usual with a bootstrap grid.
Hey we have a label to display the date range that the user selected with the brush.
And here we have a select box where the user can choose the variable that should be shown on the main
graph.
Here are the divs that you'll be using to attach to your stacked area chart and your context chart and
here's where you'll be attaching the four other visualisations.
I've also included five javascript files which will need to build this site in the main file I've just
loaded in the data set that you'll be using for the project.
Logging this and that console as you can see we have 5000 rows of data showing all of Freedom Corp sales
calls from January to December 2017.
As usual you'll need to perform some operations on this data as soon as it gets loaded and this page
should handle all the data loading for the page.
Create new instances of each of our visualization objects and contain all the events and global variables
that your page will use.
For your donut charts I'm giving you the file that I created over the last two lectures which already
counted in Opie's style you want to convert this code so that you can make a stacked area chart object
in your main file.
And again you'll need to make a few changes so that it fits with your data.
Similarly I've included the time line.
Yes file that I was using in the last lecture.
You also need to make a few edits to this to use it for this project.
For your stacked area chards I'm stuffing you up with the code that I watch through back in Section
7.
You want to convert this code so that you can make a stacked area chart object in your main file.
And again you'll need to make a few changes so that it fits with your data.
I've done the same with your batch file taking an example implementation from Mike busto that I've found
on blocks.
After this lecture you should be ready to get started with this final project which should help you
to cement your understanding of all the different topics that we've covered.
If you're feeling a little uneasy or any of the syntax that you'll need to build the dashboard then
you can always flick back to earlier in the course and re watch some of the lectures you might find
that re watching the lecture about stack area charts and Section 7 will be particularly helpful for
getting started with the main graph that you'll be building if you get stuck.
And as always you can either leave questions in the comments section or check out my solution on get
up.
However as always I would always recommend that you should try to solve these problems yourself first
using any resources that you can.
However as always I would recommend that you should try to solve these problems yourself using any resources
that you can find online to help you on this project.
You'll often find yourself using both the D-3 API reference as well as community code from Brox to figure
out exactly what's going wrong with your code.