Congratulations.
Great job.
After finishing your final project you're now at an advanced level with D-3 where you can handle complex
data visualization projects all by yourself.
The data dashboard that you just built wouldn't look out of place on a real companies web site you'd
synthesize the knowledge that you've been gradually building up throughout the course which is culminated
in a really impressive set of base ations this section was focused on the challenge of handling multiple
visualizations on the page which introduced you to writing your visualizations as objects using the
project structure that we've been using together with this object oriented approach.
It should serve you well going forward whenever you start to tackle visualization projects of your own.
In the next section of your wrapping up the course running through a broad overview of everything that
we've covered and summing up with a few final thoughts.