Great job! After the finishing up that last class project you're now able to do some really impressive stuff
with D3. You've show that you're able to handle complex interactions between many different components
on the page and you've built something that could easily be adapted to form the building blocks of any
data dashboard.
Beyond that you should now feel comfortable with exploring new data visualizations by yourself, and even
designing and building your own you know had to search for what the D3 community is already put together
with most visualizations and you should be comfortable with flicking through someone else's code to
figure out what's going on.
In this section I'll be running you through everything we've covered in this course and I'll leave you
with a few final thoughts.