In this lecture, I want to give you a quick summary of what you learned in this course.
We covered a lot of content in D3, going all the way from complete novice level at the start, to a level
where you're able to build incredible data visualization pages.
at the end.
In the first few sections of the course, I taught you about the simplest components of D3 that would
keep coming up again and again as the material became more advanced. You learned about how SVGs and work
how to append them to the screen with D3, and you had a basic primer in the D3 data join. In Section 4,
I introduced you to the fundamentals of visualization design. In section 5, we started adding updates
onto our visualizations.
And by the end of section 6, the user could directly interact with elements on the page. In Section 7, 8 and
9,
I gave you a quick run through of a whole host of different visualizations. On the way, we covered important
topics like layouts, nests, and Queues, which you'll see everywhere going forward in D3. Finally, in the
last section, I taught you the proper file structure to use to create a fully-fledged web app, where our visualizations
could communicate with each other through events in a control file. We gradually added complexity with
our projects as the course went on.
We started off with just a few rectangles in the page which turned into a bar chart. We added in updates
to make a clone of Gapminder's
bubble chart.
And then we added in events to make an interactive line chart.
Finally the final project represented the culmination of everything that you learned in the course,
as you created the professional data dashboard with many visualizations on the page at once.