So that's it.
This is as far as I can take you in the world of T-3.
Like most things with programming courses like these can only take you so far.
The way for you to take your skills to the next level is by practicing with more and more real world
projects.
I don't know what your main motivation will have been when you first set out that journey of learning
to but there are endless possibilities the kinds of fascinating visualizations that you are now able
to create.
There are lots of places out there where you can find open source data sets for a range of different
purposes.
My favorite one is here at Kaggle dot com where users can upload data on just about anything.
All of the data sets are rated according to how interesting they are and they cover a huge range of
different topics.
I hope that by now you're used to the process of appropriating other people's code and figuring out
how to use these snippets in your projects.
Don't be afraid to give back to this community as well by sharing the code that you write for others
to use.
You can contribute to the vibrant community that makes the three best visualization library out there.
I hope that you enjoy taking this course.
It's been a pleasure to teach you.
I've learned a lot by creating these lectures and it's been a fantastic experience for me to get to
share this knowledge with you.