Hello and welcome to mastering data visualization and D3.js.
.
My name is Adam and I'll be the one to take you through the journey of learning D   3.
I work as a freelance data visualization engineer using my knowledge of D 3 to build complex Front-End
systems for businesses.
I've been living and working remotely for over a year now, picking up interesting projects from companies
all around the world.
I designed and built data dashboards for successful startups including consulting roles teaching CEOs
about the best way to design their products.
I worked at a large NGO to communicate the results of a 20,000 person study of youths around the world
and I've been a coach and mentor
to new
learners of D3 who are just starting off on the same path.
I first picked up my skills in data visualization at Harvard University where I was a computer science student
I first learned the material that I'll be teaching in this course.
Although the bulk of what you'll learn will revolve around the finer points that D-3 library, the course
is also structured to give you a formal introduction to the principles of design.
I'll teach you how to effectively showcase your ideas justifying design decisions to your colleagues
and also teach you how to discern between good and bad visualizations and how to avoid the most common
pitfalls of design.
We'll be working through four exciting projects which are all relevant to the real world and you'll
be following along every step of the way.
As we gradually add complexity onto what we can do with D3. By the end of this course you'll
be able to create new and exciting visualizations of the web's premier visualization library.
You'll learn to design and build your own projects to work with the data that matters to you the most
and we'll be covering advanced topics in D-3 like brushes,
choropleths and layouts. We'll also be using the latest version of D-3: version 5.
If you don't have much prior experience in web development then I suggest that you take a primer course
in both JavaScript and jQuery before launching into this course. You'll want to feel comfortable with selecting
elements on screen and interacting with the document object model in order to get the most out of
this experience.
This course is meant for you if you want to build user interfaces that can add real value right away.
If you want to stand there from the crowd and generate new and interesting ideas and if you want to
change the way that you see data in the world around you.