In this lecture, I'll be giving you a general overview of how this course will look.
I'll be talking about how the course is split into three different parts, and I'll introduce you to the
four class projects that you complete at different stages.
In each of the first few sections of the course, I'll be teaching new concepts that should add onto the
previous sections to give you a strong foundation in D3. You'll learn how to render SVGs to the screen
to express data.
You learn how to use scales and axes for some common visualizations like bar charts and scatterplots.
You'll be making visualizations that dynamically update to changing data, and you'll be making interactive
visualizations that react to user input.
Importantly, I'll be helping you to thoroughly understand the D3 update pattern, teaching you what's
going on behind the scenes, which will allow you to make any visualization that you can imagine.
In sections 7, 8, and 9, I'll be giving you a crash course in a range of different visualizations, showing
you how the principles that we learned in the first phase of the course can help us to quickly pick
up any type of visualization. I'll be stepping you through sunburst plots,
node-link diagrams, choropleth maps,
treemaps,
trees, area charts, and more, and I'll be teaching you the process of finding, interpreting, and adapting
any kind of visualization by yourself.
Finally, in Section 10, you'll be writing complex linked views, where visualizations on the page communicate
to each other through a controller file.
At this point, your page will be handling updates for several different charts at once, which will be
rendering as javascript objects, which will also make code more reusable for future projects.
You'll complete four different class projects in this course, which will gradually become more complex as
your skill level increases. For your first project,
you'll be making a simple bar chart for a friend's business.
You can see that at this point, the visualization will be fairly simple and won't really exceed anything
that you could whip up in Microsoft Excel. For your second project,
You'll be making an updating scatterplot, based on a famous visualization from Gapminder, showing how
countries' incomes have increased with life expectancy over time.
Here, we already have a complex visualization, with data coming from positional attributes as well as
from the size and color of the circles. In your third project,
you'll be creating a line chart that tracks cryptocurrency data over time, which can show different coins
with different metrics like price and trading volume, and can be filtered based on a date range.
At this point, you'll be able to manage a complex system that is updating automatically, and you'll develop
a production quality interface, working with real data. Finally, for your last project,
you'll be building a data dashboard to keep tabs on different sales teams' performance at a large conglomerate
company. Here, your data will be split across different files and you'll simultaneously be rendering
six separate visualizations to the screen.