By now, I hope that you're ready for the challenge of learning D3,
and excited by the possibilities that this powerful JavaScript library has to offer.
You should now know a basic amount about visualizations, and you should understand why D3 is such a
great entry point for web development work.
You also know what to expect from the course as I've shown you what you'll be learning across three
different stages, and you've had a look at the four class projects that
you'll get to complete. In the next section,
I'll be helping you to get set up with your development environment,
using D3 by yourself, and I'll be introducing you to some of the most important concepts for the library.
You'll be writing your first lines of D3 code, and attaching your first SVGs to the screen.