At the end of last section we ended up with something that actually looked like a real visualization.
We were communicating some data using rectangles on the screen to represent the heights at different
buildings.
But where did the height values for those rectangles come from.
I actually just gave you some real numbers that will be the right size to fit on your ass Ficci.
Candace over the course of this section will gradually expand on the visualization that you ended up
with at the end of last section to turn it into a bar chart.
I'll be teaching at to use scales in D-3 to take in more data and spits out some values that we can
work with.
We'll also be adding in some axes and labels to make it look more like a typical bar chart.
And are we making the rectangles rise up from the bottom of the canvas rather than hanging down from
the top at the end of the section you'll be ready to take on our first project in this class.
You'll be helping a friend who owns a burgeoning coffee chain to make a simple bar chart communicates
his sales figures to investors.