This lecture I'm going to introduce you to scale's explain why we need them for our visualizations and
show you the syntax that we'll use for any skills from the visualization from the end of last section
I gave you your height values reach building used to your size.
I computed these values myself.
So these buildings would have the right portions.
This will only work for completely static visualization.
What if we suddenly wants to show a building which is taller than a tall building.
We would need to increase the size of our SPG canvas or we compute all the values in our dataset for
it to fill the screen.
This is why we need scales.
Three according to Mike Bostock one of the creators of D-3 scales a functions that map from an input
domain to an output range.
What do we mean by this domain domain corresponds to the raw data that we want to put into us.
And the range comes 1 to the value that we want to get out to the scale.
Looking at this diagram should give you a good intuition for what's going on.
I want you to think about scale as being like a magical black box that takes an input and spits out
an output.
We need to set this black box with a domain and range value for it to work.
Let's imagine that we have an SPG with a height of 400 pixels.
I want to say the minimum height for any rectangle should be zero.
If we have a building of zero meters tall and the maximum height of any rectangle should be 400 pixels
representing the tallest building that we want to show.
So the range of this scale our output is going to be between 0 and 400 for the domain we want to take
an interval between 0 and the height of our tallest building which is 828 meters.
So the domain should be between zero and a 128 for this scale if we put in an input of zero.
The scale would spit out the rows and outputs.
If we put in an input that eight hundred twenty eight the scale would spit out 400 as an output.
In this example we have an input of 414 which is the middle of the mains.
The output is hundred.
The middle of range we can also do something similar with colors.
If we pass in strings of two different colors for the range here we can see how the scale would look.
It finds a color which is 30 percent of the way between red and blue.
This type of scale would come in handy if we wanted to make something like a heat map which would convert
a piece of continuous data into a color.
Let's take a look at what the syntax looks like for linear scale the function that we want to use is
called D-3 scale linear and we need to use the domain and range methods to set up the domain and range
in both taking an array of 2 values representing the minimum and maximum values for each.
When we store the scale as a variable this becomes a function that we can use the function will take
one argument which the input value that we want to scale the standard naming convention for scales and
D-3 is to use the name of the axis that the scale will apply to.
So I'm calling this variable y.
But we could just have easily name this function or something else from the console logs underneath
we can see what the scale is doing.
If we put in a value of 100 which would be a relatively small building then we'd get back a value of
just over 48 pixels.
And we think if we have an input of 700 we get a value of around three hundred thirty eight.
Another thing to note is that we can use the inverse method of a scale to find the domain value which
is associated with something in the range for example if you wanted to know how tall a building would
need to be to have a pixel value of forty eight point three then we could call why don't invert with
an argument of forty eight point three.
And it would return 100.
So these three cores to white or invert are basically doing the opposite thing to what three chords
to Wyat doing.
We'll be using the invert method later in the course but we want to get the position of the cursor on
the screen.
Flicking back to code we can use a scale like this to set the heights of our rectangles.
I've copied the scale that we just saw into my main geus file and have changed the building.
Jason File from last section have all meta values instead of pixel values.
If we load the page at this point we can see that everything runs off the page.
The smallest height value in metres is greater than the height of size Fiji.
So it runs up the screen.
All that we need to do to fix this is to pass the height values into a scale function before we return
it as the value of height attributes.
Once we do that we can see that we end up with the same thing that we had from last section but this
time these heights are coming from our scale.
We use a linear scale in this example because we want the height of the rectangles to be directly proportional
to the height of the buildings.
There are other types of scales that we can use for different purposes which will introduce you to the
next few sections.