In this lecture be teaching about log scales and why we might need to use them instead of linear scales
in some situations.
I'll also run through the syntax which looks pretty familiar from the last lecture.
Sometimes you might find that you're working with a variable which is increasing exponentially over
time.
In this example because population is increasing so rapidly if you want to show population size much
further in time then it would seem like the population in the first half of the graph was basically
the same level.
In cases like these it becomes more useful to use a logarithmic scale rather than a linear scale.
For example for a second class project we want to show how different countries GDP per capita is changing
over time.
As you can see a linear scale doesn't express this data very well.
The domain of scale ranges from about $300 to $150000 which means that a lot of wasted space to fit
in the most extreme data points when we're looking at the countries in the year eighteen hundred.
They all seem to be about the same level of wealth.
In reality some of the countries are an order of magnitude better off than others.
We can see this in the image on the right of our screen when GDP per capita is around $4000 per year.
The richest countries and around $400 per year in the poorest countries are large scale is a much better
job using this space on our screen to show the difference between these countries.
Looking at this with our black box analogy again a large scale was pretty similar to what lineas go
we supply it with minimum and maximum values for its domain and range.
And we get an output when we give it an input.
We can also give it a base value which people tend.
This means that the output values of inputs are five hundred five thousand 50000 will be spaced equally
because that all factors of 10 part.
If we wanted to use a base value of two instead then this would mean that our values for 500 1000 2000
would be equally spaced because they'd all be factors of two of us.
We can play around with the base value as much as we like to make up visualizations as useful as possible.
A log scale with the base of one actually works out to be the same as the linear scale.
Something to note here is that the domain for a log scale need to be strictly positive or strictly negative
because the log of zero is always undefined.
If you try to make a log scale and D-3 that contain zero in its domain then the scale just simply won't
work.
To create a log scale we use D-3 scale log in terms of the syntax.
It's almost identical to a linear scale except that it uses an optional base method.
We're giving the scale a name of X this time because the scale is for x axis.
We can see the same inputs and outputs as a black box.
When we run these console logs and again we can use the invert method to go from a range back to a domain.
Now that you know how and when to use a large scale.
Next up will be running through time scales which are a special variation of linear scales that deal
with dates.