In this lecture I'll be covering timescales which you'll often want to use in your visualizations a
time scale is actually a type of linear scale and D-3 but his domain works with javascript data objects
instead of integers.
His domain is between the first of January 2000 and the first of January 2002.
One if we put in the date around the middle of these two dates we get a value that's in the middle of
our range.
So here we can see that the time scale is mapping the first of July 2000 to a value of 200 which makes
sense because we're giving it the midpoint of our domain and we getting back the midpoint of our range.
In case you haven't used javascript data objects before.
We're creating new data objects here by passing in the year month and day that we want.
It shouldn't surprise you.
The syntax here is identical to our linear scale.
As the time scale is just a special version of it that deals with dates.
If you want to do this with actual data rather than just creating a dummy data object you will need
to convert a string representation of a data to a javascript data object.
You will learn how to do this in section 6 when I'll be taking you through parsing and formatting into
three.
Hopefully you're getting the hang of scales by now and you can see how the syntax is working.
Next lecture will be covering ordinal scales to use for assigning color schemes to categories where
the syntax will be a little different when we're setting the domain.