In this lecture I'll be talking about ordinals Gayles which are frequently using whenever you want to
use color in your visualizations and also show you how to use the color schemes that T-3 provides us
with that generate quick and easy colors for us to use.
Sometimes we want to use scales to work with discrete data like a collection of categories instead of
continuous data.
For this we need to use an ordinal scale will pretty much only be using this type of scale when we want
to associate different categories with different colors.
But it can be used to associate any two strings with each other for an ordinal scale the domain and
range are always arrays of values and the scale will provide a mapping between them based on that position
and the array.
For example if we put Africare into this scale it spits out red because that both index zero in their
array.
And if we put ajor into this array it will spit out blue because then both index for an array.
If we use the ordinal scale it's something that isn't in the domain then D-3 adds this value it's a
domain for us associating it with the next available range.
So in this case putting Antarctica into a scale We'll add it to the domain and associate it with the
color gray.
If the more values in the domain and in the range then the scale will start to loop back to the start
of our range was signing new mappings for example after we put Antarctica into upscale the domain and
range will each have set values.
If we try to insert Pangea as well then our scale doesn't have a free value that can use that range.
So it looks back and assigns that the value index 0 which is red.
If we wanted to call the scale and another value that isn't in our domain then the scale will assign
it to orange then yellow.
So to save us from having to pick a new array of colors every time we want to make a color scale D-3
comes with a few useful functions to generate color schemes for us we can use any of these categorical
scales from that DS3 scale chromatic module which is included with the three.
And this will automatically generate some colors for us as you can imagine.
The syntax is a little different as we need to supply an array of strings to the daily method.
On the left I'm using the example from earlier and on the right amusing one of the D-3 color schemes
that range there is no method that can be used for an ordinal scale because it's possible for multiple
domain values to map to the same range value next lecture Perales scale will be returning to our buildings
visualisation to demonstrate band scales which are pretty much exclusively meant to be used for bartk.