In this lecture I'll be explaining band scales which I used to space that rectangle is what we want
to make for charts.
I'll be showing you how the scales look nobody making some edits to a building bar chart from the last
section.
Going back to the code from the last section we have a similar problem that we need to address with
the X-axis as the one we had with the y axis although we can automatically adjust the heights of rectangles
if RJJ it changes things that lineas scale that we made for a y axis with an explanation value for our
rectangles are hardcoded based on that with the ASCII G.
If we wanted to add another building into our data giving us the six tallest building as well then we'd
need to resize and reposition our rectangles or make our SPG wider.
We will be using Ben's skills to do this which are less scale that you'll need to know of course band
scale that pretty much exclusively used to space out different categories in a bar chart which is what
we're trying to do with our buildings.
You can see what a band scale looks like in this diagram the scale splits up the range the band equal
length based on how many elements as the main we give the scale and the array of categories that we
want to display as their main and a minimum and maximum value for the range which defines the pixel
positions that we want that chart to be spaced over.
We also need to provide ratios for padding out certain padding in which defines how thick the bars should
be.
If we pass in an input then the square will return the starting position of the band that the category
maps do.
We also have access the width of the bands through the band width method of the scale and we can use
the step method to get the distance between the start of adjacent bands.
Looking at this from our black box analogy again we need to give the scale an array of strings for the
main just like an ordinal scale.
For the range things look similar to a linear scale taking two integers representing the minimum and
maximum pixel values that will be scaling between.
We also need to provide padding in the padding adds value which need to be a number between 0 and 1.
If we use a padding in a value 0 then there will be no space between any of the bars.
If we use the padding out of value of 0 then there'll be no padding between the first the last bars
at the edge of the SPG.
Candace looking at these examples we can see that our scale wants to position the South American band
that 209 pixels which makes sense because it is the fourth element in our array.
So the ban should be a little bit right of the middle.
Similarly we get a value of thirteen point one for the start of our African band because there are no
bends before it and it's just a little bit of padding something to note with bends scales is that we
can't add new values in the same way that we could for ordinal scale.
So if we try to call it on a value that doesn't exist in the domain then the scale will just return
undefined taking a look at the syntax here.
Nothing should be too surprising the domain should be similar to the domain of an ordinal scale and
the range should be similar to the range of linnus scale.
We also use the padding in there and padding out to methods figure out how much whitespace we want between
each bands in the final console log on the screen you can see that we have access the bandwidth of a
scale which will come in handy for a chart to set the weights of our different rectangles.
Let's take a look at how we would use this band scale in our world's tallest buildings chart.
This should look really familiar.
I'm using a range between zero and 400 to reflect the size of our SPG canvas and I'm passing in the
strings about building names that we had an adjacent file.
I've started up with a value of four point two for both the padding in and the padding outer and we
can adjust that value later depending on what it looks like.
Now if we wanted to pass in one of our building names such as the Burj Khalifa or X scale then we should
get the x coordinates where the rectangle should be positioned.
I'll try this out with a console log.
This value looks about right for the first by an up arch up.
We have a little bit of room.
The padding outer Jamaica x values come from X scale.
We just need to return the value that we get from passing a building name into the X scale.
We also need to update the width property and we can give a value of x bandwidth
once you refresh the screen and we can see the changes that this has on rectangles.
This is working as expected but I'll fiddle around with the padding values to make the rectangle a little
narrower.
Where the value of no point free I think that this looks about right now.
Let's say that I want to go back and adding two more buildings to my data.
I did a quick search on Wikipedia for the sixth and seventh tallest buildings in the world and then
added values in here.
One World Trade Center and the Guangzhou so CTF finance center.
If we refresh the page it might look like we have a problem here because the scale didn't readjust.
But it turns out that we still need to add in new buildings to the main
typing in both of these values.
Now we can see that our bands have adjusted keeping the same proportions as for congratulations.
You now know all of the most common types of scale that you'll need to make pretty much any visualization.
We also now have a charge that can display any number of buildings of any size which is a real step
forward.
Next lecture will be making another improvement to our code so that we don't need to set the main uses
hardcoded numbers.