In this lecture I'm going to be talking about free Hendee functions but D-3 gets us to automatically
set the domains for us.
Galles I'll also be talking about map functions in javascript which are useful for setting domains for
categorical data.
It's pretty annoying to have to write in new values for their main whenever we update a data.
It wasn't too bad when we're just adding two new buildings in the last lecture.
But what if we needed to add hundreds of items to our domain.
Once we might have the same problem with Y-axis to for instance what if we had 10 new buildings at the
two adjacent file and we weren't sure whether any of them would be taller than our tallest building.
We'd need to manually search through our data and check for us selves and then update the Y scale domain
if necessary.
Ideally we want to write functions that will automatically set our domains Fouras G-3 provides three
useful functions that we'll be using all the time to do just that.
The three men did three max and D-3 extend.
Here we have an example dataset we shouldn't look too different from our buildings data.
We have an array of three objects which each have a grade and about property minimax and extends all
work in more or less the same way they take into arguments an array of data and the callback function
the callback function will loop over every item in the array for each item we need to return the piece
of data that we're interested in and the men nag's or extent function we'll compare these values and
return the relevant data.
For example the main function here is taking out great data and we're providing it with each of the
grade values.
This callback function.
The result is that it looks at three numbers that we're staring into and it spits out the number two
which is the smallest the max function is doing the same thing except it'll spit out the largest value
for if we provide the extent function with the same two arguments then it will return an array of the
minimum maximum values.
In this case the array of 2 for with discrete data we can use a map functional data right to come up
with an array of names.
This will be useful when we want to write and scales and ordinal scales as it can save us from having
to hard code a long list of categories springs into javascript code on the right of the screen as you
can see how we'll be using minimax and extend our scales when we're using minimax.
It's important to bear in mind that our domain takes an array of values.
So we need to enclose these values in square brackets.
Which will give you an array of 2 and 4.
First example this would mean an input value of will be scaled to output zero and a value for Biscoe
to 400 with doing the same thing using D-3 extent in our second example.
We say US space finally you know third example we using a map function pass in an array of string to
our domain which will associate each of these values with a band position between 0 and 400 pixels.
If we use these X and Y scales to create a bar chart then it would look something like the image of
the bottom of the screen going back to our code.
This section I'm going to incorporate these functions into us scales.
First we can get rid of this messy array of names here and we can use the map function to generate this
array for us
for each element.
This map function should return the building name that relates to giving us the complete list of buildings
for our domain for our linear scale we still want to use 0 for the minimum about domain.
So we'll just use D-3 max for this.
I'm passing in an array of data and the first argument to D-3 Max
and for the second argument our anonymous function is pointing towards the buildings Heidfeld you.
So if we fire this up now in the browser that we can see that everything is still working as expected
at this point our scales are getting pretty much all of that information from the data which makes our
code really usable in the next activity.
I want you to make sure that you have a good handle on different scales that you covered.
So you're ready to start using them in your first project.