In this lecture I'll be talking about SVGA groups which are a type of invisible SVGA element for organizing
data which will be using to make up visualization conform with the D-3 Moggi convention which will be
needing to use age when we want to at accedes next lecture.
In 3 we tend to define a margin to round up visualization which can be tweaked within a maned of X-File
these margins are allowed to use threes inbuilt access generators to acces the top left bottom right
about visualization.
It also allows us to better tweak the dimensions of our visualizations directly from within our javascript
files the way that we implement the margin convention in D-3 is by attaching everything to an SPG group
element which we can translate into the central Canlis SPG group elements are containers for different
shapes as elements groups don't have any visual presence by themselves are they useful in the tree as
they can bundle graphical elements together and apply transformations to many shapes at once.
For example let's say that we have three squares on SVGA Kandace.
If we decide that we need to move each of these squares 200 pixels to the right then we could change
each of the X attributes by 200.
However if we needed to do this with 100 squares then this could get pretty tedious if all squares were
instead contained inside of an SPG group element and we could apply what's called the transformation
of the group a transformation allows us to alter the position of every element that is contained within
the group.
At the same time for instance we can use a translation to move the entire group 200 pixels to the right.
We apply a transformation with the groups transform intervened which takes a function for a translation
The function takes an X and a Y value which expresses how far the cube should be shifted in the positive
direction of our candidates.
If we want to move the group towards the top left of the screen then we can supply negative values to
this function.
We can also use a different kind of transformation on groups to rotate switches which we'll be doing
in the next lecture for a y axis label this code lays out the standard set up for our SPG canvas which
will be using from this point onwards.
We defined the margin here as an object pass to mean values to find the top right bottom and left margins
the entire SVGA Cambers will have a weight of 960 and the height of 500 in this example.
But we are deducting the margins from a height and width variables so that we can plug them into different
parts of the visualization without needing to worry about the margins.
Let's work this Margene convention into a bar chart to see how this looks like in practice.
At the end of the next lecture we should hopefully have a chart that looks something like this.
We will be appending all of our rectangles to a group element and we'll need to leave enough space in
the left and bottom margin for an x and y axes with this in mind.
All right my margin with 100 pixels on the left and bottom and 10 pixels at the top and the right.
We can always adjust these values later on if we end up needing a little more space than expected.
So I'm defining a margin as an object at the top of our main Jaspal passing in all of our different
values.
Then we want to set the height and width values for our visualisation these values are going to define
the size of the group that we're attaching everything to and won't include the space that we're leaving
for.
With that in mind I'm starting with a width of 600 pixels and the height of 400 pixels here and taking
off the horizontal and vertical margins from these numbers.
I'm also going to sub out the hard coded values for a width and height for setting on SVGA size and
domain the size of our SPG canvas actually wants to include our margins as well so that axes can render
properly on the canvas.
So I'm adding these back in here.
Now occurred is a lot more reusable because we can now just change the size of our visualization in
one place and not have to worry about changing values all across the file.
Next I want to append a group to our canvas which should have a transform attribute that translates
our visualization into the center
to do this we need to shift it to the left by the value of the left margin and shifted downwards by
the value of our top margin.
Then of course after I rename this variable i need to go in and update the code later on when we're
appending our rectangles to the screen.
Now that we have our margins set up we can see that our visualization is a little smaller and it's being
pushed a little into the center of the screen.
Let's take a look at our group using our browsers element inspect.
If I hover over this group element here and we can see what our margins are doing.
We now have some space for axes to live which will be adding in in the next lecture.
After this lecture our code is far more clean and reusable than before.
And we also have some margins where we'll be putting on x and y axes labels in the next lecture.
We'll be adding these pieces to a graph which will let our users see exactly what they're looking at.