For most types of chod it's important to have some kind of axes that give us a reference point to interpret
data from our.
The moment isn't particularly useful if our users don't already know what these bars are meant to represent.
We can't tell which building is which.
And our chart only expresses relative heights between the buildings.
In this lecture we'll be adding an X in the y axis to our chart and we'll be adding in some labels indiscreet
version before we can use one of four different axes generators to create axes for this example we'll
be using D-3 access left and D-3 X's bottom but we could also have used D-3 access right and D-3 access
top.
It's important to know that each of these scale the rended the origin point device weekenders when we
first add them to the screen that's fine if the axis is on the left or at the top.
But if we want the axes on the bottom or on the right of our graph we want to attach our access to a
group and give it a translation for the button.
This will once you give it a translation of the height of visualization and the y direction for an axis
on the rides.
We need to shift it by the width about visualization in the x direction.
Let's take a look at the syntax here.
Follow the X generators working we're making a call to one of these Xs generators passing in the relevant
scales.
Our only argument then we're attaching SPG group to our visualization giving it a translation if necessary.
And then we use the call method to run the Xs generator.
D-3 also gives us some methods that we can use on axes generators to customize how the text should look.
We can change the length of our text using these three methods here.
To take salaries out of method will only affect the outermost takes the take sides in a method will
any effect.
It takes and the regular tick size method will affect them all equally.
If you use the tick size method alongside one of the other two methods and the last one that gets called
will be the one that counts.
We can also define how many takes should be shown on the axes by using the ticks method.
Here we giving an argument of 10 meaning the axis should try to show roughly 10 ticks because D-3 uses
a special algorithm to make the ticks values as neat as possible.
The X is often one containing exactly the right number of takes that we ask for.
But at least try to be fairly close.
We can use the take format method to choose how we want to display or take values.
We can do this with D-3 format which will cover in section 5 or we can use just use an anonymous function
which gives us access to the point that the tick is showing.
We can then apply some kind of transformation to it which will do for this section.
Finally if you get annoyed by the finicky nature of these tick generators then you can just pass in
the specific values that you want to display as an array with the take values function if you use take
values as well as tick format then the access generator will pass the values that you supply onto the
tape format method so that you can format these accordingly.
Let me take you through how this looks.
In the case of our chart first a right to access generators will use D-3 access button for x axis passing
and X scale and D-3 X is left for a y axis passing in a Y scale.
Next I'm going to group elements to our visualization area.
One for each axis for our x axis we're going to need to remember to translate this group by the height
of our visualization
and a Y axis will be in the right position already.
So we don't need to worry about shifting it
finally Arcola access generators on both of these elements with the Coleman.
So now we have two axes rendering on the screen as we expected.
Something to note here is that on our x axis our take values are overlapping each other to fix this.
I'm going to apply a rotation to all of the text elements in the x axis group I'm using Select all here
on x axis group to get a hold of all the text SVGA that are Xs generators appendant for us for each
of the text SVGA inside that Access Group.
I'm adding a transform attribute to rotate them.
We're applying a rotation transformation here.
In a similar way to the translations that you've already seen the rotate function just takes one arguments
which should be the number of degrees that the SVGA should be rotated in a clockwise direction.
So here I'm passing in a value of minus 40 means that all these text elements are rotated 40 degrees
anti-clockwise.
I've also moved these SVGA around with the x and y attributes.
So they line up with take marks and said that text and gets and is.
They all line up.
I'm also going to fiddle around with the takes on the y axis to show you how a few of these methods
are working hair I'm telling otic generator.
I only want it to be three ticks and I'm using a special format function to show all the values and
metas.
All I'm doing is using this function to edit and character after age of odd numbers you can see that
D-3 reduced the number of takes to five here.
But it wasn't able to make the numbers work out with only three ticks for completeness.
I'm also going to add in some labels to our visualization.
So the user can clearly see what we're displaying or just do this with some text SVGA for both axes.
Here's the code I'm using for X label.
I'm giving an x coordinate.
They'll put it in the center of the axis I'm putting is y coordinates 150 pixels past the end of our
visualization area so that it sits under our x axis take labels.
I'm also saying the font size and I'm giving text anger middle.
So it's a with the center of the page.
Finally I'm passing in the text of the SVGA should display using the text method for a wine label.
I've rotated it by 90 degrees so it's in line with the y axis.
I'm passing in a value of minus 19 which represents a shift of 90 degrees and the anti-clockwise direction.
I'm also tweeting the x and y values so fit in the middle of axis because we're rotating the label the
same time.
Setting these values.
They look a little strange because we're reversing the X and Y positions of our label.
After this lecture you should feel comfortable with how the different access generators work.
And you now know about different commands that we have to edit.
Access takes you might notice that access seem to be upside down at the moment.
Can you figure out why this is happening.
We just have a few tweaks to make in the next lecture to fix a y scale at that point we'll have completely
finished the bcher you be ready to take on your first class project.