We just have a couple of tasks left to complete the turn of visualization and do a real job.
Our access is upside down at the moment and we also need to make our bodies rise up from the bottom
of the screen instead of hanging down from the top.
This will be tricky because we need to think about how the SPG coordinate system is working for us to
give our rectangles the right y coordinates and height values.
The reason why our Y axis is upside down is our scale is currently running from a value of zero to a
value of 828 in the positive direction.
As you remember from the SVGA coordinate system.
What this actually means is that the values will increase towards the bottom of the screen because the
zero point of a white grid is at the top of the canvas.
Let's take another look at the linear scale that we're using for our y axis at the moment our scale
transforms an input of 0 to an output zero and an input of 820 A to an output of 400.
So here us scale is placing the take for 4:0 meet and mark at the top of the screen.
Because when it uses a scale calling y with an argument of zero gives a value zero.
Similarly calling y with an argument of eight hundred twenty eight gives a value of four hundred.
So it places the take for 828 meters 400 pixels down our canvas.
Here's how the axis should really work passing in an argument of 0 2 Alwi scale need to return a value
of 400 pixels and passing in an argument of a hundred twenty eight needs to return a value of zero.
This means that putting a higher value into a scale should give us y coordinate on a normal grid starting
from 0 0 in the bottom left of the canvas.
The fixed will need to use Prus scale involves going from this to this.
So now a value of zero maps the bottom of the Canlis at 400 pixels down the grid and 828 maps to 0 which
is at the top of our canvas after we reversed the direction of a wide scale.
Things are going to look even worse.
What exactly is going on here.
From our code these bars height values are coming from a wide scale interpretation of the height of
the building.
So now the age of 28 maps to zero in our scale our tallest bar has a height of zero.
Let's think about what we need to change to fix this chart.
The height.
We actually want to display adjust the heights under the bars that we have now.
So what do we need to plug in for a hight values to get this behavior.
Here's what we want to look like the heights that a wide scale gives us for up should lie underneath.
We need to find this mystery Lent for an new buzz.
Since we know the heights of our visualization and we also know the space that we need under these bars
we can work this value out.
We just need to take off the Y scale interpretation of building heights from the height of the visualization.
We still have a problem here because Abaza hanging down from the top of the screen at the moment we're
just saying each of us has why attributes to the wrong value zero.
So they're sitting at the top of the page as you remember the space above these bars should be the y
scales value for the building heights.
If we plug this value in when we set Y attributes then this should work as expected.
So looking back at our code for this section I'll put these changes into action to fix our chart first
of reversing the range for a linear scale set that zero maps to the bottom of the SPG the top
next.
I'm going to change the height entropy about bars to the height of visualization minus the height that
we get from a wide scale.
Then finally I'm going to shift these bars the bottom of the screen by setting that y attribute is the
value from y scale.
And there we have it.
So now we finally have a finished product of a beautiful bocher on the screen.
Hopefully this lecture gave you a good refresher on how the coordinate system is working for us.
Fiji's you'll often find these SVGA aren't being placed in the way they should be.
So a great idea is just to write out a little grid and think about where exactly each of the x and y
values should be placed graphically next lecture.
I'll be introducing the first class project where you'll be making a batch of your own using what you
learned in this section.
Feel free to flick back to previous lectures if you can't remember the writes in text to use and get
your head around the process of setting up a new visualization.