In this lecture I'll be introducing you to your first class project and walk me through everything that
you're going to need.
I'll also talk about some resources that you can make use of for building this visualization.
You have a friend Paula who owns a burgeoning coffee chain called Star break coffee after opening half
a year ago.
She's been collecting sales data in an excel file and has noticed the change has been growing really
consistently.
She's heard that you've been taking this course and she wants you to make a simple batch of Web site
which is going to show to investors I'm giving you a project folder with everything you'll need to get
started in the index file.
I've already set up the shape of the site for you.
There's a simple nav bar at the top of the screen.
And I've given this site some basic styling for this project should be adding to this chart area to
live right here.
I've also included your main G-S file and the D-3 library which you'll find in the JSE directory since
poler collected her sales data in an excel file.
It's already in the CSA the formats required for the three seeis the function.
You can find this file here in your data folder.
Here's what your visualization should look like at the end of this project.
Download the project folder and write some D-3 code to really bring this data to life.
If you get stuck at any point in the process then there are a few simple things that you can do to help.
First of all you can watch videos of the past two sections to see how we made a last batch it.
This could be especially important at the start to jog your memory of all the syntax.
If you come across a bug in your code you're really not sure what's going wrong.
Then it can actually be a really rewarding process to try to figure out the problem for yourself.
I recommend making as many console logs as possible to make sure that your variables contain what you
expect them to.
If you can't figure it out by yourself then you can always ask questions in the comments section.
The activity that I or one of your fellow students will help you out.
Alternatively if you're completely at a loss and you can't figure out what's going wrong then you can
check out my solution to the project and get help.
Which is also attached to the next lecture.
You can then cross-reference between different files.
Check out what could be going wrong.
Good luck on your first project.
It's a huge step to finally be making your first real visualization for the course.
We really start to add a lot of power into what we can already do with the three.