In this section you learn how to work with scales axes and margins to transform some basic shapes on
the screen into a fully fledged bartk.
This visualization was pretty basic but it should have helped you to learn some of the key concepts
in D-3 which will keep coming up throughout the course.
The bar chart that we made the pool isn't actually much of an improvement on just the roll figures in
terms of explaining what's going on in section 5.
We'll take this bartk to the next level by making it flick between different data sources.
In the next section you'll be learning about data visualization design which will be critical for more
complex projects.
You'll learn how to tell what kind of visualization you should use for a particular set of data and
you'll be learning how to constructively critique existing visualizations to make them better.