In this section I'll be giving you a broad overview of how we can draw maps in D-3 maybe sharing everything
that you'll need to take into consideration.
You learn about the different projection algorithms that we can use and will be introducing you to the
D-3 Jiyu path generator.
You'll also be learning how to work with MAT files in D-3 also be showing you how to use D-3.
Q module to load multiple datasets at once which will be really important going forward whenever you
want to switch sources of data together.
Finally I'll be teaching you the ins and outs of the D-3 force that will be using it to create one of
the coolest visualizations that you can make with D-3.
When I have a node linked diagrams at the end of the section again the focus of this section is all
about running through community code and building up understanding of how the D-3 files fit together.
I'll be moving through the examples pretty quickly.
Just aiming to give you a breadth of knowledge that you'll need to quickly pick up any visualisation
that you can find online.