In this lecture I'll be giving you an introduction to drawing maps but D-3 code which we can then use
to visualize data or be running through the two different types of map files that were once used with
D-3 and they'll be showing you how to use D-3 G.O. path generator for visualizing geographical paths
such as sharing different countries borders.
The first step towards creating a visualization of the world involves finding a map file to use which
contains information about the borders of country states or regions.
There are a few places online that we can create our own files for this purpose although I'll be using
the map that Mike Buster is using blocks simplicity map files tend to come in geo.
Jason.
This is a special type of Jason File which D-3 knows how to convert into a set of patternist Fiji's
using its gybe path generator.
A lot of times you'll see people using Toppo adjacent files instead of just adjacent files a chopper
adjacent file includes information about topology of a map as well as things like Borders amazingly
Chapa adjacent files tend to be way smaller than just adjacent files even though they encode more data
because of this.
I'd always recommend you to use top or adjacent files where possible and it also means that we need
to convert into Gier Jason format to be used with the three.
We can do this easily by including Toppo Jason jast library which gives us a couple of functions to
make this easier.
Chopper Jason does feature and top OJs and mash.
Have you ever seen this visualization before they show the real size of Africa.
It turns out that all of these countries which appear huge on our maps could actually fit inside of
Africa in terms of area.
This isn't something that looks obvious from the standard map that you'll see in school classrooms.
The reason why this happens is that when you once visualize a 3-D sphere a 2-D plane we need to apply
some kind of projection to it.
The result is that we essentially need to stretch the world out one way or another so that it fits properly
onto the screen.
So for instance here we have the Murcutt to a projection on the right which is by far the most common
type of projection that exists to make everything fit into the surface areas near each of the poles
looked larger than they actually are.
And areas close to the equator will appear smaller.
This is extremely obvious whenever you look at Antarctica on a globe which is hugely blown up by the
Meckstroth projection Indie's 3.
We have the flexibility to choose which ever projection we want to use without Max.
This can come in handy if we want to make a more advanced visualization where it's really important
to keep a fair perspective between different country sizes.
Here's an image on Bloch's where we have every projection that's available in D3 for some of these if
we need to include an add on library.
But it's really easy to switch up our projection to any of these different options.
I found this carried on blogs from Mike Bostock's for a few years ago.
It was written in D-3 version 3 but I was able to update it to version four really easily.
The main change is here with the D-3 module has been lumped in the main D-3 library.
So we have D-3 Geographic and version 3 which is now 83 reticule 3-G path is now the 3-G path and D-3
that you plus a projection is now just the 3-G projection to output a map onto the screen.
We first need to define the projection that we can use.
I'm using a classic schoolroom Murcutt or projection to start off with.
To demonstrate how it works in our projection function I'm setting how far zoomed in we want to map
to be using this scale method and I'm setting the center of our map with this translate method.
Next we define the path generator that we want to use which just takes our projection as its arguments.
Then we load in the data and the path to our SPG canvas with the datum attribute coming from a path
generator.
We want to open paths for the land lines country borders and Gretsch cool lines of map.
We need to provide a Jew Jason object to up your path generator.
So we using chords to our top or adjacent library to make these conversions for us.
Let's take a look at what's going on here inside the console.
The first load here is showing a map file looks like when it first gets loaded into a file.
The second log is showing the value that we're passing into our data and method.
When we want to append our land borders this top log here is in a top or adjacent format as we can see
because the type of an object is a topology because a geo path generator expects to be handed something
in a geo Jason format we're calling the top Jason doc Feagin method on this before passing it to our
data join the object that get Spatz out is now in angio Jason format.
We can see from this geometry field that we have a large array of coordinates that you can generate
will be using each of these items here represents a different path that our generator will need to drop
in order to mark out the land borders for a map.
In this block of code here we're going through the same thing again but this time we're using the top
adjacent mesh function which is taking in a list of different countries and spitting out a path of all
the borders between them.
We're passing an apology this time giving a list of countries.
And finally this filter function is making sure that we only add one border between each country.
Finally this chromatic secure variable here comes from calling D-3 geographic cure which we can pass
straight to your path generator which will add engrafted fuel lines for Matt.
Now if we change the type projection that we using an up projection variable we'll see a completely
different map gets outputted to the screen.
So here let's say that we want to use an equal area map in the shape of the curve.
D-3 gives us this projection called D-3 Geo conic equal area.
We can see the difference that this has.
And you can play around with any kind of different projection that you want to show by changing this
one line here after this lecture you should understand the challenges that go along with trying to visualize
a 3-D sphere onto a 2D plane you now know how to create paths of countries from Geo.
Jason ON-TOPIC Jason files and add them onto the screen using D-3 is Jiyu path generators.
Now do we know how to render these shapes on the screen.
It's not a huge step to associate these shapes with data as we usually want to do in 83.
However this will involve the need for us to load in a separate set of data from a different file in
the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to the syntax that we need you to do this in the most efficient way possible.