So far the data from visualisations has always been coming from one unified file.
However a lot of the time your interfaces will need to display data from multiple different sources.
For example in the next lecture we'll be combining a metafile like we store in our last lecture with
some information about unemployment rates in the US.
In this lecture I'll be introducing you to Kyus in D-3 which Let's do this before version 5 and then
I'll be showing you how we can load more than one data set using premises that latest version of the
three before D-3 version 5.
If you need it to load into different data sets you might have thought that we could use one of these
two snippets of code.
But neither of these work well in the example on the left we're setting two global variables.
Map data and example data and then we're setting them to the value of two different ways.
The problem here is that any code that we cite below these two functions will execute immediately because
it's likely going to take at least a few hundred milliseconds for both files to be loaded in and it's
pretty likely that we won't be able to access or arrays by the time our code tries to use these variables
on the right.
This code actually would work.
We can access a map file using the map variable and the example data using the example variable we can
be sure that inside our D-3 CSP function all the data will have been loaded in properly.
However the downside of this is that it will take longer for the data to load in because the page can't
start loading the second file before the first file has been completely loaded.
If we have a massive file that took 10 seconds to load in and then we would much rather start the process
of loading as soon as possible.
No need to wait until all the files before have been loaded in before version 5.
We used to get around this with the 3Q module we had access to the data that D-3 loaded down with the
map and example arguments to the callback our program would then start making these file requests as
soon as it saw them.
But it wouldn't start executing any code before.
All the files had been loaded in.
You can see the effect that this had from the output of the chrome dev tools here the data files here
are the map TS for the file in the US ten file at the bottom of these images.
In both cases the map tears the files taking about 1 seconds to load in the US 10 files taking about
1.5 seconds.
However because we are using a Q in the Boston example these files are requested at the same time so
we don't need to wait until map Chia's fee was completely loaded before we started loading the US 10
file.
This means that we essentially saved ourselves from waiting a whole second when our visualization loaded
for the first time which is a pretty significant improvement for our users.
Indy 3 version 5 cents of data loading functions are structured as premises.
We no longer need to write queues when we want to load in multiple data sets.
Instead we write code like this where we're setting up an array with each of the promises that we want
to use and then we can use the Ben method on the result of passing this array into Promises dogs all
this gives us access to a new array with each item.
Now holding the data from the file could be one to look at.
So here we're accessing on that data.
The first item of the output array and we're grabbing our example data.
The second item of that array.
The great thing about this syntax with promises is that any code that we write beyond this won't have
to wait for both of these files to get loaded in before our code starts to execute as soon as our browser
sees this code.
It can just talk about these promises as if the actual values before they have the data loaded in we
get the same kind of effect by using promises as we had with the D-3.
Q We don't need to wait for a premise to evaluate before we can start throwing it around in our code.
Both of these files will start loading at the same time which will cause our page to render and much
faster
after this lecture.
You have a good idea of why we need to be careful when loading in more than one data set into a file.
And you know had to do this properly using promise to all.
I've also introduced you of the legacy syntax of using the D-3 Q module to do the same thing which will
probably come across in examples on line in the next lecture.
I'll be walking me through chloroplast map which involves color coding.
One of the map projections I covered in the last lecture to show something about some geographical data.