In this lecture I'll be introducing you to chloroplast maps which are helpful to show how different
data differs across geographic regions.
Abusing the D-3 Geo path generator again together with D-3 3Q to stitch together two different sources
of data and I'll be using a color scale to display data in a visual format
a color Plath is a fancy name for a map that shows how a variable differs across geographical regions
by showing different color coatings.
The most obvious case that you'll tend to see with these maps they use heavily in elections they often
aren't particularly helpful in explaining underlying data but they do give a good overview of how a
situation looks.
So here on the left we have a visualization from 5:38 during the 2016 election which is showing some
predictions across different states that which party is likely to win the election.
States are colored either red or blue with darker colors representing a higher chance of that candidate
winning on the right we have a different map which is color coded according to population density across
different areas.
Chloroplasts one of those awesome tools to have in your toolbox because they really present a dazzling
showcase of what you can do with these three.
Here's an example.
I'll be walking three blocks.
This is another great example from Mike Bostock which is showing the unemployment rate for every U.S.
county.
We have a legend up here that lets us see what each of these colors represent and we can use that legend
to see the parts of the US that have the highest rates of unemployment.
I'll copy this code into my workplace and I'll take you through everything that you want seen already.
Starting from the top we can say the usual D-3 set up in this example we're not worrying about margins
for that this line here could be quite confusing especially since we're writing code for a map.
In this example did the map is just creating a data structure called Map which is pretty similar to
an object job script.
This lets us set and find items by that key using the maps set and get methods we are using this linear
scale to create a legend a little further down the file which will work together with these colors.
This time we're using a threshold scale which means that any value that goes into it will be rounded
to a specific color.
This means that we're able to have one color between one and two percent unemployment then another color
from 2 to 3 percent.
And so we're using D-3 range here to create an array of numbers from two to 10 which will give us the
different values that our scale will run between.
If you're wondering where this scheme Bleus variable is coming from it's been included with this D-3
scale kinetic library which gives us a few more standard options for setting color scales.
This will basically just spits out an array of color hexes for us scale to use this code here is performing
a data join on each of the colors that we want to show on legit with setting D values to be an array
of two numbers representing the minimum and maximum values that this color should apply for.
For each of these values we're appending a rectangle with the fill of the color that we're associating
it with.
Using our scale to position and equally in the top right hand corner of Kandace then we're calling an
axis generator to add the ticks beneath the weight getting the percentage values that we want to show
using the tick values on a color scale.
Their main and with formatting each of our take labels with a percentage sign using a stick format.
Noticed that all of this character has been working on this variable called G which is just the legend
when we want to add our paths and later we'll be appended them directly to the SVGA.
Candace next we're using a queue to load in both of our different datasets.
We getting a map file from the D-3 website.
This one is just a map of the US and we're getting some data about unemployment figures from this TSB
file inside our data folder.
As you'll recall this q is going to wait until 3 three Jason and D-3 ts the functions are what their
magic before executing this ready function the low you might notice here that were an argument short
in this ready function when not passing in unemployment figures here but instead we're just saying each
of our pieces of data into the maps that we defined earlier we can do this with a set method of a map
which is running inside optional initialize method.
Let's take a look at the data that we have to work with this first log here sharing the data that we
loaded for my Toppo Jason mat file in this object field.
We can see that we have geometries for counties and states and in this nation field we have everything
that we need to draw the U.S. as a whole this second log here shows the map that we made for unemployment
data each of these keys represents a different country which is set in using an ID that matches up with
an ID from our map file this call to Toppo Jason doc feature gives Jason a collection of counties and
then accessing this feature.
I feel that this collection gives an array with every county in the U.S. we're using append and ends
as a separate path for each county we using our color scale to set the field for each county depending
on its unemployment rate in the same anonymous function here.
We're also giving each item a field called rate which we're setting to this unemployment rate value
then for each country.
Our path generator will be fed the item in the array that we're looking at which will add the shape
of that county to screen.
You might notice that we didn't set the projection that we wanted to use for you that generated this
time.
This is because this time our map has already had a projection applied to it.
You'll often find that this happens from map files that you'll find on line if you want to use a custom
projection in your code then you'll need to make sure that you're using a roll top or adjacent file
that hasn't had a projection applied to it already.
Finally we're adding a title element here which will display the rate value that we just set.
This is a really easy way to add two steps to your visualization as this figure will just pop up whenever
you hover over this particular county.
Then underneath all that we're adding in a path that the state borders in the US we're using the same
Toppo Jason Dharmesh function at less time to get borders.
But this time we're passing in our state field instead of our counties field.
We've set some simple styles for us state borders and our counties which give us thick lines for separating
States then the lines for separating counties.
Here's how you'd want to write this code in version 5.
Since we can't use the D-3 Q module anymore we're setting out to data loading functions as usual.
Then again we're only making use of our map data inside out ready function since we're setting our unemployment
data using methadose set.
We're calling our ready function within the then module and we're passing the first item the array of
data sets that we get back as it's arguments.
We can then catch any errors using the catch module as usual and this gives us back the same graph for
after this lecture.
You should know how to stitch together a metafile using D-3 top O.J.'s library with some kind of external
dataset.
This will be crucial if you ever want to make one of these particular visualisations yourself.
But it should also have given you some practice at working with multiple files which you'll be doing
a lot more going forward.
In the next lecture I'll be introducing the D-3 force layer which can be used to create all kinds of
interesting visualizations.
What elements are moving around on the page.