In this lecture I'll be introducing you to the D-3 for slabs which allows us to make visualizations
with shapes that move around the screen in a way that represents something about data.
This is a really good way to create custom interactive visualizations because it can add an element
of playfulness that helps to engage the user.
I'll be showing you the basic syntax for adding these forces to your ass.
Veejays and I'll show you a few examples which use of force lay out particularly well
the first layout allows us to create a physics simulator which we can use to visualize what it would
look like to assign the SPG some forces depending on the data that they represent.
Some examples of implantations could be to make elements or tracks or repel each other by a particular
strength to show that some elements are in some way connected by adding links between them containing
elements into a particular area of the screen or giving element some sense for positions that they're
spaced out to medically or show you a few examples that show us the kind of stuff that you can do with
a forced laugh.
Here's a map showing all of the different flight paths between different U.S. airports.
The map is updating to show how different flights have wiggled around these pets over time.
We're using links to illustrate these flight paths and updating them as our data changes.
Here's a different example where we're using forces to space out our data points into separate categories.
In this case we're visualizing MLS teams performances in different years and we're also using D-3 forces
to space them out to the right year.
This is important because if we did this as a normal scatterplot then we'd have overlapping circles
where teams scored the same number of points.
As one more example here's a version of a word cloud which is made with forces rather than the cloud
layer.
All of these words are flying in from the size of the canvas and eventually settled down in the middle
as a basic three step process that we need to follow whenever we want to add forces onto our visualization.
Firstly we need to make a call to D-3 for simulation to start running of physics simulator.
Next we need to add some forces that we want to visualize using some force function that D-3 gives us.
And finally we need to create an event handler which will run some carrots updates as Ficci positions.
Every time the simulation has a take
Here's a simple example of some D-3 forces action.
You'll often see the terms nodes and links used in this setting.
In this context a node is a piece of data within the system and the link represents a relationship between
two of these different nodes with defining and lists of nodes is an array of empty objects here which
we're passing into us simulation.
We're adding two forces setting the charge in the center point and then we're firing this take function
whenever the simulation updates inside the tick function.
We're appending our circles that relate to the same array of data that we're using with simulation.
What's happening here is that a simulation is attaching x and y fields to data objects which will update
on every tick of a clock within a dating circle positions appropriately whenever the tick function runs
once everything settles down.
The image on the right is what we're left with setting the charge force means that our circles repel
each other little and setting the sends a force means that they gravitate towards the middle of canvas
has a list of the different forces that T3 is forced lay out kids to play around with for center to
find the center point of gravity force many body defines the charge of each of these feet.
GS force Kalighat gives is a way to stop the elements from overlapping force x and y make elements point
towards a certain coordinate and force link causes linked SVGA to stay a fixed distance from one another.
We add in forces using the force method as shown here below.
The first arguments this method is a type of force that we're adding.
And the second argument is the force function that we want to use or go through each of these forces
one by one to show you how they work.
Full force sensor.
We just need to provide x and y coordinates to the function which will define the point that our nodes
will revolve around.
So here after using this all of us locals will be sucked into the points in the graph has an x value
of 100 and a Y value of 100.
Next we can set up elements have certain charges to attract or repel each other by using the force many
body functions.
We can pass in a strength value to set how this chart should look if we pass in a negative value here.
Our SVGA age will repel each other and if we pass in a positive value then will attract each other.
If we use a larger number then if change will pull each other with more strength if we don't specify
its strength value.
And D-3 will default to a value of minus 30 which should keep everything spread out neatly on the page.
Next we can set the collision force using the D-3 collide function.
The idea here is that we'll pass in a radius value which should match the radius of each circle and
circle won't be able to encroach on other circles past this invisible buffer.
In this example here we're setting some random radius values for each item in our array and we're giving
a fourth collide function access to this value when we're setting a collision radius on the right.
We can see how this might look if we didn't include a collision force and this would look a lot messier
as all of these circles would lap
the force acts and force wife functions can be really useful to grouping together different categories
on the page.
For example we're setting an X force here which we're setting based on the category of each of the circles
belong to.
This means that each circle will gravitate to an exposition that matches its category.
Again we can set the strength of this force using the strength method with a larger positive value meaning
the SVGA will be more firmly attached to the point that we pick.
Finally we can force certain nodes in our graph to be a certain distance apart by using the link for
us to do this we need to provide an array of objects that looks like this in the top left.
Each object should have a source and the target value which should match the idea that the two different
nodes in the system we can also set the distance these node should be separated by using the distance
method to this function and we can define the strength of this force using the strength method.
After this lecture you should have a good idea about how we can use forces and D-3 to make a host of
really cool effects and I've shown you some examples of how we can use this.
Lay out the data visualization in the next lecture.
We'll be exploring one of the most common uses of the force that I'll be introducing you to node link
diagrams.