In this lecture I'll be walking you through an implementation of a node link diagram which uses the
forced laugh that you learned the back.
The last lecture to show connections between different nodes in a network.
This type of visualization is a common use case with the D-3 forced out you just learned about in The
Last Lecture.
It's also one of those visualizations that will really impress people if you know how to make it properly
known link diagrams present a completely different format.
All of the visualizations that we've seen so far.
They're really useful to share the interaction of different parts of the network.
We can show connections of different strengths by linking notes like this together and we can encode
information about every node and circle size and we can add in some cool features by making use of different
forces on the left.
We have an example where this diagram is showing the sales performance of different members of the team
a link here shows the team member that recruited a given employee the size of the circle represents
the sales volume that the rep is dealing with and the color of a circle represents the rep's job title
on the right.
This labeling diagram is displaying all of somebodies friends on Facebook.
The graph is separated into distinct community groups which tend to know each other and everything feeds
back to the node at the center which spawned the whole Grath.
This is a classic example of the type of visualisation that we want to use and link diagrams for because
it highlights the relationships that exist within a complex and connected system.
This is the example they'll be walking through over the course of this section which I found that blocks
each node in this graph is a character in Les Miserables with thicker lines meaning the characters appeared
together more often these nodes are spaced out so that unrelated characters are further apart and the
color of the circles were laid to the group that each character belongs to.
Let's take a look at this code nab it's been copied into my working directory.
After setting up our canvas making our color scale here we're initializing the forces that we'll be
using for our graphic.
Firstly we're using the sense of force to make sure that all on there it's a balanced random middle
of our canvas.
Next we're applying a negative charge between our notes nicely spread out from each other.
Then we're applying the force collide to keep us from overlapping.
We can just passing the radius of our circles as an argument here rather than explicitly setting it
with a radius method.
So here we're setting up both 10 pixels.
Finally we're setting some length forces within our visualization.
We're using this optional ID method here which lets us simulation know that it should look at the ID
field at the node object to find the element that it should connect to.
We still need to define our array of different lengths with the length method which will do once we
have access to data.
Once we have this initialized appending our links and notes within our data loading function.
Let's take a look at the data that we're working with here.
We can see that our data is conveniently split up into two different parts in the node part.
We have an array of objects with each item representing a different character.
Then in the links part we have an array of all of the different connections that exist between characters.
So here we have the format that links method is expecting.
Looking back it carried the next step is to add a line for every link that we want our graphs to show
and a node for every character in our data we're passing in our array of links into our data join appending
one line for every connection in our dataset within setting the stroke with these lines according to
the value of each connection.
So this means that characters occur together in more scenes will have thicker line than others.
We're taking the square root of this world value so that none of these lines are massively thicker than
others.
Once we have the links appended for the first time the next step is to add a circle of every node in
our diagram.
This time we're using nodes that right in our data for our data join appending a circle for each we're
giving each of them a radius of five and we're setting fill based in the group that they belong to.
This quarter D-3 drag here allows us to drag these elements around with a Fiji canvas.
We can use this call any D-3 selection that we want in any of our visualisations.
We're also setting three event listeners which will fire at different stage of the node being dragged
this line here is just adding in some simple tool tips again which will show the name of the character
that we're looking at when we hover over one of these nodes then we're telling us simulation to run
on the same array of objects that we use to draw circles.
We're also adding an event listener so we can run a function that will update our visualization on every
tick of our force simulation.
Then here we're finishing off our links forced by feeding in our array of associations between our different
nodes.
Here's our take function which is going to execute repeatedly on every tick of us simulation.
All that we're doing here is to update the position of our circles and lines in our chart.
Remember they're on every tick of our simulation our force layer is adding different positional attributes
to both links and race for our lines.
This means that we can have access to the two points of our line using the source and target field which
are populated with x and y values.
Then for us circle's we can update the x and y position by using x and y values.
The simulation adds on for us when we put all of this together.
This visualization unfolds itself properly.
The last thing to talk about is how our drag functions are working calling this restart method together
with the alpha target call here reheats the simulation whenever a node gets dragged.
So all of the notes will keep changing position to react with the position of the mouse the alpha.
The simulation represents have tempered all of the forces should be initially our Grath starts off with
an alpha one.
And as time goes on the value decreases to zero.
Setting our alpha target to 0.7 here means that once we restart the simulation causing everything to
move around again the simulation will only decay to have an alpha value of nought point seven as a minimum
meaning of the know which will continue to be repositioned automatically as we move them around.
After doing that with setting the force x force y value of the note that we're looking at to its current
position so that it doesn't immediately fly that way.
Next every time we moved the node to a different position the nerd gets pulled up to match the position
of the cursor again by setting its f x and x y values.
Finally when we let go of the circle that we're driving we're setting out the target back to zero.
So eventually the graph will come down again and we're clearing the force x and force y values that
we set so that the note doesn't stay pegged to the position of the cursor.
After this lecture you should understand how a node linked diagram fits together in D-3.
Hopefully this lecture has also solidified your understanding of the D-3 lamp function meaning you can
use it to create interesting visualizations on your again I'll be capping off this section with a quick
quiz just to make sure that you have a good understanding of the new topics that we've covered.