At the end of this section you now know how to build two of the most impressive visualizations that
D-3 lets us create these visualizations for showing maps and networks.
A pretty tough to create in most other systems but they're actually fairly easy to build with D-3.
You've also had more experience interpretating some boilerplate code from the community as I've been
going through our examples line by line again to understand how everything is working.
You will find yourself using the D-3 Q module a lot if you keep doing D-3 development because you always
want to use it when you want to work with data which is spread across multiple different files.
The next section will be the final crash course section that I'll be taking you through.
I'll be covering everything to do with hierarchical data and I'll be showing you how to build for new
visualizations which will express something about hierarchical systems.
I'll be helping you to format your data so that it will work with these layouts that will use.