In this section I'll be rambling off the second part of the course which involves plowing through a
whole range of different visualizations each of the visualizations and this section involves hierarchical
data.
What this means is that we'll be communicating something about a system where different elements in
our data that can be thought of as belonging to others.
So for instance we might want to communicate the structure of the business.
There's a chain of command stretching from every lowly employee way up to the company's CEO using the
visualizations in this section we could compare how individual employees are adding to the overall performance
of that teams as well as to the civilians of the company as a whole.
Another good example of hierarchical data could be geographical entities such as continents nation states
and districts.
Every district belongs to a state.
Every state belongs to a nation and every nation belongs to a constant.
We can make some interesting visualizations that play on this hierarchical structure compared between
these separate entities.
By the end of this section you'll be able to format your data properly to work with these lay outs and
you'll also be able to add tree diagrams treatment circle packs and sunburst plots of growing visualization
toolbox.