In this lecture I'll be talking about deathrays hierarchy stratified lamp's which we can use to structure
our data as a hierarchy.
We'll be using these labs throughout this section to build visualizations that reflect hierarchical
system.
Before I dive in with the description of these two lads I want to clear up some of the terminology that
will be coming out over the next section.
All of these terms on the left come up repeatedly whenever we talk about data structures.
We always want to talk about different pieces of data nodes being connected with one another in a chart
like this.
Nodes are connected and network like this by links and you can have a number of notes that they connect
to.
Beneath them called child nodes or nodes are they linked to above them called parent knows the root
node represents the first node in data which all of them would spawn from the root node is the only
note that has no parent nodes.
Think of it like a tree where the root starts everything up.
There's also the term leafnode which represents any node that doesn't have a child node of its own.
Again the tree analogy works well-head because a leaf hangs off at the end of a fully grown tree.
With nothing else attached to it.
Whenever we want to visualize some kind of hierarchy D-3 we need to provide our data in the right format.
Specifically we need to pass in root element which is connected to a number of children which are in
turn connected to more children up until the point where we have expressed every single node in the
hierarchy.
Whenever we're working with data that doesn't quite express all of this already we'll need to use the
D-3 hierarchy or T-3 stratify layouts to make this conversion for us for D-3 is hierarchy lay out our
data should already look like this image on the left before we pass it into this function.
We have a javascript object here which is an object that contains an array of children who live at a
level below it in the hierarchy.
We just need to pass in an array of data like this to D-3 hierarchy.
And we can also provide an optional access function which will tell a function where to find the array
of children for every node in our network.
You can see here all the fields of hierarchy that will add to our data depth represents how far down
from the root node is nowadays whereas PI communicates the further distance and node is above the leaf
for every node the hierarchy level also attaches a field that shows the parent knows that it belongs
to as well as a field containing an array of every child that the node is connected to.
We can also feed in an optional method to find some of the values of all than those descendants or we
can count how many descendants each node has saurians in the value field we want to use to stratify
layouts when our data isn't already structured neatly into a tree format.
For instance we have the same data that we were communicating in the last example here except this time
we just have every name in our dataset showing which parent that person belongs to.
We can turn this into a hierarchy by using the stratified function.
We need to pass in an access function to show an unique ID to each element in the array holds.
In this case the name field and another access a function to show the item is parent.
In this case the parent field in this scenario we store this data in a variable called table and we
can pass that in as an argument to this root function here.
The result is the same data that is returned by the hierarchy lay out in the last example so we can
see here from this console log that this will return the root node which connects to each of its children
with the children.
Right.
And again we have the data depth ID and parent fields attached for use with a hierarchy.
At the end of this lecture you know how to use the three hierarchy D-3 stratify layouts to format your
data to be used with the layers in this section.
In the next lecture we'll be putting this knowledge into practice as I'll be walking you through the
code to create the tree diagram which offers a nice high level perspective on the structure of a hierarchy.