In this lecture I'll be introducing you to tree diagrams which we can use to illustrate the structure
of a hierarchical system.
I'll be walking through a simple implementation using the T-3 tree layout.
And we'll also be using the D-3 stratify lab for the first time
tree diagrams are most often used to give a broad overview of the complex system showing how everything
fits together.
Here we have a couple of different examples on the left.
This visualization is illustrating the chain of command in a company the root node here at the top of
the diagram shows the person in charge of the whole company and then we can see the company structure
based on which members of staff are managed by which executive on the right.
We have a famous visualization from the New York Times which shows the number of paths to victory for
presidential candidates depending on who wins each swing state.
This visualization is actually interactive so you can play through different scenarios and the graph
will update the root node to show how this changes the shape of the tree.
Here's the example that will be taking you through for this lecture.
This is just a really simple implementation of a static tree diagram which you might use just provide
some simple information about hierarchy the data that we're looking at here is showing the structure.
Another visualization library called flare just like the three flares split up into different modules
which each have different packages that you can call inside of them.
So here's the code that I copied into my workspace and some basic setup we're creating a tree out by
passing in the size that we wanted to take up this size method just takes two arguments to wait from
the height that we want our tree to be spread across then we're setting up the D-3 stratified function
which were used data in the right format for a hierarchy layout this parent IDM method here is just
retaining the name of each item the parent node.
Since we're displaying methods which are nicely stored into different modules we're reading the data
in as usual and we're setting up our root node by passing in our data to a stratified function.
We're also providing a sort according to the depth of each node in the tree.
Within passing this value onto what tree layout function which gives a few different fields that we
can use.
Let's take a look at this data in the console to see how everything is working.
First we have the data as it looks when we first load it into what PSP file as you can see.
This just gives each Aitken's ID and its value.
This data isn't yet in the right format to display as a hierarchy which is why we're passing it on to
our stratified function.
Next time logging the contents of this root variable which is the stratified version of this array.
Now we can see that our data is neatly formatted so that we can display as a hierarchy.
Each node is flittered where it belongs into this object.
And for every node we can see its height depth ID children and parent.
Then we have the result of passing the stratified data into a tree layer.
This gives us from the same hierarchy that we just defined except this time each node has an x and y
value that represents where it should be placed on the screen.
Finally I'm showing you what gets returned after we called the links method on this object.
We now have an array of 251 items with each item corresponding to a link that we need to draw between
two nodes in a network flicking back to our code.
Now let's see how we're setting up tree.
Firstly we're performing a data join on this array of links that we got from our tree labs.
We're passing in this D-3 link horizontal function here for id attribute so that we can attach a custom
path for each link that we need to draw for every item in our array.
This will draw a line between the coordinates of the source node and the target node.
Next we're using descendants method on a tree layout to return every node that we need to enter into
our tree lay out and we're attaching a group to each of them and giving them a translation depending
on the x and y coordinates.
Finally for each of these groups we're attaching a circle and the text label to them to finish off the
tree diagram at the end of this lecture.
You should feel comfortable with working with tree layouts to visualize the structure of hierarchical
system.
You also had your first look at how D-3 stratify works in a really simple example.
In the next lecture I'll be showing you how to use tree maps which also allow us to convey hierarchy's.
But this time they allow us to show something about the size of each component.