In this lecture I'll be walking through an example of a treatment which is a really useful visualization
to know to compare data across different categories that fit into a hierarchy.
We'll be using the D-3 hierarchy lab for the first time together with D-3 is treatment plan to create
this specialization.
Tree maps are a really powerful tool for visualizing data.
Essentially they consist of nested squares with disgrace.
Essentially they consist of nested rectangles which display some kind of information based on the node
in the hierarchy that they represent.
This allows us to show how some different components of a hierarchy hold a different weight and the
contribution to some kind of metric that we care about.
For example on the left here we have a tree map that shows how each county in Florida voted in the 2016
election.
We're encoding counties that voted for Trump in red and counties that voted for Clinton blue a deep
shade of his color again represents a larger margin of victory.
The size of each of these rectangles represents the voting weights that each of these counties have
on the result of the race.
We can then tell a story for example of how only a couple of these large swing counties would need to
change their allegiance to completely change the result of the national election.
In the example on the right we have different countries splits according to their population these have
all been nicely separated into different continents by that position and that color.
The great thing about a tree map is that we can make some really quick and easy size comparisons based
on whatever metric that we're looking at in this example this team is talking about population but it
could just as easily have been talking about pollution or world GDP which would have given us a different
message.
Here's an example of me taking you through for this lecture.
It's yet another beautiful Mike Bostock example from Bloch's again.
This one is a nice example to use because it comes with an update function built into it already which
we can use to flick between seeing different metrics.
We're actually using the same data set that we had last time.
Except that this data comes in a format that we can using the D-3 hierarchy Latt rather than with the
D-3 stratify.
So each one of these rectangles represents a package of the flayer library and we're encoding the area
of these rectangles according to either the size of that package or the number of packages contained
within it.
Let's run through this code to see how everything is working in our team.
We're starting off with two radio buttons which let us choose which type of data we want to show for
a color scheme where we're using a map function together with this fade function to set the value of
each of our colors to 20 percent of the way between that color and white.
This just means that each of our colors appear a little bit lighter when we use them to fill in rectangles
where we're setting up our treatment plant passing in these four different fields.
The tile method sets the algorithm that D-3 were used to space out these tiles which D-3 gives us some
options for the size method is again dictating the height and width of the tree map which we're just
saying is the size of our canvas round is saying that all values should be worked with integers and
this padding in a value gives us a little bit of space between each of our different rectangles.
Next we have our data loading function.
I'm going to make some Konsole logs in here to show you what our lab is doing.
We can see here from our first log how our data looks when it's first loaded into our code.
It matches the format that we're looking for.
Since this is representing a root node with a set of children attached as an array since the data is
in a format like this we can pass this value onto a hierarchy layer so we can use it without treatment.
We're using each before to set custom ID on every element in our array which will make it easier for
us to work with them later.
For some method we're passing in these variables some by size which comes from a function that we define
at the bottom of a file.
This means our treatment will attach a value to each node in our hierarchy with each number coming from
adding up the size values each of that nodes to send its finally after this we're transforming the States
again by calling our tree map lay out on it and we using the leaves method again to perform a data joint.
So this is the array of data that we're using for a data join.
We can see that our treatment as attached as 0 x 1 Why is there and why one values which represent the
four corners of our rectangle where each of these nodes should be placed from this point on.
It's really simple for us to build up this treatment.
We're appending a group for each node in the network and shifting it to the top left position of where
each rectangle should be.
Next we're adding a rectangle for each of these groups setting the width.
There's a difference between the two x values and the height is a difference between the two y values.
We're also recursively setting the color of each of these circles depending on whatever color its parent
takes.
All of this code is doing is making sure that the labels for each of our rectangles opposition sensibly
and if they stretch over into the neighboring rectangle and we apply this clip path so that the label
only shows on the rectangle that it belongs to.
Again we're appending some simple tool tips by appending a title to each of them and we get to show
the name of the package plus its value on that line.
But let hey we're attaching an event list and then onto our radio buttons and we're triggering this
change function whenever it gets pressed.
With this data method we're passing in the name of one of these functions at the bottom here which will
appear as some argument and changed within remaking our team at play here using a different some function
depending on which radio button was pressed.
If we pressed the size button then we'll use the some by size function which adds up all the size values
at the roots those descendants.
However if we press the command button then we'll use the number of children a package has size it within
updating the size of each rectangle based on these new values using the transform attributes on that
group and by changing the width and height to rectangles after this lecture you can now add tree map
to your increasingly impressive arsenal of visualizations that you know have built.
This should hopefully have cemented your understanding of hierarchies as well as giving you more experience
dealing with a range of layouts in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to a pretty similar visualization to this except that we'll be encoding this
data with a set of nested circles rather than nested rectangles.