In this lecture I'll be introducing you to the circle packing lab that comes with three this type of
visualization is really similar to a treatment and you'll see parallels in our code and you'll see parallels
in how our code is written between this lecture and the previous lecture.
We're once again using the D-3 stratify lay out to set up data.
And this time I'll be introducing you to the D-3 packed Ladd's
circle packing can be used in any situation where you might think about using a tree map instead.
You could argue that the circle packing offers a more unique and interesting design than a regular treatment.
It all three groups is categories more explicitly than just by using a single color scheme.
However to play devil's advocate here you could also argue that it's more difficult for our brains to
text areas between different circles than it is for us to pick apart the areas of rectangles.
It's really just a personal design decision that you'll have to make by yourself as to which visualization
you want to use.
On the left you can see the same data that we saw in The Last Lecture visualize with circle packing
instead of the treatment.
Again the areas of each of these shapes represent the population of different countries which are split
up into regions the example on the right.
Here is a visualization.
I'll be walking through in this lecture to keep things simple.
Here we have another visualization that I found blocks using the exact same dataset that we've seen
in the last two lectures.
This time data is in the format of a table again.
So we'll be using D-3 stratified Wrotham deep hierarchy.
We have a nice effect here where we can hover over each of these circles and the stroke gets changed
so we can clearly see which packages inherits from.
We're also using a nice color scheme where the darkness of each of these circles represents the height
of each node.
So our root node on the outside representing the entire floor library has the darkest color.
And these leaf nodes over here with the most ancestors have the lightest color.
So let's start looking through this code to see how everything is working.
The way that we're getting our color scale to work for this visualization is by using a sequential scale
together with this interpolator for colors that D-3 gives us basically the zero value for this interpreter
is in the middle of this set of colors.
And since we're saying the domain between minus four plus four we'll be using some of these colors in
the middle of the chart.
So next we're using the stratify layout suggest hierarchical order.
Each of the rows in our dataset all this line is doing is providing the access a function to each node
in a network to connect with its parent here we're setting up a pact that we're just passing in the
size that we wanted to take up and the padding value which represents a bit of padding that we want
to surround inside and the outside of every circle.
Again I'll make some console logs here to show you what layouts are doing.
First of all we have the raw data that we're loading it all the way we have to start with an ID for
each package which we're used in first position in the hierarchy and the value sharing the sides of
each package.
Next we're setting up our written word here by passing in our data to a stratified function.
We're summing up our values based on each element value field and we're sorting out elements by this
size to.
So this spits out hierarchy format that we now know and love which we'll be able to pass on to any of
our layout functions.
Once we call our pack layer on this Ruge object data we add in x y and our attributes which we use to
position our circles.
We're performing our data join here on the descendants of our root node which gives us this array here.
For every descendant we're adding in a group which we're translating according to that it's X and Y
about these lines.
Setting up a nice hover effect where we get to see all of the nodes ancestors whenever we mouse over
it then we're adding a circle to each of these groups setting the radius with the value the layout function
provided us with.
And we're saying Phil accordant the depth in the hierarchy again this code here is just making sure
that we have some tidy labels that we can use for each of our nodes and we're leaving at the leaf nodes
because they're too small to read labels from.
Here again we are using the same simple tool tip from a treatment.
And finally this is the function that we're using to set the hover effect of each of us circles when
we mouseover a circle.
This how the value gets set.
True.
So for all of the nodes ancestors we're setting a class of node Hubner using this class method.
And then when we miss out the hover argument takes on a value of false and then we can remove the class
that we gave to these ancestors.
After this lecture you should feel comfortable working with the circle packing lab that Dietrich Gibbs's
for making this type of hierarchical visualization.
In the next lecture I'll be taking you through your final crash course in this class where I'll be introducing
you to the sunders plot which is a unique display of data to show splits in the hierarchies of multiple
levels.