In this lecture I'll be introducing you to the final crash course in data visualization.
I'll be running you through I'll be showing you how to use the partition lay out in D-3 to create a
sunburst plot.
We'll be using D-3 as our path generator again to add different nodes to the screen and I'll be showing
you another example of the D-3 hierarchy layout for getting our data into the right format.
Sunders plots are actually a really unique type of visualization that you can use for communicating
data about values within a hierarchy.
We're essentially communicating the same kind of data that we're using in the past two lectures except
this time.
We can easily compare groups with other items at that level in the tree.
We can see how the structure looks from this image on the left the root node is placed at the center
essentially conveying that 100 percent.
The chair of the value rests with the root.
At this level next going and level out of the tree we can see that the portion is split in two by the
two children and the node then even further out we can see that these values are split in the same way
to show leaf nodes every layer of this chart represents 100 percent of the system.
For example let's imagine the graph on the right is showing how population is split between different
regions in the middle.
We have the world a root node which contains 100 percent of the world's population.
Lay it out we might have continents would separate the world further route this ring still adds up to
100 percent of the world's population but it's showing another way for us to think about it.
Another layer out we might have regions within the continent which still includes 100 percent the world's
population.
We can follow any of these arcs outwards to see the proportion of regions population relative to a said
region.
It's also interesting to note that we can show hierarchies with different numbers of levels with this
plot.
For example we might want to show States Districts and Counties in the US but these groupings might
not exist in every country.
In this case the size of the Ark is still relative to 100 percent the world's population to 100 percent
the world doesn't have that categorical distinction.
Here's the example they'll be taking you through in this section.
Once again the data we're using is all about the flashlight.
So each of these arcs around a sunburst plot represents a package within the library.
For us color coding we're just giving every arc its own color unless it turns out that we're looking
at leaf node in which case the color will come from the color that we just gave to its parent node the
inner circle here represents flesh as a whole then we can see that this video package contains maybe
two thirds of the whole thing.
The next level down we see that this operator package comprises about a third of the size of the package.
You can compare X directly beside each other or we can compare them to the size of the whole library
by comparing its size to the ring that belongs to to make things even clearer.
This sunburst plot will we adjust to rent one of our packages whenever we click on it.
So here after clicking on this visit package we can see the packages inside it more clearly and we can
keep drilling down further to go back up a level.
We just need to click the point in the center of a chart.
So let's run through how this code is working.
This scale here is actually going to be used to set the number of degrees for UCS since it's just spitting
out a value between 0 and 2 pi which is equivalent to a full 360 degrees of a circle within using the
Y scale to set the width of each of the rings of a chart.
We'll be updating the domains for both of these scales.
Whenever we click on one of these running's this line here is setting up a petition which the lad will
be using to generate us on those plot values.
And then here's the generator which will be using to draw charts.
All of these next functions are just making sure that we never try to draw a circle with negative angles
or radiuses and we'll be using the scales that we just defined position.
Each of us of these calls to math don't mean are also making sure that none of our angles will ever
exceed 360 degrees.
I'm making some console logs as usual inside out data loading function to show you what's going on with
that data.
When we first load in our data to a file when given the root node of a hierarchy connected to an array
of all its children.
So we're using the hierarchy lay out to format it into something that we can use with the politicians
that we're passing into some method.
So all of those will give value field according to the sum of the size of all the fields and their descendants.
Once we pass the result onto a partition Lau we now have an x 0 x 1 1 0 and white 1 values attached
to every node in a hierarchy.
If we take a closer look at these values we can see the y values ranging from 0 to 1 depending on the
nodes depth and the hierarchy and the x values seem to add up to one for each level.
We're then calling the descendants method on this data which will pass onto this data join his descendants
giving us 252 nodes that exist within a hierarchy.
We want to append an arc in a sunbursts for each of them.
So that's why we're doing a data join on that.
Ray for every item in this array we're appending a path and passing in the array item to a function
to set the attribute.
We're also giving it a fill with the color scale which will give us a new color.
Unless we're looking at leafnode in which case it just inherit from the color of its parent.
When using this click listen it updates all charge whenever the nut gets clicked before adding a simple
tool tips.
Again let's look at what's happening inside this click function.
We're using a few different twins again to define some custom transitions when our selection changes
the tween method of a transition is slightly different from the answer tween method since it can be
used old and multiple values once.
It's not really important what we decide to call the first argument here since it's just a name for
reference.
The second argument or attend a function that will run on every take of our transition's clock these
inter-relate is running on the domain of x and y scales as well as the range of a Y scale.
The values on the right are showing the values that should take on once the transition is finished.
The function that was spitting out will update x and y scales repeatedly according to the interpolated
values.
Each moment in time then we're updating the attribute of each of our paths with the actual Queen function
down here which is spitting out the path that should be showing at every point of the transition making
use of updating scales.
After this lecture you should now know how to set up a sunburst plot in D-3 by combining the D-3 partition
lay out with D-3 is arc path generator.
Since this is one of the last war trees I'll be giving you this course.
I hope that you're now at a stage where you can quickly understand any piece of data from community
code all by yourself in the next lecture.
I'll be asking you to find a visualization by yourself which we haven't covered in this course.
I want you to find an example on line that somebody else has written copy into your workspace and play
around with the file until you can explain everything that's going on.