Congratulations the step that you just took in the last activity should hopefully have given you a lot
of confidence going forward.
You can now apply the skills that you first developed in the first six quiet sections of the Course
to understand adapt and improve.
Any kind of visualization in this section I introduce you to a range of different visualizations revolving
around hierarchical systems.
These visualizations are some of the most eye opening displays of data out there because they give us
a broad overview of how a different part of the system fits together in the next section.
I'll be returning to the visualization that we made for a third class project.
We were visualizing cryptocurrency prices over time.
We'll be restructuring our project files to clean up our code.
I'll be rewriting visualisations as objects to make them more usable.
And I'll be adding multiple visualizations to the page at once which will all connect together through
common events Hanlon's.
This will pay you for your final project where you'll be making a fancy data dashboard for a large conglomerate
company.