Now you have a good amount of experience with using the D-3 library.
It should be pretty easy for you to understand what's going on in a D-3 file.
So for whenever you introduce you to a new visualization I've had to step you carefully through the
process and show you how to write everything at in the real world.
You should never do starting your projects with empty files in almost every visualization that you're
likely to create.
There's probably someone out there who's already created something similar.
The process of physically writing this code out for yourself was useful for making you more comfortable
with what different functions are doing in D-3 But now you should get used to adapting your code from
others.
In the next three sections I'll be introducing you to 11 new types of visualization.
Instead of writing these visualizations myself I did what you'll be doing now.
Going forward I looked up the visualization that I wanted online and they copied the files they wanted
onto my local machine.
By the end of this section you'll know how to read somebody else's D-3 code to get a quick overview
of what's going on.
You'll know where to look to search for the visualizations that you're looking for and you'll be aware
of some of the nuances that come with dealing with different versions of the three.