One of the best things about the D-3 library is the buzzing ecosystem of developers though already using
it in this lecture.
I'm going to show you two of the best sites to check out to find helpful boilerplate code that can get
you started writing visualisations.
I'll be using these sites myself over the next three sections to find the different example implementations.
I'll be walking you through the reason why I've structured these next few sections as a series of crash
courses in different visualizations that you never really want to be writing all of your code from scratch
unless you're coming up with a new kind of visualization which is totally revolutionary to anything
that's come before.
Then you can be completely certain that some other code exists on line that you can adapt for your own
visualizations.
For D-3 we have two great Web sites blogs dot org and block build a dot org which make it easy to appropriate
small useful chunks of other people's code for your own projects.
I'm going to show you blocks first.
The idea behind blocks is that you can share snippets of D-3 code on line showing the code and the output
in your browser blocks is maintained by Mike Bostock who is one of the creators of D-3 and he's uploaded
many of the most commonly used visualizations out there.
On the home page you can see a list of the most popular blogs and generally speaking if you Google something
like bar chart code D-3 an implementation in blocks will probably come up near the top of your search
results.
So for example here we have a blog with the code building and tree map which will cover in section 9
on the top of blocks is another site called block building org which lets you edit someone else's blog
with an online editor meaning that you can basically make a fork of someone else's visualizations because
of this you'll find lots of code snippets on block builder that take something that's already been done
with blogs but has a slightly different twist to it.
So for example if we use the same you around that we would just on except with block build it instead
then we can edit it like Bostock's code directly in this window and things will just automatically update.
So for example I can change the width from 960 pixels to 500 pixels and the graph changes accordingly.
Did you sign up with an accountant block Builder.
Then he can also save the changes that you make inside the editor and you can force changes into a repository.
The best thing about block builder is that you're able to search through the catalog of code snippets
that users have upload a lot of times if you're looking for a fairly unique visualization.
Many of the best implementations might still only exist in older versions where you can do here is only
search for visualizations that use D-3 version for for example let's say that we want to find a bar
or in Version 4 we just type what we're looking for in the search box and we find one that we like.
So here's an interesting visualization where we have a diverging scale depending on where the data is
positive or negative as you can see.
Most of these files just have everything on the page a male page rather than splitting things up into
different javascript files.
As we've been doing your first step finding the visualization that you're looking for should be to separate
things out a bit into the files and from that you want to adapt the visualization to fit with your own
data using what you know about the D-3 update pattern and then handling from Section 5 and 6 in this
course and then be able to make static graphs of data based on the events that you care about.
After this lecture you should be aware of the different sites that you can use to find new types of
visualizations or be using these two sides repeatedly over the next few sections to source our example
code.
And I'd highly recommend that you take a look at then to check out the wide variety of prepared code
which you can download for free.