In this lecture I'm going to be talking about changes that came with the latest version of the three
version five we'll be showing you how to deal with them.
We'll be taking you through a quick example of the visualization that we've already seen to show you
exactly what we need to do to convert any file to version 5.
When this course was first published we were working with version 4.
So all of the videos in the next three sections assume that we're still running on that version.
Since this code block building still won't be updated for a while now I figured that it's easier and
more useful for me just to take you through the process of switching code over rather than redoing all
these videos from scratch.
The good news is that there's very little that we need to worry about with the switch over to version
5 for what we cover in this course.
We only really need to worry about two major changes which can cause version of apps to break.
Firstly we had a restructuring of D-3 data loading functions.
These functions now use promises rather than asynchronous callbacks to load in data.
We covered this already back in Section 2 and this change also meant that we don't need to use QS in
D-3 for loading multiple sets of data.
More on that later.
Secondly one of the old color schemes was removed with the D-3 chromatic library being installed in
the core build of the three instead.
Apparently some of the colors and D-3 scheme catch twenty scale with two similar and that might make
it seem like it was some relationship between categories that wasn't really there.
Let me take you through a quick example on block builder of how we would go about converting some version
for code to version 5.
Here we have a pretty contrived example of a simple but John blocks with everybody getting a different
color.
This gives me a good opportunity to really show off the power of this online tool and actually use the
editor which I won't be using for the rest of the course.
We can actually view this code side by side with what gets rendered in the browser window which is a
really nice feature.
We can see here that the script is using version 4.
Instead include in the script tags if we change this line right here it's come from the latest version
then we'll immediately see page breaks but nothing showing up on the screen.
Notice that block build up automatically updates this browser whenever we make a change which is also
really nice.
The first step for updating code to version 5 needs to be to look for any data loading functions and
convert the syntax that we've been using for promises.
We also have some error handling here in case something goes wrong when we try to load in a file we
are using this optional first argument in version forth to do that which will handle differently in
version 5.
We'll get rid of it now and we'll come back to it at the end.
First of we just need to tuck this callback function here.
The argument for the then method and suddenly we can see a buzz again.
They're turning it black.
What's happening here.
We're going to see that right here on line 22.
We're making a call to D-3 scheme catch 20 which no longer exists in the D-3 library.
We just need to replace this color scheme with any one of the three other color schemes to get it to
work properly.
If we go to the D-3 API reference which is a vast resource for anything about D-3 then we can find this
page on color schemes that we have to choose from.
You can see that the category 10 schemes still exists in version 5.
And in general we have a huge selection of options to choose from.
I'm going to go for D-3 scheme past the one which looks nice and then we just need to go back and change
this line right here to get it to work.
Finally the error handling.
We just need to define a catch method for a promise in case a promise is rejected.
I'm just passing in an anonymous function here and we'll just log out whatever the error message is
say to the console.
And that's it.
This is all we need to do to get our visualizations to work with version 5.
We already have them in version 4.
After this lecture you should now be able to take a walk cruise over the last three sections one step
further to they work with version 5.
You'll need to do this with your own projects at the D-3 eco system.
It can be quite Sloat de-tox example to the latest version.
This isn't too much of a process especially considering how tough it was when converting from Version
3 in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to the concepts of layouts and D-3 these functions and a set of different fields
that the data that we're working with which we can use to quickly build a certain type of visualization.