In this lecture I'm going to be introducing you to lab functions and D-3 which can be used to quickly
create all kinds of different visualizations.
I'll be walking through two different examples that will see over the next three sections to show you
how these functions work.
It's good to understand what these functions are doing because they give us the power to create a whole
host of common visualizations that would otherwise take a lot longer to figure out.
The basic idea behind the lay out is that you can call it on the set of data and the magic of the layout
function will spits out the same data with a new set of fields for each data point.
So just where this particular item should be placed on the screen we can then use these values generated
by our lab function to set attributes of a SVGA is all we can plug them into some kind of path generator
to draw something on the screen.
If you ever find yourself looking at some legacy code from the trees version 3 then you should be aware
of the difference in the syntax that exists in version for the only difference is that version of four
transitionary used a flat namespace.
So D-3 layer PI became D-3 pi the three layer force became the three fourths J2EE last stack became
D-3 stack and did really trim it became just D-3 trauma.
This final one here which we're covered towards the end of the section is a plug in lay out from our
community that generates word clouds this namespace didn't change between version 3 and version 4 because
it's maintained outside of the main D-3 library.
So what do these lab functions do exactly.
Here's an example that we'll cover later in this section where we're formatting our data using D-3 is
pilot.
We're starting off with an array of data in this format here on the left.
If we initialize a pi function in our code and call it on this data and this gives us the output on
the right we still have access to our original item in the data field.
So here again we can see accounts of 200 fruits of oranges and the rest region of east.
But now we also have a set of new values attached to each item in our
So here are pi function is looking at the Campfield for each of these items in the data and it works
out what the start and angle need to be.
Each of these values to make a full pie chart will then be plugging these values into a path generator
to draw each of the arcs of pi if we wanted to figure out the value of these parks ourselves.
Then this could have been a pretty tedious process.
We need to write some special kind of functions that looped over our array added these values together
found the ratio of each of these values to the total and then converted these values to be read in radians
for a graph as common as a pie chart.
It's helpful that D-3 comes with an easy way to figure out these values for us.
Here's another example that will cover in section 9 where we're making a treatment we're passing in
the data in this format on the left and our treatment plan is spitting out the values on the right.
Each of these 220 browes is representing a category that we want to display.
This time the data that we're providing on the left is actually the output from a different layout function
which formats the data into a hierarchy.
We can see that feeding this array of values into the treatment function.
We set up gives the same array of values just with some x 0 x one y one and why one feels
for this visualization all that we need to do is to append the rectangle for each of the rows in our
data and set that positions based on the coordinates the treatment function at it and for us it will
be a nightmare to try to figure out how to make each one of these on your own.
It really matters that rectangle rectangles in the same category a place together and there's a lot
of complex math going in to formulate the position of these areas.
This is the kind of chod the D-3 layouts are really useful.
Somebody has already done the hard work of implementing this layout already which handles all the complicated
stuff like figuring out the right spacing out for them is to use.
We just need to understand format the data should be in and get the syntax right for using them.
You know visualisations at the end of this lecture you should have a basic understanding of what let's
do it.
The three I've shown you some examples of how these functions mutate the data that we pass into them
and you'll be well-prepared to encounter some of these different labs in the next few sections in the
next lecture.
I'll be giving you a crash course on area charts and giving you a walkthrough of an example in notation
from somebody in the D-3 community.