In this lecture I'll be introducing you to every eight jobs in D-3 a walk through some example code
line by line introducing you to anything that we find.
You went have seen before the code in this lecture is really similar to the line graph code that I gave
you at the start of project three.
Except this time our path generates it will give us an area rather than a line just to be clear before
we get started.
An area chart is pretty similar to a line chart except that we have two lines that withdrawing an area
between.
Instead of just one we can use area charts and D-3 to make something quite advanced like the curve on
the right which is showing the difference between temperatures into different cities at different times
of the year.
If the area is green it means that one of them was warmer than the other and if it's red then it means
that the other one was water.
If you're interested in learning how to make this chart in D-3 you can actually find all the code for
this one on blocks.
However to start things off simply I'm going to show you the simple case on the left example that I'm
using for this lecture is coming from one of Mike Bostock's blocks which has a really simple static
implementation of an area of whenever you can.
I'd suggest trying to find one of the blocks by this author because all this code fits really well with
the D-3 conventions since he's one of the founders of D-3 and he makes sure that all the code he writes
works well.
You can see that this graph looks almost identical to our line chart except that the area beneath the
line has a field to it.
This example comes with an index to h g m l file as well as a TS.
The file containing two rows the first being a date and the second being number.
So here I copied this code into a folder at work from.
I've downloaded the data that was included into my data subdirectory.
If I was using this file in an actual project then my next step would be to transfer this javascript
into a separate maned.
Yes.
But for these examples I'll keep all my javascript in the script tags.
I've also added a nav bar to each of these examples to make the page look a little nicer.
In this example has already been SVGA on the page which app tweak to a size of 600 pixels by 400 pixels
looking at a javascript.
We can see the set up of our margins in the first two lines.
When getting hold of the SPG can this with this select tag then we're defining the size of our margins
here in the usual way for a width and height.
We're getting our values from the attributes of our existing as Candis meaning that to change these
values we just need to edit the HVM helpful.
Next we're adding on group element to the canvas and giving his usual translation into the center of
the page.
Here's the past function that we're using present day here maps to a two digit day of the month.
Person B maps to a three letter is shorthand for the month and percent.
Why is a four digit year.
We're setting on X scales a time scale and the y scale as a linear scale.
Something to know here is that we're using this range Rand method instead of our usual range method
for these scales.
What this means is that any output returned by this scale will be rounded to the nearest whole number.
For this graph we could easily just have written range and it wouldn't really have made much difference.
Here we're setting up a path generator.
This should look really similar to the line path generator that we saw in project 3 except that this
time we supply both the Y zero value and the y one value for this chart we're just saying the wise zero
value should always align with the bottom of Kandis to why there are line tracks the x axis you know
visualization and the y one line is varying according to the y axis value.
We're learning in our data with the D-3 TS We function since we're working with tab separated values
hey we're making use of an optional argument to the D-3 TS V function which lets us alter the attributes
of the data that we're loading in.
You can think of this as being equivalent to the for each loop that we've been writing so far.
But you might find this syntax to be a little more concise this function maps over our array of data
as soon as it's loaded and the result is passed on to our data as Ray within passing in the callback
function as usual we are using that era argument.
What data takes the second position of the argument list and here which is throwing an error if something
goes wrong when we try to read the file next we're setting that domains for axes as usual.
Since we now have access to our data array we using the extent to get minimum the maximum value for
x domain.
And the winds are Maina scaling between 0 and the largest value of a Y variable.
Next we're appending area path we using some syntax which is a little different here than we're using
for a line graph.
Here's how things look.
Between these two examples for a line graph we call the line function on our array of data.
This time we're passing our array of data to this data method and then passing up area generator to
what deam method without giving it an argument.
We can provide a data method like this when we want to perform a data join on just one element when
we provide an element with some data to use like this.
The attribute will automatically try to fit that array of data into the path generator that we provide
this syntax is useful when we want to think about how we might add multiple area paths to the same visualisation
to do that.
We're providing an array of arrays to the D-3 selection with the data method and then after calling
enter and depend on the selection we'd have access to each of these arrays when we're setting out the
attributes I'll be showing you how to do that in the next lecture.
Just to be clear the syntax that we right now is completely interchangeable with how we rotate that
line up if we change things up here we'll see that acha is working exactly the same as before.
Finally we're adding in both axes.
Generally speaking I would prefer to write the code that sets up groups outside of this data loading
function and then just call the access generators on this group.
But here Mike Bostock has chosen to add them both in the same time.
Both will work completely fine.
In this lecture I gave you a quick overview of some area code in the three I took you through the process
of interpreting someone else's code and introduce you to a couple of new things that you hadn't seen
so far.
I want you to think about what you would need to change to make this visualization update between different
sources of data.
Which parts of your code would crucially need to live in your update function.
And which part of your code would you want to keep at the top of the file.
When you think about this bear in mind that the code in this example wasn't really too different of
the code that you were using for project 3 in the next lecture.
Be you now be working with a similar file to this but this time I've been using the D-3 stack layouts
to create a stacked area chart which can be used in a slightly different way.