In this lecture I'll be covering two different example implementations of stacked area Cha's and D-3.
Again I'll be explaining anything that shows up that we haven't covered already and I'll be showing
you how to use the D-3 stack.
Lay out formant this data in the right way.
Stex charts can be really useful because they can show overall value and a category value of a variable
at the same time.
A classic example is to show how a company's market share has changed over time relative to its competitors.
Stack charts have a lot of explanatory power here because on the one hand they can show how ratios are
changing over time.
For example we could look at the question of how is Samsung been doing compared to Apple in the U.S.
smartphone market.
But equally the graph also illustrates how the entire market's value has been changing at the same time.
So we could also use that look at the question of how is the market for smartphones grown in the U.S.
recently.
I'll be walking through stacks area charts from this lecture.
Or you could also use the same stack that I'll be covering two mega stacks but not here's the first
example they'll be walking you through from might bust up again.
It's showing the shift in market share of different web browsers over time as a percentage.
We have an index file and the is Theophile which I'm copying into my folder again the data is in a format
where each row is a point in time with different numbers for each of these different browsers.
Here's the second example that'll cover from somebody called Maggie.
It's showing the change in oil consumption per country over time.
Notice that with this one the overall value is changing over time as well as the proportion between
different areas.
I found both of these blocks pages from a simple Google search and they were two of the top results
for stack area charts.
I'll start off with our first example here.
A lot of this code is actually pretty much identical to our last area chart example with setting the
SPG and I Jamail and we set in the exact same variables at the top of our javascript file to sort out
our margin convention we have time on the x axis again and you can see that our specifier is in a slightly
different order to match the format of the data.
Next we're making a call here to do three stack which I'll explain a little later.
We're creating a similar path generator again for this area variable but this time we're accessing some
different fields.
We'll get all of these values using our stack layout.
We're setting this G variable as usual although for some reason this is a little out of order from normal
then here's our data loading function this time.
Here is the name of a function at the bottom of the file which is transforming every data point in our
array.
We're converting all of our data straight we're converting all of our date strings into jobs script
data objects with a parser again and this line here is just diving into all about objects values and
this line here is just dividing all of our objects values by a hundred so that we have them as a percentage.
Next we're getting hold of this list of column headers again in a similar way.
Whenever we load in data using one of the three data loading functions we have access to our column
headers by this column field
slicing this array index one again removes the date heading.
So we just get an array for our browser names.
We're setting up X scale domain for here but where is why scales their main.
It turns out that the scales domain defaults to a value between 0 and 1 in this example because trigraph
is measuring between zero and 100 percent on the y axis we don't actually need to separate the main
within then using this list of browser names as the domain for a color scale.
And we're also passing this list as the kids method to us stack.
Next we're doing a data joint on the stack of data matching elements where the class of Leya within
appending one of these layers which turned out to be SVGA groups for each of these items in the array.
Then for each of these groups we're attaching a path using our area generating function this block of
code here is responsible for adding the text labels to the chart because we're writing the labels at
the far right of the chart we're filtering out browsers that don't really exist in the most recent date
because otherwise they might all pile up in the same place.
Overall I'd say that it's a pretty bad design decision to write the chart this way because you always
have a danger that these labels could overlap and it doesn't look particularly nice.
If I was rewriting this visualization now then I would instead choose to make a legend for each of these
browsers.
Finally again we're adding in the axes at the end of this data loading function.
So let's figure out what's going on with this D-3 stack function.
If you ever come across something that you haven't seen in D-3 before then a great place to look is
in the D-3 API reference which you can find on the D-3 page.
This gives a really thorough explanation of all the different parts of T-3 here.
I'm looking at the entry for D-3 stack.
We can see that our stack expects input data to be in specific format.
Here we have a table with columns for different fruit's with every row giving us values for these foods
at different times.
We'll be passing this data in an array of objects just like data loading functions return.
We need to provide an array of strings to this case method which aspect function will match with the
field names for each of our objects.
We can also provide an optional order method which can be used to sort these keys and there's also an
optional offset method which you can use to shift the path around the set point.
For example you courageous stacked craft where a positive value set over the base line a negative value
set below the baseline.
Once we've set up this stack function if we pass in our data in the right format and it will give us
an array like this for every column we have an array for every line in data containing a lower end of
value.
The idea is that for each line of data we now have a stack between all of these different Cullens which
will stay in order.
So here in our first period apples go from zero to three thousand eight hundred forty then bananas goes
from 3000 aged 40 to five thousand seven hundred sixty.
Then Cherrie's goes until six thousand seven hundred twenty and then dates go until seven thousand one
hundred twenty.
We can then pass on these values to us scales to use them in our visualization.
Going back to our code I'll make a couple of console logs to help us understand what's going on here.
I'm logging in the data that we're loading in from a file and the result of a step function on this
data which we're passing into our data join.
So let's take a look at the format of this data.
We have an array of 367 rows of data.
You can also see the columns field data loading function gives us which has the header names that we're
using to get our array of browsers.
Each row is an object which has a field for each of our web browsers and the date field which contains
a j as Date object.
Recall that this is the right format the data should be in before it gets passed to us.
That function after we pass this array into a stack.
This is what we get we have an array of eight different items to one for every browser name from Akis.
Ray for each item we see the column name it relates to with this key variable that the stack gives us
then for every row in our dataset.
We have our array of two values which are stack function has prepared for is showing its lower end up
value in our stack.
We can then access the original row of data that this item relates to using this data field.
Looking back at our code now we can see how it's all fitting together.
Firstly we're passing an array of 8 browsers for my stack function to our data join on this legislation
then with Enter we're appending a group for each of them since we're giving out groups a class of Leya
here.
This means that if we wanted to update that data then a selection will match on these groups updating
them with a new data rather than adding new groups every time.
Then for each of these groups we're adding a path and giving a fail by calling an ordinal scale on the
name of our browser from the key field.
Next we're saying the idea should be of these paths with an area generator this passes the array of
data that we associated with each of our groups to every function.
So this is what we're passing to our area generator for each of our browsers.
We're writing an area path between the lower and upper values from our stack running across each of
the 367 points in our dataset.
We're setting the x coordinates here through the data field which gives us access to the data objects
for each row.
We also need to remember to pass each of these values to us scales as usual so that the face on our
chart I'll also give you a quick run through of this other example just to show you what would be different
when these values don't all add up to 1.
The way that this graph has turned there is a really good argument for using a legend set of labels
but these because we can't tell what any of these labels at the top is supposed to say.
The only real difference between this code and the code to my other example is that we need to work
at the right maximum domain for a wide scale usually with set the maximum for a domain based on the
maximum y value that we want to display.
However in this case because we're stacking our White values the maximum of our domain should be the
largest total value of adding these categories values together in a given row of data.
For example in this graph the largest total value of oil consumption came in 2015.
So we need to end up with the value of the total oil consumption in that year.
We're working this out with this Max date function first we're using the DS3 max function on our array
of data which loops through every period.
Here's the access a function that we're using which will return the values that D-3 should find the
maximum between We're using a map function on the head and names for data returning each of the values
into this array called vals.
If we're looking at the date field the value will be zero.
Then we're returning the results of adding each of these values together which is provided by the D-3
some function.
The result is that this function will spits out the largest total value from these countries which is
in 2015 we're then using this to set the maximum wide main.
It's really useful to be able to do this with this chart because we simultaneously able to tell a story
about how global oil consumption has been on the rise and also to the degree to which countries have
contributed to that rise.
Not after this lecture.
You should understand had the D-3 stack Ladds is working to create a Stex area chart of your own.
You'll be making stacked area charts like this in your final class project as part of a data dashboard
which connects between different visualisations in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to some of the challenges that come with taking the right data structures to
use for your visualizations and showing you how to use D-3 handy nest function to group different categories
of data.