In this lecture I'll be talking about how we should work with different data structures that we might
find ourselves using in D-3 will often find that our code comes in a certain format and that we need
to coerce that data in some way to use it with D-3 I'll be demonstrating the difference between storing
data in arrays versus storing them in objects and also be introducing age at the D-3 nest function which
allows us to group arrays of objects into different categories.
Whenever we use a layout in DS 3 the function will expect our data to appear in a certain way.
We'll often need to juggle our data around a bit so that works as expected.
As you begin to make larger and larger visualizations You can also improve the performance of a visualization
considerably by picking the right data structure to use in the first place.
There are two main data structures that we have to work with on the one hand we have arrays.
Every element in the array can be stored at an index which we can then use to get its content the advantage
is that we can loop through these arrays pretty easily with a map function or a For Each loop.
43 is also especially useful that we can pass an array is that data method to a selection to use it
for a data join.
On the other hand we have objects or maps which are pretty similar for objects.
Our data is stored in key value pairs.
The advantage here is that we can immediately fetch the value stored inside one of these keys without
having to search through the entire data set.
Right.
This is especially useful if we repeatedly need to access the value.
For example every time a visualization updates
in G-3 will often find ourselves handling arrays of objects for example every time that we load in a
data file with D-3 we get back an array where every item is an object representing a row in that table.
Here's a situation that might seem a little challenging if we have an array like this.
We want to find the size of the item with the ID of Homer then we'll need to search through the entire
array checking to see whether each item's ID is equal to home.
And then we'll need to return the size of that item.
This is what's known as a brute force search.
It's not really a problem for this array because it only has two items search between there when we
need to do this for a data set with thousands of rows.
Then our visualization can start to get overloaded pretty quickly.
In this case a more elegant solution could be to convert data into a different format.
Here's another way that we could have written data on the right data has been stored as an object instead
of an array.
Now whenever anyone wants to know the size of Homer all they need to do is use the home key in the object.
This can be really useful if we'll need to look up the value repeatedly.
We can also do something similar to group rows of data into different category names so that we can
immediately access each of these categories by different keys.
D-3 comes with a really useful function to make this kind of conversion easy for us called a D-3 nest.
This allows us to group the rows of our data according to different keys.
We can even do this on multiple different levels.
For example let's say that we have a data set with Baali yields for different sites in Minnesota for
different years with this yields variable.
We were just reading in from a C S V file.
Let's imagine that we're working with a huge set of data.
Let's say that we want to make a pie chart comparing the yields of the different varieties of barley
and we want to use it to be able to choose a year to look at so each of these are to representing a
different strain of barley in the year 1931 the way that our data is structured right now our code would
need to loop over every single element in the yields array check if it's year matches the year the user
selected.
And if it does we need to add it to the total for the variety that belongs to.
This ends up creating a lot of different operations that our code needs to run through in order to make
a really simple update to a graph.
If the array that we're searching through is large enough then this could cause some serious lag for
our visualization.
We can improve on this by using D-3 as Nest function to use D-3 nest.
We just need to provide it with an access function using the key method which will point on that to
the values they should be grouping by.
If we provide more than one of these key methods and be grouping our data by more than one category.
So here we're pointing out first key method to look at the year of each item and our second key method
is looking at the variety of each item.
Then we pass in our array of data with this entry's method.
This means that DS3 will restructure the array of data that we're passing in returning an array of objects
one for every distinct year in data and within that array 3 has broken it down further.
Returning an array for all of the different varieties in our data the output of this entry is variable.
It's given here at the bottom.
Now we can calculate the yields in each of these different years when we first load in our data.
And then if we wanted to switch between different years all that we need to do is pass in the object
with a different key of the year that we're looking for.
This means that we don't have to search through nearly as many lines of code to find the relevant pieces
of data for a selection.
So a visualization should update with far less lag.
After this lecture you should understand some of the considerations you'll need to take into account
when you want to get your data in the right structure.
You should also know why we might need to use nest in D-3 to group Avro is by different fields.
You'll find yourself needing to worry about this more and more as your projects become more and more
complex requiring data in multiple formats.
And as you begin to work with the greater volume of data in the next lecture I'll be showing you how
to create PI and donut charts in three.