In this lecture I'll be teaching you how to make pie charts and Donat charts with T-3 using two different
examples for this I'll be showing you how to use the D-3 PI lay out introducing you to trees ARC path
generator and shanking the trick tween method which we can call on transition's.
I'll also be taking you through the process of converting some code into E-3 version 3 version for as
our second example is adapted from Version 3 code pie charts and one of the most common visualizations
out there because they offer a really simple way to visualize ratios between different categories because
they're so common.
Everybody knows how to read them.
So they usually a really safe bet that displaying any kind of data on a per capita basis if you're wondering
a donut shop is just a pie chart with an area cuts are in the middle.
Personally I think these are a lot more aesthetically pleasing than the regular pie chart and it's really
simple switch to go between the two three.
I'll be taking you through these two examples in this lecture for a first example here.
I've once again found an example from Mike Bostock on Bloch's dot org.
This time we have a CSP file for our data and I've gone ahead and put all of this code into my project
files.
As usual Again I don't like the idea of using these labels for a pie slices because they could always
potentially overlap if one pie slice comes to small.
So for this example I've taken these out of our walkthrough code.
If I was making this chart for an actual project I would once again i'd to make a legend to sit alongside
the graph for another example.
I wanted to show you an updating version of the pie chart because the update pattern looks a little
different morphing between different paths.
There was a beautiful example here from Mike Bostock but unfortunately it's still in Version 3 this
code needed a few tweaks so that we could use it properly envision for this is a common problem that
you'll sometimes have as legacy code in Version 3 still needs to be updated with version 4.
So let's take a look at our first example pie chart here.
We're not using the margin convention here although that's less important if our graph doesn't have
an X with setting a height and with variables and with defining the radius value here which we'll keep
using with setting the radius as half of the value which ever number of smallest out of width and height.
Next we're setting an ordinal scale with an array of colors and we're declaring our generator.
Our generator just needs to be given an inner and outer radius value where we've said the inner radius
to zero which gives a picture.
But all we need to do to change this to be a donut char is to give some value as the radius for example
of set the inner radius to be 8000 pixels less the radius value.
So isn't that sandwich nicer.
Next we're setting up a pie layout function which will pass our data to.
And here we're adding an SPG canvas using a group to shift it into the middle of the screen.
Next we're loading in our data here with the D-3 CSP function and we're using this type function again
to clean up our population values into numbers that we can work with then we're converting our data
using up-I layout function giving the results onto our data join entering a new item in that array and
then appending a path for each item.
This is working similarly to stack area.
So it's working.
We're passing in a function with no arguments which will automatically get given the item of data that
it's associated with we're then setting the fill of each of these shapes with a color scale.
Let's take a look at what our lab function is doing with some console logs.
Again a log or data as it's loaded as well as when we call our pi function on it.
So here we have the structure the data needs to be in to work with the pie lay out each row need to
associate to a category that we want to display.
Then we're using this value method of Pi layouts as an access a function to tell the three where I can
find the value for the pie slice that the item should show.
After running this function on our data we can see the changes that this has for every item of Pylea
or has added in some attributes for start and end angles and the original data object is available in
this data field again.
There's also this padding angle which you could have set up as a method with the Pylea out to give some
space between each of the slices.
When we passed this data onto our generator the generator will automatically recognize these field names
and construct the path as pages accordingly.
Once again we didn't actually need to do that much to build this chart.
The magic of using layouts in D-3 that we just need to figure out the right format of the data that
D-3 expects and then pass the Right now used in those methods.
Here's the code for the second example that we're working through.
I'm just working with the same file from blocks except that I've switched from using D-3 version 3 to
Version 4 everything at the top of our code looks the same except for a few lines in Version 3 which
has changed.
This is to be what scales looked like in version 3.
We used to have nested name spaces where each of the scales belong inside the D-3 scale module inversion
for one of the main changes which was that each of these names were changed.
So now we have D-3 scale Timon's to the three scaled up time three scale linear and sort of T-3 scaled
up Linnea and so on for ordinal scales.
In particular the syntax is totally different in version 3.
There was a scale that came fitted with each color scheme already but now we need to create a generic
ordinal scale and then sets it with one of the color schemes that D-3 gives us.
As I mentioned already when I introduce you to lay out back in the day layouts also used to come in
the branch of D-3 But now we have a layout function for each graph that we want to make.
So getting back to our code of change these two lines here so that our graph will work with version
4 will loading in the data as before with a TSB function.
This time however our data isn't in the right format straight away.
I'll make some console logs to show you what's going on.
We're flicking between two different categories for this chart.
Apples and oranges for each category.
We have some different regions that we're showing in our own chart.
If we look at our data as it's loaded in then you'll notice that every row is a region fruit.
If we passed this data straight to our pilot now we would get back a pie chart with eight slices but
we only want to show either the regions associated with apples or the regions associated with oranges
depending on what I use it wants to see.
So we need to group our data according to these keys.
We're achieving this here with the use of this next function.
Let's check out what this is doing.
We're setting the key to mesh on the fruit value of each item in the array.
Meaning that this will spits out a two item array with the rows associated with apples in one group
and the rows associated with oranges in the other this code here is just adding in our radio buttons
and it's saying that whenever a selection changes between oranges and apples the change function should
get fired.
This is actually coded in a really interesting way.
We're using a data joint at each of these options in Fromont nested data.
And here in the change again we're passing in the data associated with each of our items to the change
method.
So every time this radio button gets changed to oranges it will fire the change function with the orange
is part of the nest that we made.
Then inside our change function we're passing these rows to our pilot function with this values field.
This code gets a little confusing here.
We're looking at two variables.
Data zero data one data zero is the data that the pie chart is currently set with data.
One is the new array of data that we're updating our chart to show.
We're keeping track of these two arrays because we will need to look between both of them to handle
the transitions.
You can see that we're using unusual D-3 update pattern for these arcs here.
We're starting out with our data join we're passing in data one which is showing the rows in our data
specific to the fruit that we look at this key variable is just an access a function defined at the
bottom of a file which is telling the data method to match array items based on that region value.
I'll start off by explaining our code for the entering arcs first because we're setting some values
that we'll use later on.
For every item in the array that we need to enter onto the screen or appending a path we're using this
each method here to run some code for every item we're starting up by calling this fine neighbor our
function which we have at the bottom of the file.
We passed this function our data zero array which is the current state of our data for the change function
fired and our data one array which is the data that our visualization is changing to.
We're also giving it the items index in the new array and it's key which will be a region name.
Here we are using two separate functions fine proceeding and find the following fine proceeding will
give us the element in our data 0 Obray that is 1 index for where this element is placed in our data
1 array.
Then fine following will give us the element in our data zero array which comes after this element in
our data 1 array this code here is finding the element that comes before the item in the data zero array
and returning an object with the same starting and ending angle which matches the end angle as the up
for it.
We basically have an ELSE IF condition here which deals with the case that the new item that we want
to add in our day to one array is added that index 0 7 be no preceding values in the data zero array.
In that case we look for the following elements in the array the item at index 0 in data 0 and return
an object of the same start and end angle at the start angle the arc that follows it.
If the function can find either of these then this means that the array in data zero must be empty.
So we can tell that we're adding odds for the first time so going back to our Enter method here we're
setting a private field for each of our paths using the name Current.
This is just going to be used within the code that we're writing here and I will keep track of the data
array that it's currently set to.
If this is the first run of a change function or we haven't entered any auks onto our canvas yet then
we're setting the current value of our object here to the value of the item that we're looking at.
However if we do find a neighboring arc then we're setting the current value of Arc equal to the object
that was returned so to clarify this will be an object with the same start and end angle which matches
the angle that it's going to appear from then here we're setting the args fill value with a color scale
here is the first time you've seen this method called a tween Etra tween is a method that you can use
on transitions to define a custom interpolator for transitioning an attribute.
Why do we need this.
Well for simple attributes like the width of an SPG D-3 is transition's we can pretty easily figure
out the right values to use however D-3 has a tougher time with pack's for transitioning between paths.
It's not as obvious where D-3 should be requiring each path with its transition to make this clear.
We have to set this behavior with Ettrick tween the first argument here contains the attribute that
we're twinning.
In this case the D attribute for a pair the second you mentioned return a function that will run in
every take of a transition clock which will update the path that should be displayed for each ugh.
Here's the function that we're using at the bottom of a file as usual we're allowed access to the item
in our data array that we're working with with this the argument this is the item in the data 1 array
that we want to enter onto the screen.
So this function that we're returning here is going to run on every take at the clock and it'll update
or attribute to this value.
This team variable turns out to be a number between 0 and 1 representing the time and this variable
here is giving as a custom interpolator to use when giving it two objects which is going to transition
between the current.
Is the value that we just set which is the object with the same startled end angle where arc is going
to appear from.
So when we pass a value between 0 and 1 to this and interpolate here it will spits out an object which
has some proportion of the way between the object that we're starting from and the one that we're ending
up with.
Once we have that set we're updating the current value to show the angles the arc has once it's transition.
We also have an update which is doing something similar.
We are using the same arc tween function and the bottom of the file to change the value of a D attributes
every take of the clock.
So once the arc enters we have it start and end angle from setting the current field.
So for updating we're transitioning between those angles and the ones that we get from the new data
array.
Finally for exiting elements we want to transition from our current value to an arc with the same start
and end goal which matches where its neighbor will be.
We're doing this by setting the data associated with the exciting element to this value here.
This time when using find neighbor with data arrays switched around.
This will return the position of the angle in our data one array.
The options shrink towards giving its neighbor in the data zero array.
After this lecture you've been introduced to making pie charts and D-3 you should know how the pie layout
works together with D-3 is our generator to quickly make a pie chart on your.
Now where the Attah tween method the transitions gibbers to handle path transitions.
There ended up being a pretty in-depth walkthrough.
Again don't worry if you didn't completely understand every single line in this file right away.
In the same way that you don't need to know how a car's engine works to drive.
You don't need to know how these particular help functions are working to successfully build the picture.
The important thing is that you know which code you need to change in order to fit the visualization
with your data.
In the next lecture I'll be running you through word classes which will represent an engaging way to
visualize lots of text.