And this lecture I'll be talking about word clouds which are a special type of visualization designed
to show the most commonly used words in a piece of text for D-3 version 3.
Somebody in the community created a fantastic plug in lay out for generating world class however this
plugin still hasn't been updated to the latest version.
I'll be walking through a piece of community code that was written by somebody else which applies some
fixes to this plug in to make the world class work with version 4.
So what exactly is a word cloud.
You're most likely to have seen word clouds in the context of a Web site called Wordle where you could
paste in a big block of text and then get back something that looks like this where the size of the
text representing how many times a word is used.
This is a really useful visualization to never have to build because it gives a fun and interesting
way to visualize words although there are lots of great examples out there of word clouds written in
D-3 because there's is a bit more of a niche visualization.
There aren't that many version for implementations I'm using the search page for block builder to see
which implementations already exist in version for this is the one they ultimately settled on where
somebody in the community has written some edits into the D-3 cloud plugin library.
So they may even use it with version for this example here it works with Chinese characters.
They're conveniently The data also comes with some English characters that we can sub in and that the
size of these pieces of text don't actually mean anything since they're generated at random.
But we could easily tie this attribute to something data here's my local version of this code which
I've copied into my workspace.
You can see that we're including this D-3 cloud file here which is a community edit that came with this
example.
As usual we're setting up everything that we need with margins and loading in our data from a cxxviii
file and data folder Ahmed to console logs here to show what's going on with data.
The first log here is showing the format of data as it's loaded in Frolov file.
We have an array of teams with both Chinese and English names and for each team we have to state that
it belongs to were then passing this array of data into the words method of a word cloud layer.
After we do this we have a new set of attributes which can get added on to each element in our array
giving us access to some coordinates where an item should be placed on the screen as well as the font
size and some styling for each of them.
It's important to note that this layer function is destructively altering the array that we read and
from our data.
Rather than creating a new array to contain a layer this carried him might look a little confusing.
So break it up a bit so that it's easier to read we using a D-3 nest function to group these items in
our data array according to this date fields then once we have that we're passing this array into the
D-3 kids function which will return a string of all of the different keys together.
This is just being used as a quick way to get a list of distinct state names in our data.
And there are a few different ways that we could also read this where this font size variable is a scale
that we'll be using to set the size of each of our pieces of text.
The scale is a power scale which essentially does the opposite of a log scale.
This will mean that if we passed in two inputs that are really close together then we'd get out to outputs
that really far apart.
The scale runs from an input inside the domain of 0 1 and an output inside the range of forty eight
next we're saying up our cloud.
First we're setting the width and height of a word cloud.
Using this size method next we're passing in our array of words with this words method and we're setting
a font size to be a random value between 40 and 80.
We're also passing in this field that contains our text by giving an access a function to this text
method.
In this case we want to show the team names in English.
This listener here will draw the line for us.
Once the algorithm is complete.
Using this Krol function finally we're calling starts on this lay out which starts the Liya algorithm
going once D-3 cloud has figured out exactly where the words should be placed.
The code inside of cross-functional will add in a new word for every item.
Data the words value head that we're passing in is coming from a layout function which gives us the
transformed version of our original array.
We're setting the fill of our text SVGA based on the color scale and then we're saying this size font
text content and position based on data.
After this lecture you should now be able to create a word cloud of your own by adapting a file like
this to work with your data.
By this point you should hopefully be starting to get the hang of the process of understanding someone
else's code which is written into three in the next lecture.
I'll be testing out what you've learned with the last that we've covered so far.
Making sure that you have a good understanding of what we've been covering.