At the end of this section you now have five new types of visualization.
They are able to express with these three I've taken you through a quick tour of different people's
code covering a few topics that we've just glazed over before.
And at this point you should be starting to get the hang of the process of quickly understanding what
D-3 file fits together and you should feel like you could afford any of the visualizations that we've
covered already and adapt them into your own data.
Importantly you also learned about how lappets work in D-3 attaching a set of attributes onto the data
that we're trying to work with.
And I'll be showing you some more examples of these over the next two sections as they're making the
job of building more complex visualizations a whole lot easier.