The visualization that we ended up with at the end of last section lets us see a nice overview of how
this data is changed over time.
However the visualization will be far more useful if the user could explore the data with some more
advanced features over the course of this section.
I'll be introducing you to a variety of extra components that will gradually allow the user to do more
without visualization.
We'll be using event handlers and listeners to update the visualization as they use it interacts with
different elements on the page.
And by the end of this section you should feel comfortable with implementing a host of that interactions
and attaching event listeners to SVGA use on the screen.
Finally will use your new skills to develop an interactive line up your third class project.
The project involves displaying historical prices at different crypto currencies and gives you a chance
to really experiment with some common interactive components.