So looking in the visualization that we built at the end of last section we actually can't tell for
sure which consonants we're looking at before we get into handling user interaction.
I'm going to take you through the simple process of adding legend to your charts.
This will also give us some more experience working with espying.
JS This time using them to break our code into a better more reusable structure.
We're going to be adding a group to contain the whole legend then a group to contain the legend rose
and then for each legend Rowe will be adding a text SVGA to the relevant label.
The square with the right color to make things simple since we only have four different consonants to
worry about.
I'm just going to hard carried a list of consonant names for us to work with.
First of all writing group to contain the entire legend and then shift it with a translation so it sits
at the bottom right of up actualization.
Next I'll use a For Each loop on our list of constant names to append each of our Legin bro groups.
Are stored in a variable so that we can append to it later and then give each of these rows a translation
so they don't overlap amusing the index for a For Each loop to do this so that each of our rows are
separated by 20 pixels in the wide erection for each of these rows I want to append a colored square
and a text SPG with the name of the consonant.
So for starters I've added a rectangle with the height and width to 10 pixels for each run of the loop
giving a fill of the color return from an ordinal scale on the name of the consonant that we're looking
at.
Finally I'm going to append a text SVGA for each of outros of even the text an x value of minus 10 and
the text anchor.
And so the text gets appended to the left of squares and they're given a y value of 10.
So the text lines up vertically.
I'm passing in the string of a constant name that we're looking at.
The text method and I'm also using the style method here to capsulize each of these strings.
Since they're in lowercase a quick know about the difference between the style method and the actual
method here.
The style method is used to set CSSA styles of SPG and D-3 sometimes styles can also be attributes such
as field stroke stroke with incapacitate but not all styles can be set as attributes such as the text
transform style.
You'll often see Antara in style used interchangeably but realize that sometimes you need to use one
rather than the other.
Now once we go back to our browser we can see that a legend is working as expected and we now see what
each of the colors is representing.
Hopefully this lecture was useful as a refresher to think about what we can do with groups he'll often
be using legends for your visualization.
Whenever you are using a color scheme and it's helpful to have a simple process to work through making
them because the way that we've written this code it should be easy to copy and paste this lecturn to
work with pretty much any chart that you need.
In the next lecture I'll be introducing you to formatting and parsing in d 3 which would be really important
for working with time series data and which will also be using in the following lecture.
When we add tool tips to our chart.