In this lecture I'm going to be running you through some functions that D-3 gives us formatting data
I'll be introducing you to the D-3 format function which allows us to convert messy numbers into a clean
format that we can display on our graphs.
You learn the syntax behind specifiers which these format functions are meant to interpret and also
introduce you to D-3 time format and D-3 time pauvres which will often be using whenever you need to
work with dates and your visualizations.
We'll mainly be using the format function in this course to convert Mesi floating point numbers into
a clean uniform format.
This could involve adding income as a separate thousands with large numbers determining how many decimal
points are some significant figures we should use or displaying numbers as a percentage as a currency.
The way that the format function works is by feeding in a specified string which tells the format function
how to format its inputs.
I'll be giving a brief overview of the specifiers in the next few slides but you should check the D-3
documentation if you want to understand it more thoroughly.
Here's what format functions might look like in D-3 these strings that we're passing in as the arguments
to a format functions of the specifiers and you can see how using different characters we can induce
few different behaviors.
The syntax might look a little confusing here.
D-3 format actually returns a function which is taking a numbers argument.
We can also store this function as a variable as we have an example below and then call that variable
as a function.
This might make more sense if we're using the same format repeatedly in different parts of our code.
For putting together a specifier of our own to use we need to put the right characters in the right
order of us ring.
There are a lot of different options for exactly how each format numbers but to keep things simple.
I'm just going to talk about the sign symbol comma separator precision and type part of the string.
All of the other fields are optional so we can leave any of the shows out as long as everything else
is in the right order.
The first important field to talk about is the sign field.
If we use a minus sign here then a format will show a minus sign for negative values with nothing for
zero positive numbers.
If we use a plus sign then a format will add a plus sign for zero and positive numbers with the minus
sign negative numbers.
If we use a left bracket we'll have nothing zero and positive numbers and a number in parentheses with
negative numbers.
Next if you write a dollar sign then D-3 will add a currency symbol to that number.
It's important to know that if you want to use a different currency than US dollars then you need to
define a custom locale and call the function as a module of the locale.
A locale is basically an object with fields containing country specific information such as the unions
that things are measured in.
If you want to learn how to make a locale of your own and you can check it out and the D-3 documentation
if at this point you add a comment to the string then the function will add a comma as a thousands separator.
Again if you want to use a different character as a space eg thousands or if you want to group digits
by a number different than three then you can pass that information into a custom locale and call it
from there.
Next if you add a decimal point in followed by a number then this will tell D-3 how many Deprenyl points
to show as the precision depending when you put the type field covered in the next slide you could take
this number to be a number of significant figures or to be a number of decimal points.
Finally we can add one of these type values to give number a particular format.
The most common values that you'll actually want to use are F which formats the number is having a fixed
number of digits after the decimal point or a cent sign which forms the number as a percentage.
For formatting time D-3 has a separate suite of functions called the three time format in the time.
Cause again we'll be creating a string to pass into our time format and time pass functions which will
determine how the data is formatted.
We're using the time format function.
The goal is to go from a javascript data object to a human readable stream.
For example we might want to show the data on the screen corresponding to a point on a time axis.
Since that time scales only work with javascript data objects will want to format the output as an easy
to read string.
D3 timepass goes in the opposite way.
We provide a differing format and possible will convert spring of a date that matches the format into
a javascript date object.
For example we might have a list of dates in the spreadsheet strings which we want to make a time scale
with again as time scales.
I only work with the javascript data object and we need to write a parser to work with the dates in
a spreadsheet in terms of how we structure a specifier.
For time formatting and passing we can use any of these directives to get different pieces from the
date object.
Each of these directives take the form of a percentage sign followed by a character.
We can add any kinds of characters that we like outside of these directives and they will be rendered
with the format space things out.
Let me walk you through a couple of examples here to show how the specifiers should look in the time
pass function here.
We're using three directives present day gives as a two digit number representing the day of the month
percent and gives us a two digit number representing the month and percent y gives a two digit number
expressing the year.
We're also using three slashes as padding.
When we feed in 19 slash 12 slash 93 here.
Our parser interprets 19 as the day 12 is the month and 93 is the year and spits out 19th of December
1993.
A javascript date object for the time format function we're passing in percent and present day in different
order and we are using a percent capital Y which instead relates to four digit regimentation year.
We're also using dashes to separate dates instead of slashes.
We can put any characters that we wanted to specify to do this with.
Now if we put the data object that we got from a time pass example into this format function we get
a string representation of the date in the format that we are asking for.
So here we have the American style date format where the first field corresponds to the month the second
field corresponds to the day.
Hopefully by the end of this lecture you should understand how to write specifiers for both number formatting
and time for it.
You shouldn't need to memorize all of the different symbols that you might need to write to the specifiers
but you should feel comfortable with using the D-3 documentation as a reference for what to use in the
next lecture I will be adding tool tips to graph from the last section which will let the user take
a deeper look into the data.