Although a graph now has a legend that lets you see the consonant that each of us relates to.
It might be useful for our users to view the broad data from a given country in a given year.
It would be nice if the user had some way of following one of the circles over time and finding out
which country it represents.
In this lecture we'll be adding some tool tips to a graph what this means is that the users will be
able to hover over one's circles with their mouse and the box will appear giving all the information
to relate to that particular data point.
To do this we'll be making use of the D3 type library which is the third party plug in that somebody
from the D-3 community is designed to work with these three.
We'll also be putting on newfound knowledge about formatting into practice to make our data appear in
a tween and readable way.
At the end of this lecture we should have a tool kit that looks something like this hovering over Italy
here the user can see a nice clean display which shows country name continent life expectancy.
GDP per capita population in the current year.
Here we can see the sin taxes involved in adding a tool to it.
Firstly we are calling the D-3 tip function D-3 tip libraries giving us which instantiates our tool
tip element we're adding a class called D-3 tip.
The aftermath which will take care of styling and then we're saying the constants of our two tape and
the AGM element we're using a function head to separate email which is going to get past that piece
of data from the shape that we want to look at later on.
In Step 2 we are using the cool method on our visualization to let our Page know that we want to attach
a tool tip to our visualization area.
Finally we're adding to event listeners to ask veejays which is saying that the torture should be shown
when the mouse moved over the shape and the tool tip should be hidden.
When the mouse moves outside of the area of the shape tip show is actually relaying the piece of data
associated with the Eski G to the h t m l function from step 1.
Whenever the mouse over event is triggered
this is a good point to mention the on method in D-3 which is used for attaching events to the cheese.
The method takes two arguments an event type to listen for the function to run whenever that event is
fired.
The tooltip uses the mouse over and makes out events but there are a huge number of different events
that we can listen for the functions that we're using for a tortured tool to hide and tooltip those
show which are methods that the D-3 library gives is to effect the elements display we'll be introducing
a number of other event listeners in the next few lectures as we continue to make our visualization
more and more interactive.
The D-3 temp library also comes with some simple examples C Ss which will be using to give us some quick
and easy styles for taught it.
Now that we've seen the syntax for creating a tooltip in the three I'm going to walk through the example
of how we would go about adding a tortilla to a bubble chart.
As D-3 tape has a plugin library for D-3 it doesn't come included with the regular D-3 library.
She will normally need to download it from its repository and get her include included in your ingenius
folder.
As I mentioned I'll also be grabbing the examples C S S file from the same repository so that we don't
need to worry about making anything look pretty.
I've already gone ahead and added these files into my project folder and I included them here and in
my index to H.T. mail file.
Going back to a manger file here we add a tool tutor to our visualization for the first that we need
to initialize the tooltip by calling the D-3 test function.
Here's what this code will look like.
I'm giving it the class of D-3 test which matches the CSSA name for an AC SS file and I'm going to set
the mail with a function.
For now I'll just return the object that we're looking at and I'll come back to setting the HDMI out
later.
Next I'm going to use D-3 is called method on our visualization group to set the context for our Toltec.
Finally I'm adding in the two event listeners that we need to use the tools to work properly.
First there's the mouse over events where we need to show the tool tip by providing the tip top show
method as the function.
And secondly we need the mouse out-of-band which we use to fire the Tip-Top hide method.
I should note that we're attaching these events before we merge into selection with the update selection
because we only want to attach these event listeners once for every circle that we enter onto our.
Now when we go back to our browser we can see the tooltip appears when we hover over one of these circles.
However we still need to format the content of our tool tips age Jamail so we can actually see the contents
of this object.
I'm going to go back to when we first initialize the it and write out some HDMI code for us to display.
We're actually going to make a fairly long string hit output inside out towards it because we have so
many fields that we want to display to make our structure clearer and making a variable called text
and adding to it one line at a time.
I'm starting out with a country name here.
I want all of my variable names to appear older than the pieces of data.
So I'm surrounding each of them with a strong tag for other pieces of data.
I'm coloring them in red.
So they really stand out with this span tag and setting the text color with an inline C says when it
comes to actually including the data.
We're using some string concatenation here for the first row we can access the country name using the
key of the country from our data object.
We're also adding a brake tag here.
So every piece of data it will display on its own line.
Next we're doing the same thing for the continent.
The data point belongs to.
I just copied and pasted the same line for my country field replacing the word country with consonant.
Again I've done the same thing with life expectancy using the life XP field.
GDP per capita with the income field and population with the population field finally and returning
this long text variable which is what actual tape is going to display when we refresh the page.
Now it looks like a tooltip is doing what we want it to.
However these figures look a little messy as they are.
So we'll use some format functions to clean them up.
First off I want to capsulized the names of our continents so I use the same text transform trick that
we used for our legend to capitalize these names.
Next I'm going to add a D-3 format call for life expectancy data or life expectancy data is sometimes
given to one decimal point and sometimes given to two decimal points in our data.
To clean this up or make a specifier.
To format this figure as a floating point value to two decimal points from the D-3 documentation I can
figure out that we need to provide the precision before the type for a format and specify that we're
ultimately looking for the string of point to an I'll do something similar if the GDP per capita.
Except this time I'll use the specifier dollar column as the rope and the Dollar Sign here tells the
three that are using a currency.
The comma adds a thousand separator and the zero error gives as a fixed point number with no decimal
points.
Finally for population I'm going to use the specifier comma 0.
This should do the same thing as the last format function.
Except here with not formatting a number as a currency once you refresh the page and take another look
at tooltip again we can see that our data is showing up in a much nicer format than before.
One thing that's pretty annoying is that the circles are constantly moving so it's hard to get a clear
look at a certain country but will be introducing a fix for that in the next lecture.
After this lecture you should now be able to add your own tool tips to your visualizations using the
three step process of initializing metod it calling it in the context of your visualization and adding
its event handlers to us.
Geez you also got your first look at event listeners in this course when we added listeners for Mansingh
over the way from the SVGA circles in the next lecture we're going to be adding in 3 new interactive
features to a graph including a pause button so that users can take a look at the visualization in a
set and yet because we'll be listening to so many different events at once.
We'll also be introducing an event handlers to simplify our logic.