In this lecture we'll be adding three new interactive elements to our visualization which should all
improve by use as experience.
We'll be writing some lines of Jay queery to attach event listeners to these ailments and react to these
events to get the behavior that we're looking for.
To do this we'll need to take a step back and figure out exactly which actions each event should trigger.
As I mentioned in the last lecture one pretty annoying feature of our bubble chart right now is that
we can't pause the visualization to look at different countries in the same year to fix this will be
adding a pause button which allows users to stop or loop in a certain year.
It might also be helpful for our users to have a reset button which flicks the timer back to the 18:00
again.
This would mean that if someone's interested in looking at the world early on in the data then they
don't need to wait for a visualization to loop around again to replay the same period.
I will also be adding a constant filter to our visualization which will lead the use of filter out the
countries from just one continent which might make the graph less crowded and easier to understand.
Let's think about which events we need to listen to and consider what our event handlers should be doing
in response to get the behavior that we're looking for.
First of let's think about our butts for stopping and starting that visualization when a loop is running.
This button should be a pause button.
And once it gets clicked a loop should stop running and the button should become a play button.
When we press play this should restart our loop at the same point and the button should become a pause
button again.
To do this we'll need to think about both conditions the button could be in will have one response if
the button is a pause button and another response.
If the button is a play button for a reset button We'll also be listening to a click event this time
or event handler function should reset of visualization time the back to the start.
So the button started dating from the 18:00 again will also need to update a year label again to match
the year that we return to for our constant filter.
We'll be working with a select box to use it can choose a value from the event that we'll be listening
for will be the change event on the select box and again to add filter to our update function according
to the current value of our selection and I'll trigger an update visualization when the selection changes
which will update the chart at the current year in case the visualisations currently reports.
The visualization that we have at the moment has a problem.
We don't have the ability to stop and start our interval through decrease interval function as you might
recall from Section 5 will need to use javascript set interval method instead which allows us to pause
the loop using clear interval.
This will mean the pause button will use a clear interval method and play button when you use the set
interval method will need to store this interval as a global variable.
So the play button and the reset button will both have access to it.
Returning to our code I started off by adding three new components to index indexed HVM l file including
some bootstrap classes to give it some structure.
We'll start off with a play button when the page is first loaded so users can start the visualization
themselves.
For a select box the default selection has a value of all the values for each of the other options corresponds
to the consonant names from other data going back to our main js file here.
Or start by converting our D-3 interval function to javascript set interval function because I don't
want to start running as soon as visualization is loaded I'm going to put out interval code into a separate
function.
I'm going to call this function step and whenever it gets called it will add 1 to the value of the timer
resetting it to 0 if we're at the end of our data and update the visualization.
At the time I'm going to call this step function when the user presses play.
Next I'll write the code for a play button.
I'm grabbing hold of the button element here with Jay Querrey and I'm going to attach an event listener
using on method.
We're listening for a click of the button so Pasch click as the first argument here and I'll write out
the logic inside an anonymous function which will be our event handler.
We know that we'll have to write some separate logic for the case where the button is a play button
and this is a pause button but I'm just going to start off by implementing the button as a play button
once I click the button then all willing to do is start the interval loop running.
Here's the code that will use to do that all you are saying here is the loop should start executing
a step function repeatedly with the delay of 100 milliseconds.
Then with storing this interval in a variable called interval and I'll make this available throughout
my code by declaring it was a global function at the top of my file I also need to add the formatted
data variables like global so we can access this data from us.
That function which lies outside the data loading function or then makes sure that we're working with
this global in our data loading function rather than creating another variable with a local scope.
Once we flick back to our browser we can see that the button is doing what we are expecting it to.
So I'll move onto the next stage of making it work.
It's a pause button too.
Firstly I want the buttons text to say pause after we click it to do this.
I'll grab hold of the button element using j query on this which in this context represents the button
that we just clicked.
Next I'm going to set the buttons text to pause as a quick sanity check or refresh the page and test
this again.
And it looks like the button is behaving like we want it to.
Next I want to consider the case where we're pressing the button when it's meant to be a pause button
to do this.
I'm going to use an if else statement in the first case.
The buttons text says play them we want to run the code that we just wrote.
However if the text says pause then we want to run some different code.
Pauses.
Loop to study this case of.
I'm going to change the text of a button back to play when it gets pressed the way that we pause a set
interval loop is to use the clear interval function on the interval that we have running.
Can access the loop from the integral variable that we set earlier.
So the line that we end up with is clear interval of interval.
Now when we refresh the page we have a button that does the visualization when we press the play button
and then pauses the visualization.
When we press pause the next step is to add this reset button which is make a visualization jump back
to the 18:00 again our reset button should follow the same pattern that we just used for a play button.
Will you j where to get hold of it.
Using the ID reset button this time and again we're going to make an event handler for the Click event
Theresa.
Outside all that we need to do is to adjust our time variable.
Setting it to zero.
If we just leave it like this.
Then the visualization will continue to run if the loop is active and will stay paused if the loop isn't
running.
However if we try to hit our reset button while our visualization is paused then a chart won't update
until we press play again as a quick fix to this we're adding a quarter update with a data in its first
year.
Testing this out in our browser again we can see that the reset button is behaving as expected.
It's working here if the visualization is running.
And if we press pause and reset it then we can see the state of the world and the 18:00.
Finally for our constant filter I want to add a filter function at the start of the update function.
I'll start by grabbing the value of the continent select box using Jey query and use that value to filter
the data array.
If the select box has a value of all then I want every element in my array to pass the filter.
So it just returns true.
However if the select box has a value of something different a string that matches one of the consonant
names then I only want the filter to return the data points that belong to that consonant to do this
or return the expression where the consonant field of the object in the array is equal to the name of
the constant that was selected.
This expression will evaluate to true.
If we're looking at a country that matches the consonant which will mean that the filter keeps it in
an array and they'll return false if the country has a consonant with any other name which will excluded
from the array.
Looking back at the browser now we can see that our filter is already working as expected because our
filter is placed inside update function and the update function is running on every step of timer.
The visualization is constantly checking to see whether our selection has changed.
However just like with our reset button if we try to make a change when our visualization is paused
we won't see the effect until we press play again.
To fix this we just need to update our visualization at the current time whenever the selection changes
or grab hold of the select box.
With Jake we're again using the ID tag constant select and this time will listen on the Change event
instead of the Click event.
Once we have that over our event handler need to do is to update our visualization.
At the current time which we can access with the time variable now that we finished off our constant
filter we now have the ability to selectively look at just one constant at a time which makes it easier
to separate all the circles on the screen.
We added a lot of new functionality in this lecture which will make a visualization a lot more useful
to users.
At this point you should feel comfortable with the practice of grabbing elements.
Jake Querrey attaching events to them and figuring out what our event handler should do.
In the next lecture I'll be taking things one step further by adding a Querrey UI slider which will
allow users to pinpoint the gear that they want to look at.