At this point although users can pause a visualization on this year it can be annoying to have to wait
for a whole year to roll around to view the world at a certain point in time.
By the end of this lecture we'll introduce a slider where users can pick up the exact year they want
to look at.
I've decided to use the j where you find library from slider in this project.
This library has a plugin library that works on top of Jey query and it allows you to add a few different
features on a separate page.
We didn't need to use j where you slide this project and we can just easily abused that bootstraps it
that this slider also gives you the option to select a range of two different values instead of just
one.
This will come in handy for a third class project.
So I will introduce it to you in this lecture.
Here's what the syntax looks like to create a slide.
After we select an element with J Querrey we can add a slide to it by running the slide method which
initializes the slide on the page.
We can pass in a variety of different options.
Here is the object which gives the slide as some initial setting.
Here with setting the max option is hundred men option 0 meaning that slider will be arranged between
zero and 100.
The step option hand means the slide it goes up into the corner and so one the range option determines
whether or not we want the slider to be a range slider.
If it's set to true then I slide it will have two pointers which can be dragged to set two different
values.
The value option sets the initial value that the slider is set to.
If we were using a range like that here and would want to use the values option instead which would
take an array of two different numbers.
Finally we can add event listeners to us light up by setting a value for the different slider events
that we had to choose from the start of and fire.
When the slide first begins that new the stop event fires when the slider is released and the slide
event fires.
Every time slight changes.
We could also use the change event which would find it when the slide moves to something different.
We can use a function head to dictate what should happen when the event is fired.
These two arguments that the function takes is access the event that find that function as well as the
State of the slider through this UI variable we can access the current value of the slider which will
be used to update of visualization.
Now that we've seen how the syntax for us slide should look.
I'm going to add one to our bubble chart.
I started off by adding a couple of lines to a DML file which will give us some where to put the slider
on the screen I've also added a label which will display the year which should match the Year at the
bottom of the screen.
I've also added Jay Querrey UI library here which I downloaded into my drafts folder.
Now in our main file I'm going to initialize the slider on a date slider div using Jake where query
wise slide a method.
I know that our data ranges between 8500 in 2014 so use these values to set the min and max from the
slider I want our users to be able to select any year in the dataset.
So we'll set the step to one and we want to update our visualization whenever the slider moves.
So we'll set a handler on the slide event in the event handler function here.
Although we want to do is to change the value of a timer to match the data we use and move the slider
to we can get a hold of the year that the user selected using the value method this variable and we
can minus 8900 from it translate it to the index of our data array.
For example if we said eighteen hundred here then we'll set the time to zero which will show the data
from the first year in our dataset will also run update function at this new time of value in case we
want to move the slider when the visualization is paused.
We also want to update the slider label whenever the visualization updates.
So we'll just add in a quick line at the end of the function so that the label always gets the same
value as the label at the bottom of the chart.
Finally as the visualization updates we want the position of the slider to gradually slide to the right.
So a Adeline at the bottom of the function to do this recall that we can change the value of the slider
using the value method like this.
And again we're just passing in the same time variable the same as label after we've added in these
changes.
We can see that we can select any data we want manually and we can see that this behavior works whether
or not the visualisation is running at the end of this lecture.
We've once again improved our user interface allowing users to look at the world in any of the data
set.
You should now be able to add a J query slider to your own projects which you'll get the chance to do
in project 3 in the next lecture.
I'll be teaching you how to build a line charge in D3.