By now you should have a good feel for the general scaffolding which is involved for writing a java
script file with D-3.
And most of the time in DS3 you won't be making a new visualization from scratch but instead you'll
be adapting existing code that somebody else has written already in this lecture.
I'll be introducing you to line graphs and D-3 by walking you through an example the found on line.
This will be the approach that I'll be using in Section 7 8 and 9 to rapidly integer to rapidly introduce
you to a broad range of visualizations that D-3 lets you create.
I'll explain anything new that comes up in the example code and I'll be walking you through what the
code is doing.
In this lecture I'll be introducing you to the D-3 line function which will be the first path generator
that you'll be using in this course.
For your third project I'm adapting this example code from somebody in the D-3 community called Alan
Dunning.
This is a Web site that we'll be using repeatedly in the next two sections to source our example code.
I've chosen this visualization process to start with because it implements a nice tool tip for a line
graph.
I've made a few tweaks to this code to fit the coding style that we've been working with and I'm giving
you this code to start off with a project 3 I'm going to walk through this code line by line so they
can see what everything is doing.
At the top of our file we have the usual margin setter that we've seen in previous lectures where attaching
an SPG canvas to an empty div tag on a page.
And then we're appending a group onto that to conform with the magic convention we are using a parse
function which is just using this directive here to interpret four digit streams it's years.
We're also declaring this function bisect date which we'll be using for a tooltip.
What this function does is to return the index that a date would fit into a array.
If it was added in order here we're setting the range for x and y scales we're defining two Access generators
which we'll call them we have some domains available for us scales.
In this example there's a simple formatting function for a y axis ticks which we're using to show the
data in thousands.
Next we're adding two groups which will contain axes we'll call the generators on these groups later
run we're adding a text SVGA to a Y axis here.
So that label will sit on the y axis where we're defining a path generator for creating a line chart
which I'll talk about more later on.
We load in the data from our data set as usual using D-3.
Jason and we are using a four inch loop to coerce our data values that we can work with.
Here we have a past time function being called.
Not yet.
Give us a javascript Date object and here we are converting a string of a number to an integer using
a plus sign.
Now that we have a data loaded properly we can set the domains for us Gayles for our X domain.
This extend function is returning the minimum and maximum dates in our data for the Y domain for the
minimum with dividing our lowest population value by 1 point 0 0 5 to give as a slight buffer.
And similarly for the maximum with timesink the largest population value by 1.00.
5 to give us some space at the top.
For your line chart I want the minimum of your wide domain to be zero because a broken Y-axis is generally
frowned upon in data visualization because it exaggerates the impact of minor changes in values.
Now that our scales have a domain we're calling on Access generators in the context of our access groups
in terms of attaching our actual line to grab this block of code.
Here is where all the magic is happening.
Notice that for a line chart because we're only appending one path SPG we don't need to worry about
using that D-3 update pattern all that will be doing is changing this D attribute whenever a line needs
to a date.
We won't need to worry about using Enter Exit because there should always be just one line on the page
at all times.
Let's take a closer look at what this block of code is doing.
Remember way back in Section 2 when I mentioned the final type of SPG called the path this is way it
looked like this D attribute contains a complex set of symbols that defines how a path gets grown by
our browser.
We don't need to know how to write these attributes by ourselves because D-3 comes packed with path
generators that we can use to create them.
Namely in this instance we can use D-3 line function.
Looking back at our code from earlier these are the sections that we're using to draw a line.
The top section here is defining a line generator a line generator expects to be given an array of data
and for each element in that array we're telling a line generator how to interpret the data point is
X and Y coordinate feeding the right now using scales to get pixels
in the bottom section with calling a line generator with an array of data each data point in this array
is an object with both the Year and de-value field which a line function will interpret as a set of
coordinates calling this line function with an array of data spits out a complicated string of characters
which we're plugging in as that should be for the path that we're appending.
The end result is that our browser will draw this path on that screen to connect between these different
coordinates.
Here's what the result looks like in the wage mail.
This string is just a fancy combination of symbols the line generator created to express the path between
each of the points of a line.
Finally we have some code at the bottom of our file here to add a different kind of tooltip to grab
this tool.
It consists of a circle which surrounds the point but looking at two dotted lines that we can follow
to each axis and a text.
SVGA the display is the y value.
First we're appending a group which we can use to hide or shared the whole tilted.
Next we're adding a vertical line to connect to our x axis and a horizontal line to connect to the y
axis.
We're adding a circle here.
And then we're adding our text as Fiji.
Finally we're adding an invisible rectangle as an overlay for our visualization which we'll be attaching
our events to when our mouse moves inside the oberl area.
We're making the tooltip visible by setting the display of our group to know.
And then when our mouse moves outside the oberl we're hiding the tooltip by setting its display to
non finally this mouse move function here is doing all the heavy lifting to update each part of our
tooltip.
When a mouse moves around if you remember from a lecture on scale's we using the invert method on a
scale here to find the time value that matches the coordinate position of the mouse.
The bisect date function is returning the index in our data array where this time value would belong
if it was its own data point.
So this line here is comparing the date that America is looking at to the closest to time values in
our array and returning the data point that it's closest to.
Next we're shifting the whole tooltip so that it's centered around the point that we're looking at.
Then we're updating the text of our tooltip with the y value that we're looking at.
Here we're adjusting the second point of our x axis line so that it moves to the new Y value.
And finally we're doing the same with Y-axis line.
All of this tooltip code is pretty complicated and it's not at all obvious what this smooth function
is doing.
The good news is that realistically you don't really need to know what this code is doing to use it
in your files as long as you're getting the behavior that you're looking for from a piece of community
code then you only really need to understand which pieces you need to alter to fit your own visualization.
This lecture was your first crash course through some example code helping you to understand where a
line graph looks like and D 3 I'll be following this format in Section 7 8 and 9 to give you a good
breadth of knowledge into D-3 and to gauge the process of understanding and adapting visualizations
by yourself.
You'll need to make a few more edits to this code and project 3 so that fits with your data and to make
it interactive in the next lecture.
I'll be helping to get acquainted with the project template files I'm giving you and I'll be explaining
what you'll be building.