In this lecture I'll be introducing you to a third class project where you'll be making a line chart
display historical cryptic parts of prices for different coins.
I'm going to take you through the template files that I'll be giving you know show you what you should
end up with the End of Project.
You have some friends who are thinking about getting into cryptocurrency trading looking for any excuse
to show off your dazzling new data visualization skills.
You decide to help them out by creating a visualization to show them how different coins have changed
price over time.
You want them to flick between the five biggest coins in the market in terms of market capitalization
you find some historical dates or a line they've already converted it into a useful folder for each
coin you have data for every day that's been trading showing you its price in dollars.
The trading volume of the past day and its current total market cap.
I want you to make a line graph that can show any of these metrics for any of these coins.
The graph should also let the user narrow down on a specific date range with the graph automatically
adjusting so that it takes up the whole screen.
Here's where your project should look like once you're finished I can look at stats for any of the different
coins with the drop down on the left and I can set the y axis to the price in dollars.
Total market capitalization or 24 hour trading volume using the dropdown on the right.
I can also choose to look at a specific date range using this Jake Query.
I slide it on the left.
Notice that this time we're using a range slider so that we can choose the interval between two different
dates both the line and the access transitions smoothly.
Whenever the graph gets updated Here's the code I'll be giving you to start off with for this project.
As usual I've taken care of the basic set up for your index to H.T. M-L file including all the libraries
that you might need to use.
I've also written in a div to put your slide into with a date label on top of it and I've given you
two select boxes one to select the coin that the visualization should show.
And the other to select the variable on the y axis.
I've also made some changes to the C S file that comes with the project.
So just changing the color of the garish purple line that came with the original code.
In your data folder you'll find one file that came with your example in this example that Jason File
and the coins data that you'll be using in the Coinstar js file.
Since you've already had the experience of writing everything from scratch in your previous two projects
I'm starting you off with the community written line graph code that I showed you in the last lecture.
In this project your main goals should be to adapt this starting code changing the source of data and
figuring out how it should update when our selections change.
This will mirror the kind of work that you'll be doing in real world D-3 development as it is extremely
rare that you'll ever need to write this kind of code from scratch.