Well then at the end of this section you've built something pretty substantial.
You've made a production quality line graph which updates seamlessly when they use that place around
it.
You can now configure a host of different elements to trigger updates on a graph.
Now you've had experience of doing this with some common examples.
You should hopefully be confident of wiring any kind of interactive elements up to a visualization like
this.
The process gets a little trickier when we have to worry about multiple visualizations on the page updating
at once in Section 10.
Once we separate our code into different files and to start thinking about visualizations as javascript
objects will start to introduce some more robust event handlers which will be triggered by multiple
events.
In this section you also had your first taste of things to come where I took you on a crash course of
line graphs and D-3 although we don't have time to go through every visualization that we can imagine
over the course of the next three sections I'll be giving you the tools for finding pre-written cared
for what you want to build your self and how to understand how this code works.