Now they know how to make some simple visualizations in D3.
I want you to start to think about how you might apply this knowledge in your own field of work.
Unlike most of the projects in this class your own projects will require you to create your own new
and exciting ways to express the data that you're working with.
Although the D-3 library really allows you to build anything that you can imagine.
There are some best practices that you should be aware of to make it good fishless station in this section
I'll take you through the process of sketching out your ideas before launching into coding something
I'll help you to understand the different types of data and how to visualize them and I'll introduce
you to the bootstrap grid system for making responsive pages.
By the end of this section you'd have the knowledge to constructively critique existing data visualizations
and you should have the confidence to be able to challenge other stakeholders who have an interest in
influencing the design of your projects.