In this lecture I'm going to be talking about some best practices.
Think about before you start to design any visualization.
We'll be talking about tough to design principles which emphasize making clear and easy to read visualizations
and we'll be giving some examples of visualizations that do this well and others that do this badly.
A key aim for data visualization needs to be to make the data as easy to interpret as possible.
You want your visualizations to be credible because the last thing that you want as a designer is to
have your entire project discredited because the data was displayed misleadingly visualizations should
also achieve the aim of drawing attention to the data rather than anything decorative that surrounds
it.
This approach is embodied by the work of Ed Wood who is an American statistician the pioneer in the
field of data visualization tough to emphasize four main principles that we should follow to craft a
clear and readable data visualizations all of which focus on staying honest to the data eliminating
distracting elements in terms of graphical integrity data can easily be skewed by its presentation.
Here we have a famous example in Fox News where they are using a distorted Y-axis to exaggerate the
difference between 35 and 40 percent.
The graph on the right conveys the data more truthfully and the effect isn't quite as shocking.
It's generally considered to be bad practice not to start your waxes from zero.
For this reason it gives an instant shock impact but it throws the whole argument into question when
it's viewed in a critical light.
Tough to define the life factor as the size of an effect shown in the graphic divided by the size of
the effect as it's measured in the actual data.
For a church with high graphical integrity this figure should be as close to one as possible and there
shouldn't be any inherent bias that skews perception a good example is shown here from a keynote speech
from Steve Jobs back in 2002 8.
The tilting Fredy pie chart makes the section at the bottom representing Apple's market share seem WAY
bigger than it really is
turf.
Coined the term chart junk to mean any elements on the screen that distract the viewer from the data
whilst adding no extra information.
We have another good example from Fox News here to illustrate a point.
In general anything Fredy background graphics or any of that unnecessary framing elements would be considered
as chaat junk according to the two if to uses the term data in Gratiot to measure the amount of charging
the visualization has here we have two expressions of the same data each which have different data to
anguishes top that would argue that the chart on the right here is far clearer as it gets the point
across more successfully than the chart on the left.
After this lecture you should feel primed to weigh different visualizations according to some common
rules for design.
This is an important skill to develop as a data visualization engineer.
You should be able to justify your design decisions that you make to people who we are working with
and should have the vocabulary to constructively critique visualizations that can be proved.
However it's important to note that these are just guidelines.
Design is always a highly subjective matter.
In the next lecture I'll be making a counterpoint that these principles aren't always essential to make
visualization.