Although Tufters principles have been influential to many data visualization engineers there's still
a lot of debate about whether it's actually better to eliminate elements that they would consider it
as challenging.
In this lecture I'll be taking a closer look at this argument and providing some balance to his opinions
on data visualization design.
When we think about what visualizations are used for our most important goal might not always be just
to communicate data in the most efficient way.
Sometimes the most memorable visualizations are the ones that really grab the attention of the reader
and make them take a closer look.
Especially when the visualization wants to tell a compelling story.
This could be especially important as the goal could be to the reader.
The best way to do this might not be with a completely dull line or a bar chart that might use aesthetically
pleasing supportive elements compay what the data is showing.
This could call for a new and imaginative types of visualizations that people have never seen before.
All of these factors aren't caught by his own estimation of what makes a well-designed visualization.
For example here we have a visualization of countries that spend the most on military spending every
year.
There are certainly a few things wrong with this graph.
The graph is really a histogram rather than a bar chart which is generally a poor design decision to
make as our minds are bad at telling between different area sizes.
However this visualization looks far more interesting than if it was displayed as a minimalist but chose
another famous example here shows a creative adaptation to a line graph showing diamond prices.
Over time the graph has a terrible data to ink ratio and it's not even totally clear where the individual
data points are but how much less interesting with this specialization have been it being simpler.
Finally here we have a visualization about campaign spending in the US.
The visualization on the left screams Chad junk and might even have a bit of a life factor due to the
slanting x axis.
But would it be better or worse at drawing attention to the issue than the graph on the right.
All of these charts so far a static infographics and not the sort of thing that you'd be able to create
with D-3.
But there is still some visualizations that give of a unique kind of interactivity which you can replicate
with D-3 For example this is a node linked diagram which is a really popular and interactive visualization
D-3 makes it really easy to create.
I'll be showing you how to build these in Section 8.
The bounce some of these circles could be seen as pretty distracting.
But what makes this type of visualization appealing is precisely the kind of quirky interactivity that
it offers.
It encourages further exploration of the data and it creates a novelty that will intrigue the user to
find out more about it.
With these examples in mind it's good to know that took these principles aren't always hard and fast
rules for data visualizations.
Design is a highly subjective field but you should still use your intuition to judge that element should
add to a visualization or whether it takes something at what in the next lecture I want you to critique
some visualizations that get to show you using what you know about the best practices for design.