Now do we have an idea of what a good data visualization should look like.
We can start to think about the different tools that we can use to display data in this lecture.
We'll be looking at the various options that we have open to visualize data we'll consider color scheme
selection and we'll look at the different data types that exist and how to deal with them.
How do we think about the options that we have available for displaying data.
Jack betime propose a visual design space for us to consider the different design choices that we can
make for visualizations where we can choose between physician size gray value texture color orientation
and shape to convey different data on a page.
We can see examples of how these channels can be used to produce graphically differentiated images.
It turns out the we humans are better at judging between some of these channels than others.
Let me take you through an example hit.
I'm going to flesh some shapes on the screen and I want you to come up with a quick gut reaction answer
to the different questions that I'm going to ask.
You don't need to pause the video and I'll tell you the answers after about five seconds.
First up how much longer is Line B in line a
line B is four times longer.
That wasn't too difficult right.
How much steeper is lying a than Line B.
The answer is also four times that one was a little trickier.
Right.
How much larger is circle B in circle.
A
circle B is five times larger.
It's particularly challenging for our brains to pick apart the difference between areas.
How much darker circle be than circle a
circle B is two times darker a little bit easier.
Finally how much greater is the value of circle B and the value of Circle K using this legend underneath
circle B actually has a value of four times greater than Circle A because Circle A has a value of two
and circle B has a value of eight.
This is a really tough one for us to figure out because we have a color scheme that diverges between
two completely different colors.
We have to put in a lot more mental effort to figure this out than if we were just looking at Douglas.
So from these examples we can see that makes a big difference.
Which type of visual channel we use to display our data.
Some of these data types will be easier for the reader to interpret that others and others will be far
more difficult.
Every piece of data falls into one of three categories qualitative ordinal categorical quantitative
data involves numbers of different sizes that just somebodies height weight IQ score or income categorical
data places distinct categories on each data point allowing us to compare between factors that we're
interested in ordinal data.
It's similar to categorical data except that these categories can be ordered by size.
So for example big medium and small are all distinct categories but they can be boarded so we classed
them as ordinal as opposed to categorical.
Here we have a simple cheat sheet to guide you in selecting the right channels to use the whatever data
you are using.
Typically we're best at judging position and length for quantitative data but worth the judging slope
angles and intensity for ordinal data.
It's best to stick to area bigger shapes stick out smaller shapes and we can find patterns in between.
For categorical data we should only ever break it down by shape or color as this emphasizes the fact
that each category is distinctly different.
In terms of selecting the right colors to using your visualizations you should stick to a fairly small
number of colors for categories.
If you're using more than 8 different colors then these colors will start to overlap and it will start
to get hard to pick them apart for quantitative data.
It's best not to use diverging color scheme such as going from red to white to green because then you
need to define a point as the white value.
And it's not as easy to tell points apart that are centered around that point.
Also you might want to consider selecting a color scheme that's easy to read for colourblind uses as
is a pretty simple fix and it should mean that about 1 in 20 users will now be able to make use of your
visualization a really simple tool that's free to use on line for selecting color schemes.
Killebrew which offers a variety of nice color schemes depending on the number of data points that you
have.
You can select for different types of data and you can also see a range of color blind friendly color
schemes for your visualization.
After this lecture you should understand the difference between the different Batal channels that you
can use visualisation and you should be aware of which channels best express the data you're working
with in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to the process of sketching where I'll be showing you some tips to get your
ideas expressed to something concrete on paper.