Now now you know a bit more about the design tools that you have at your disposal it's time to start
thinking about how he would apply them to your own projects.
Sketches are one of the most important parts of a designer's toolkit.
In this lecture I'm going to be teaching you huge create quick and simple drawings that you can use
to brainstorm some of the best ways to display data.
Sketching is a really important part of any design process as it lets you test out how things should
look before you leap into trying to build something with code.
As you start to sketch out different ideas you can get a feel for the type of data that you're working
with and you can test out some different options against each other.
Sketches are also really important to communicate your design ideas to anyone else that has a stake
in your projects.
It's a whole lot easier to discuss different options once they've been written out as a drawing.
Here are three quick rules.
I want you to follow whenever you make a sketch of a visualization you don't want to get too attached
to any one I did you come up with.
So you should make all of your sketches at disposable as possible.
There's something liberating about the idea that you can just scrunch up a sketch if you don't like
the way it's going and just throw it in the trash for that reason.
I recommend that you write your sketches on paper next.
All of your sketches should be as big and bold as possible.
It can be a problem if sketches are too small so that you can't see everything clearly.
So make sure that your sketches take up at least a half a side of a full paper.
Finally don't try to make your sketches a detailed representation of how your visualization should look.
The idea with sketches is that you're just trying to get your general point across.
They don't need to be drawn with a ruler.
You don't need to worry about making things to scale and you should only have enough detail so you can
convey the general idea.
You never want to be spending more than five minutes to create your first sketch of a visualization.
I'll take you through some examples of how the sketching process might look as an example.
Let's say that I want to visualize something about population and GDP per capita is of the different
continents in the world.
Here's all that I'm using to make my example sketches my sketchbook is fairly small.
So make sure that each of my sketches take up an entire page space an obvious choice to display this
data would be a world map by simply drawing out the constants with displaying positional data that shows
where each of these items are located.
We're also saying something about the size of each of the consonants and we can add data or on top of
this by changing the intensity of the colors to encode some continuous data so to quickly do that.
I'm going to add in some dots on each of these consonants which quickly articulate this.
So here we could say that the darkness of the color that we're using for these continents represents
their GDP per capita.
This is called a core uplift map which I'll show you had to make in Section 8.
You might notice this sketch isn't a particularly accurate representation of the consonants the sizes
and shapes are way off from what you'd expect.
But that's not the point.
The point is to make something quick and easy which expresses your basic idea.
For another example I've sketched out a sunbursts plot which is kind of like a pie chart except that
it allows for further breakdown of the data from was originally displayed.
We'll be building these in section 9 each of these rings represent 100 percent of the world's population.
Breaking it down into different regional categories as we move further out the size of each of these
arcs is encoding that population label just a few of these auks to let the reader know what this visualization
is talking about.
Again I'll add in some marks to show the GDP per capita of each of these UCS.
This time using crosses instead of dots to show how some dogs should be darker than others.
You'll notice that this graph isn't a tool to scale as it's being drawn terribly.
Again the point is just to communicate how the data is going to be displayed and come up with something
quick and easy to communicate.
All right does
finally image do more or less the same thing with the treatment instead of a sunbath a tree map basically
conveys the same information except that it comes in a rectangular shape instead of working with angles
the size of the rectangle should relate to each of these regions populations.
I boxed off the different consonants first and then I filled some of these in with a few example countries.
The scale is clearly way off since the U.S. is almost the same size as China.
But that's not the point.
You also see that I didn't bother adding labels for every country or even every continent because that
would have taken more time.
Again I'm linking the color intensity of each of these boxes to the GDP per capita.
I've also added in a legend here which explicitly tells us what the graph is saying.
After this lecture you should be prepared to start making sketches of your own to figure out how to
show your data.
I've gone through some basic rules that you should try to follow and show you how this process should
look.
Now that I've gone through a few different sketches to give you a general idea I want you to sketch
out some designs of your own.
I'll be giving you a Denno dataset to think about and you should use the design principles that you
learned in this lecture to come up with some ideas.
There really are lots of different ways to visualize data like this and I want to encourage you to really
think outside the box and see what fits best with this data.