If you've had any experience with web development before that you should already be familiar with how
the bootstrap grid system works will be using bootstrap thread.
This cost Diala web pages into of different elements on the page you eventually already seen bootstrap
in action for the first project.
Since I designed the index page with a simple bootstrap design by adding certain bootstrap classes to
elements we can gradually split this page into various sections.
We can define how wide these sections should be on different screen sizes too which means that our site
will look good anywhere.
Salesian designing visualizations especially for visualisations surrounded by other elements you should
start to mentally box things up.
You would with the bootstrap grid.
You immediately start to think about how these elements should fold down at the screen size changes
and I would recommend using bootstrap to do this in future projects.
I'm going to explain the setup the bootstrap version 3 which we're using in this class.
Firstly we need to surround everything that uses the grid with a div with a class container.
This gives up page padding and it lets us define different roads inside it.
We can then add a div with a class of RO which we can add further dates with column classes inside of
hey you can see what bootstrap is doing bootstrap splits.
Each of the roads into pieces of 12 equal parts and you can define columns by how many parts these take
up in the top row here.
The divs have a class of code.
I'm the one which means they have a column with the 1 12 of them can fit into one row in the second
row.
We have one column with 8 and 1 with 4 in the third row we have three columns of four.
And in the last row we have two columns of with six.
If the total of all of these columns is larger than 12 then bootstrap will wrap the rest of the room
and derate new growth.
So in this example adding a column plan for next to a column with 9 would mean that the row would need
13 parts for everything to fit so the rest of our row gets put.
Nice it.
We can also combine multiple bootstrap classes to make the appearance of divs different for different
size Greenes we can use a class prefix call access followed by a number for how screen should be shown
for phones we can use the prefix s m for tablets we can use and the for normal sized laptops and we
can use LG for large desktops.
This will be really useful when you create visualizations of your own.
You want to make sure that your visualizations will look good on whichever screen someone is viewing
it from and you want to make sure that they won't break for phones or tablet.
Here's a look at using these different classes in action.
We've given the top rows columns different classes the and desktops.
If you're viewing this visualization a phone then the column on the left will take up the whole with
the screen with the column with 12 that resolution and the second column will wrap underneath with it
with half the screen.
However if it's viewed on the desktop then everything will fit onto the first row with the first column
taking up two thirds of the width and the second column filling in the rest.
We can also use offsets to provide layers of padding on either side of color.
Adding a class would be offset for the column size will define the number of columns that the cell should
have the left of it.
So here the column in the second row has a size of 3 and an offset 3.
So you can imagine three invisible spaces taken up to the left of it which comes from the upset here.
After all that you should hopefully be better able to navigate the template files giving you understand
why certain dates have been given certain classes.
You should also be starting to think about how new patzers science fits in with the bootstrap system.
I mean starting to split up your page in two different boxes in mind.