Over the course of this section you learn about some basic rules of thumb that should help you going
forward to design and build better visualizations.
I'll keep coming back to some of the lessons that you learned in this section throughout the rest of
the course.
In the next section we'll be improving on the bar chart that you made the Paullus coffee chain in Section
street.
Adding in some updating elements.
This is where things get really interesting with D-3 as we can start to create some unique visualizations
that we can't really express in any other form.
I'll also be explaining the D-3 update pattern which should hopefully clear things up with confusing
code that we saw.
Now the data join in section 2.