At the end of section three we end up with a static bar chart to show how poor Pullens coffee chain
has been doing in its first six months.
We want to take that visualization and add some features onto it to make it more useful.
One of the benefits of using these three is that it gives us the ability to add beautiful transitions
to our charts allowing us to switch up the data that we're looking at in this section.
I'll be teaching you how to use the D-3 update pattern and you'll get to see what D-3 is doing behind
the scenes.
Using the files from a first class project will add the function that keeps updating the chart between
different sets of data.
Once we've turned towards botcher into a much slicker looking page for investors will then be able to
see how we can easily update this bocher into a scatterplot.
For us second class project by the end of this section you should feel comfortable with how the D-3
update pattern is working as you should know how to make a speed change react to a changing set of data.
This will give you a solid understanding of how the three works will make it a lot easier to design
and develop your own custom data visualisations from scratch.
You'll also have created a clone of a famous visualization from gapped mind which shows a bubble chart
displaying as different nations have evolved over time.
For this project you're actually creating something that looks really impressive as we start to unlock
the real power of these three.