If we want to add in some interactivity to our visualization class section we'll need to have some way
of refreshing the page to change something with chalk or react to specifically in this section will
be switching our dataset between two different data sources and having a bunch of data in this lecture
or running through the syntax between decrease interval function as well as the closely related set
interval function.
Jay Querrey at the end of this lecture will have a loop running on a page that simply was a text console.
An easy way for us to replicate and update and D-3 is for us to use an interval.
We basically want to run some code repeatedly every few seconds changing the data that we're looking
at.
D-3 provides its own integral function for doing this which takes two arguments a function to run continuously
and the delay in milliseconds.
The code inside this callback will run every five hundred milliseconds starting as soon as the browser
sees this code.
Let's take a look at how we would add an interval like this to our code.
To start off I'm just going to write out the D-3 integral code at the end of our data loading function.
For now just to make sure that our loop is working I'm just going to make a console log for every time
the loop runs.
The second the argument of 1000 here means the program is going to wait 1000 milliseconds a one second
between.
Every time it runs let's refresh the page and take a look at the console as expected.
We can see that our callback function is outputting the same Hello World to the console every second
in this lecture.
You learn the syntax to a really simple but powerful function in day which is going to help us to demonstrate
a lot of concepts in this section.
Next lecture I'll be adding in an update function which will be calling in this interval to continually
update the state of our visualization.