In this lecture I'll be taking you through the process of how we move from a static visualization where
all the code is only running once to a dynamic visualization where a portion of our code is constantly
executing in an interval function.
To do this I'll be making an update function which is going to be called Inside the interval Colback
that I wrote in The Last Lecture.
This is going to require us to think about exactly which parts of our code should run.
Every time our data changes and which parts of our code should just run once we can to write down an
update function which we use at the callback function from A identical loop.
This will mean that everything outside of update function will run just once when our visualization
is loaded and everything inside the update function will be run repeatedly.
Let's think about which elements need to update to get the effect that we're looking for.
Will need to change all scales and axes so that they update based on the data that we're looking at.
This means that if the chart changes to show more data points or if the maximum y value changes and
a visualization will scale accordingly.
We'll also need to update the label on a y axis to show the variable that we're looking at.
And finally we want to change the size and position of rectangles according to the new data.
We'll tackle the first two components here before we go on to update the rectangles in our next lecture.
I'm going to write up the function here at the end of mange s file.
This function will take a data argument which lets us pass in the data array that we loaded in earlier.
I'm going to call this function from within an interval loop so it fires once every second.
Let's start by moving all this code.
Adding scales axes and rectangles into update function.
For now I'm going to come in.
These rectangles because we'll be updating those in the next section.
Let's think about what actually needs to update.
The only thing that should change with scales is that the main cause is the only part that relies on
data.
I'm going to move my scales code to the top of a file but I'll keep the code that sets that domains
inside update function
with find to set up scales like this.
As long as we're only actually using them after the domain has been set
once we refresh the page we can see that we have a problem.
Each time the visualization updates we're adding new axes on top of our visualization.
The problem is that we're appending a separate group to our visualization every time the loop runs and
we're adding a new access onto each of these newsgroups.
We can fix this by appending all access groups just once at the top of the file and then by calling
access generators on them in update function.
I'll stall these groups in variables so that we can access them.
I'll call this one X X group and this one Y-axis group.
Next we're going to move these call methods which run Access generators into our update function
after we make these fixes the calls to access generators updating the current axes rather than adding
a new one every time.
We can also see that there's a delay here where we have no axes on the page.
This is because the first line of loop has to wait for the delay to start.
Although we need to do is add in another call to update function after interval.
Now US scale should be updated and axes should be refreshing.
Every time the loop runs at this point you should understand exactly why our scales and axes need to
be refreshed in this way.
You should also have a feel for deciding which parts of the code should be updating.
And we now have a visualization that's one step closer to something that updates forth to magic the
next lecture will be finishing off this process by updating the size and position of our rectangles
too.
This process will be a little less intuitive because we'll finally be learning about the D-3 update
at which reveals a lot about what d3 is doing behind the scenes.