In this lecture will be editing the size and position of rectangles within an update function to do
this we'll need to learn about the D-3 update pattern which is one of the most challenging parts of
the three.
It's hard to get your head around what exactly is happening.
I heard in the confusion that this causes can be frustrating if you can't get the data to update later
on you'll be using the D-3 update pattern in pretty much every visualization that you want to make.
So it's really important that you can get a good feel for what's going on.
Don't worry if the content of this lecture seems too complicated right now it'll become clear how the
update pattern works.
Once you've used a few times to understand how updates work in D-3 you should start by looking at our
data join the first section to recall that back then we just took it on faith that we're giving this
method called into the supply of all the elements that was supposed to screen what's actually happening
here is that when we call decrease select all passing in and read data the results gives us some handy
elements with some virtual selected built in.
Let's take a look at a repped variable that we defined earlier or start by taking a look at just the
variable after we make a data join.
We can see here the D-3 is attached three fields and to exit in groups.
And represents all of the elements in a data array that don't exist on the page.
These are the shapes that need to be entered onto the screen.
X it represents all the elements that are on the page that don't exist in the data array.
These are the elements that we need to remove from the screen.
And groups just representing all the elements that currently exist on the screen as we're logging out
wrecks before anything has been appended to the screen.
We can see that only enter has any elements in it.
This makes sense because we have seven items in our data array that don't exist on the screen.
If we then log our next variable after entering append function and work that magic will actually see
the enter field is empty but our groups field contains everything these rectangles in the array here
associate the bars and graphs.
Indeed we all want to use the same update pattern whenever our data changes.
Here's an example of how it might look with some Texas veejays first with the rolling of data join this
means that we are using Select all to grab hold of the SVGA that we care about and we're matching that
selection with an array of data.
This data array will be something different every time.
Visualization dates in this example we're expecting the data variable to be an array of strings.
Next we can get rid of all the elements that should be removed from the page.
Recall that exit method about D-3 selection returns all the elements that are on the page that don't
correspond to something in our data.
We can use the Remove method on the selection to delete these elements from the screen at that point
we can start thinking about the elements that are already on the screen but we need to update the regular
selection of a text variable here.
Essentially it turns everything into groups field but we just deleted all the text elements that needs
to be removed so we can think of changing these values is affecting all the elements that should be
updated.
Herem changing all the updating text SVGA is to have a color of red but it's more common to update the
position or size of the messages here.
Finally we'll add in all the elements in a new array of data but don't yet exist on the screen.
We're getting all the elements that need to be entered into Selecta.
We're using the append method to physically and these shapes to the screen.
And we can set a range of different attributes that should only apply to these newly added elements.
Note that updating elements should still have the same attributes for everything.
Other than that Phil that was said when they were first entered into data
with this in mind let's take another look at what we've been doing so far.
Select all here is returning a selection that still has no rectangles on the screen.
But since we've passed in an array of data we also had access to our virtual selectors.
We're using the virtual selector enter here to get all the egg the rectangles that exist data on the
screen and we're adding those with the pen method.
Let's write out our rectangles using the D-3 update pattern.
I've made a few comments here to help us to remember the structure of the update pattern.
First we have our data join.
So I'm going to put the power bar code where we select all the rights and tie it to our data array in
here.
Next we have the exit part where we're removing old elements that are no longer in data.
Here is as easy as just calling our move method on the exit selection.
Next we have the update pad.
So we're going to set the attributes of rectangles that should still be on the screen we'll be writing
pretty much the same code as an end function but we don't need to set the fill again.
Finally we have the ends at Pod's which is look exactly the same as before.
After this lecture you should hopefully have a much better idea of exactly how D-3 is working under
the hood.
Learning about the D-3 update pattern should hopefully have consolidated the knowledge you get so far
as well as helping you to become more familiar with the syntax that D-3 is using.
In the next lecture I want you to test your understanding of these concepts and the activity with a
short quiz.
Getting a firm grip on the have the D-3 update pattern is working well make it a lot easier to understand
visualizations of working later Ron when we start to add more features onto our visualizations.