Now that we can see what's going on with the D-3 update that's it.
We're finally ready to make the update function actually change between different pieces of data.
In this lecture we will be calling me up the function that we've been writing the last few lectures.
Every time interval loop runs we'll be doing this by setting a flag variable which will keep track of
which data source we're looking at.
Let's take a look at our data inside our data loading function by using a console log here.
We can see that the data is currently split into two sections.
The data are about profit and the data are about revenue.
The profit value is still a string right now.
So I'll add a line in here to clean up this data.
I want to be able to flick between seeing the revenue for the past six months and the profit for the
past six months.
We'll do this by declaring a flag variable that set to either true or false when the flag is set to
true we'll use the revenue data and when it sets of falls we'll use the profit data first.
I'm going to declare a variable called flag with a global scope and initially set it to true at each
run of the loop.
We're going to toggle the flag setting.
The truth is currently false or false that it's currently true.
Then we're going to declare a value variable that will be set according to the status of the flag.
The quickest way to write this is like this.
I'm using the turnaround operator in javascript here which is a really handy shorthand way to use it.
Elssler basically whatever's on the left hand side of the question mark should evaluate to TRUE or FALSE.
If it's true it returns the value on the left of the code long.
And if it's false it returns a value on the right after we've made this change.
We just need to make a few edits to make this work.
Or replace each of these revenue fields with the name of a value variable so that these values can alternate
between showing revenue and profit data.
Finally we'll change the value of a white label depending on what the flag says.
So here I'm using the term or the operator again to set the value of a label and then updating the label
text accordingly.
Now that we have all of this ready I'm going to refresh the page.
And finally we can see the visualization is updating every second as expected.
After this lecture you should feel comfortable going through a similar process to this day coming up
with a flag variable to flick between different data sources.
At this point we have a visualization that's starting to look more substantial and a dating automatically.
However it doesn't quite look as clean as we'd really like it to be in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to transitions in DS3 and by adding just a few simple lines of code I'll be
converting the visualization that we have now to something far more elegant and beautiful.