At this point we have a chart that's pretty much doing exactly what we want it to.
However we're not yet using the magical powers of the T-3 transition suite to give our visualization
the touch of beauty that D-3 can so easily provide
although we need to do it as a transition to our code to add this line just before we set the attributes
any attributes that we said before the transition are applied to the shapes straight away but anything
that we write after the transition will be applied gradually we're passing in a number of milliseconds
for the transition to be applied over using the generation method.
In this example where we're starting the shape of the y position at the bottom of the screen and then
we're using the transition to gradually pull the shape up into a few.
We're also making a transition from a a pastie of 0 meaning the shape is invisible to a value of 1 which
is completely solid.
This will give us the nice effect of the shape gradually fading into existence.
A good thing to note here is that you'll sometimes see a transition defined as a variable as we can
see here which is nice because we don't have to keep writing this code repeatedly and we can change
the length of our transition in just one place.
Now that we've seen how the syntax looks.
Let's add some transitions into Al-Barakaat.
Firstly I'm defining a transition variable of the top of my file calling it t and giving a generation
of 750 milliseconds.
It's important that we always keep this number lower than the value of loops delay or start off with
the axes here.
The top of this update function all that we need to do is to place a transition before this call method.
Next I'm going to add a transition for exit selection straight away.
I'm going to change the color of the existing bars to read then after the transition I'm going to gradually
change its height value to zero.
So it slides away from the screen.
We'll also need to transition the y value to the bottom by grid.
So we'll pass in y of 0 which is the pixel position at the bottom of the chart for our updating bars.
I'm just going to add the transition for any of these attributes get guess.
Then finally I'm going to make these new buyers come in from the ground up like we saw in the example
or move these y type values.
After that transition and I'll add in their initial states before the transition.
So now we can see that these transitions are working.
You might notice here that the code that we're writing isn't particularly succinct we're repeating the
same code for entering and updating elements something that we can do here is to use D-3 merge method
to set the attributes of the enter and update selections at the same time.
Let me show you how this merge method looks we're calling the merge method on end enter selection and
passing in the selection.
What we want to merge it with in this case it's a rechts variable which represents update selection.
All of these actual methods that we're changing before the merge call are applied just to enter selection
and all the actual methods that we apply after our merge call or apply to both our enter and update
selections.
To test out our exit function I'm going to pass in a different array of data to update function depending
on the value of the flag.
Let's say that if our flag is set to true meaning that we're looking at revenues then we'll just use
the regular array.
But if we're looking at profit's then we'll chop off the first element in our array.
So here I am setting a new data variable which either takes on a normal array in the first case or in
the second case I'm using be a race slice method to return.
Everything beyond that first item after we pass this code into an update function and refresh the page
we can see how this is working.
There's a problem with this visualization as it is at that moment when the chart shifts from profit
to revenue.
The last bar is the one that's entering and exiting although it's really our first bar for January they
should be changing the reason that this is happening is because we're providing data to our selection.
It's just an array.
When we first date our data join D-3 just assumes that our rate will always stay in the same order.
Actually in this case the first element in the array is missing when we look at the profits.
This means that the bar for January and profits is associated with above the February and revenues to
fix this the data method can take an optional second argument which should be a function that returns
a key to match items between different rates.
This means that D-3 will know how to associate each SVGA with the right point in the data array based
on what the function returns.
For example here will use a function that returns the month of the data so that data join tracks the
items based on their month value rather than by the items index in the array.
After refreshing the page we can now see that these bars are moving consistently with Access and it
now looks like the bar for January is the one that's entering and exiting.
This fix will be particularly important when you close the gap.
Mind the visualisation for your second class project because that visualization relies on being able
to follow each of the individual dots as time goes on and you'll get some weird behavior if you miss
that step about
at this point we now have a bar chart that's updated really smoothly and we never had to make a few
tweaks to completely change the behavior of our chart.
I also introduce you to the filter function which will be really useful when we want to change up our
data later in this course in the next leg turn again to demonstrate how we can easily convert the chart
that we have now to a scatterplot which will be at that thing into your second class project at the
end of the section.