Pross second class project we're essentially going to be using a jazzed up version of a scatterplot
where the size of our circles will change depending on the time that we're looking at.
This is technically referred to as a bubble chart.
In this lecture I'm going to be making a few small tweaks to the visualization that we have now to make
it into a scatterplot.
It's actually really simple to convert the bartk we have to a moment into a working scatterplot all
that we really need to do is switch our rectangles circles.
So first rename what we're appending to be circles rather than Rechts.
And you'll recall that SVGA circles get their position from C X and see y attributes instead of x and
y attributes.
We can make these changes was keeping everything else the same.
Next we also need to get rid of the width and height attributes instead replacing them with a radius
attribute for a simple scatterplot.
We'll just give them a radius of five pixels when we enter them
if we refresh the screen now we'll see that we suddenly have a working scatterplot.
You might notice here the circles are skewed a little bit to the left because of bend scale was positioning
our rectangle at the start of our bar rather than in the middle.
To fix this or add in half the length of bandwidth to the x value.
Now this looks like a real scatterplot for making a bubble chart.
The radius of the circles will also want to change depending on the data that you give it.
You'll be writing a new scale to do this and you'll need to remember to associate the area of the circles
with the country's populations rather than the radius of these circles.
Now they can see how a scatterplot should work indeed 3 three you should be prepared to take on your
second class project in the next lecture.
I'll be introducing you to a second class project and taking you through everything that you'll be needing.