In this lecture I'll be providing an introduction to your second class project taking you through the
project files that you'll be working with and I'll give you that look at what the finished project should
look like.
At this point in the course you should have a rough understanding of how D-3 update pattern is working
to handle updates on the page.
If you're a second class project you'll be able to put this knowledge into practice and get a good feel
for what you should be doing.
The second class project involves making a clone of a famous visualization from Gap minder which is
an organization dedicated to challenging conceptions between how we think the world is and how the world
really is.
According to statistics you should take a look at the YouTube video which is linked to the start of
the next lecture to get a feel for the context behind the visualization you'll be creating.
You'll find the starting carried in the zip file attached to the next lecture.
Again I've already set up the index to aged email file and provided you with all the files that you
should need.
This project you should work in the main js file in the JSE directory.
I've also included copies of the D-3 NJ queried libraries and your JS folder.
Let's take a quick look at the data set for our project.
Since the file is so big I'm just writing a quick Consolo get the data once it's been read into the
main jast file.
What we have here is an array of each of the different years of data you can access the year that you're
looking through this year value and the country's contains an array of objects representing each country
in that year for each of these countries.
We then have it's consonant its name is GDP per capita life expectancy and population.
The year that we're looking at I'm going to provide you with some instructions for how to get started
with this.
I recommend starting off with just making the visualization in the first year of your data and then
worrying about adding an update after that.
Once you have completed this project you should have something that looks like this.
The data is updating continuously on a cycle between all the different years in our dataset at each
point in time.
The size of our circles is changing to reflect the country's populations and the position of the circles
are changing to reflect the GDP per capita life expectancy as we mentioned back in S. history when using
a log scale here.
So you can see we're looking at Ballys for 400 then 4000 than 40000.
We're also using an ordinal scale here to separate circles by their constant.
If you find yourself still trying to find figure out any of the syntax.
Then once again you can absolutely flick between different lectures in previous sections.
You need to review the process of working through issues by yourself can really help you to understand
what's going on a lot better.
And again I'd strongly recommend you to make console logs whenever you can and claim what's going on.
Finally if you have any problems that you can't resolve by yourself and providing my solution of the
cost and you can check your work against it you can also post questions in the comments section of the
assignment page to ask questions to me or to any of the students.