Congratulations to finishing this section you created a powerful visualization that communicates an
important message.
You've had your first experience using the complete D-3 uptake Baten which is gradually starting to
make more sense.
And you've had experience using D-3 transition to seamlessly update the data.
You also now know how to use in topos and D-3 to create loops in your visualizations.
The concepts that we covered in this section are some of the most difficult to understand in D-3 if
you're feeling comfortable with the update pattern syntax that we've explored so far then you're well
on your way to becoming a D-3 master.
But if this all doesn't make much sense yet then don't worry.
With practice you gradually come to understand how the different parts of the data reliably come together
to afford you a powerful level of flexibility in what you're able to do.
We'll be building on this project in our next section to add interactive features so that users can
pause the visualization.
Choose the time that they're looking at with a slider and filter out different continents.